<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">
<channel>
<title>VICE RSS Feed</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/</link>
<description><![CDATA[RSS feed for VICE.com
]]></description>
<language>en</language>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 11:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
<item>
<title>People Who Love Guns Hate the First Smart-Gun Store</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/people-who-love-guns-hate-the-first-smart-gun-store-mb-test</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 21:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[People Who Love Guns Hate the First Smart-Gun Store
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299526</guid>
<author>Brian Anderson</author>
<category>tech, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Few Impressions: The Blurring of Fact and Imagination in &#039;Sway&#039;</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/the-blurring-of-fact-and-imagination-in-sway</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 21:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140776/franco-sway.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 359px;" /></p>
<p>
	<em>Sway,&nbsp;</em>by Zachary Lazar, is a swirling and episodic novel that incorporates the Rolling Stones circa 1969, the avant-garde filmmaker Kenneth Anger, and Manson Family associate Bobby Beausoleil in a dizzying but effective exploration of the rise and fall of 1960s mysticism. The lives of these real people are the basis of fictional characters refashioned according to Zachary&rsquo;s whims.</p>
<p>
	<em>Sway</em>&rsquo;s framework doesn&rsquo;t defy the major known events of the fictional characters&rsquo; real-life counterparts. It uses such events as a mechanism to fill interior thoughts and give depth to private actions. The way Zachary details these thoughts is so intimate and specific that there&rsquo;s no way even the actual figures would&rsquo;ve been able to recall with such clarity what they had been thinking or doing at these very specific instances from the past. I assume a careful balance of research and plausible imagination is what makes this book resonate so well.</p>
<p>
	Of course, this combination of research and imagination goes into books of all kinds&mdash;but here it feels like the approach is similar to the way an actor might prepare for an historical figure. One can exhaustively research, reading every last bit about his or her subject, but eventually there will come moments, scenes, and character questions that cannot be adequately informed by the research. This is when the artist needs to step in and fill in the blanks.</p>
<p>
	Stepping into the shoes of history to fill out the emotional and imaginative interior life of a character (particularly one based on an historical figure) is always a very delicate act. It&rsquo;s also one that excites me as an actor, writer, and director. The act of adaptation of previously incarnated material, while sprinkling on one&rsquo;s own artistic fairy dust, is deeply rewarding.</p>
<p>
	Using ekphrasis&mdash;a device where one artistic medium is used to capture the spirit of another&mdash;as a mechanism for storytelling is a daunting proposition that most modern writers avoid. When executed properly, it provides a sort of meta-contextualization that cannot be achieved through fictional storytelling alone.</p>
<p>
	<em>Sway </em>is the first book in recent memory that nails it, using the films of Anger, the music and acting of Beausoleil, and the music of the Stones to reveal deeper truths about its source material. This is a similar technique to what a biographer or memoirist might use to fill in certain gaps (an obvious example being Keith Richards&rsquo;s autobiography, <em>Life</em>).&nbsp;But by successfully tempering the material and its interpretations into a fictional narrative, Zachary makes the reader feel as if he or she is actually <em>inside </em>the characters&rsquo; heads.</p>
<p>
	He does this by circumventing prior nonfiction interpretations, eschewing scholarly analysis and critical theory so that they do not impede the story Zachary wants to tell, and allowing the reader much more room for personal interpretations of the work without years of critique stacked on top.</p>
<p>
	It&rsquo;s important to note that Zachary isn&rsquo;t trying to jump off into fantasyland with his interpretations. He very much wants his portraits to resemble the figures that we know and love (or hate)&mdash;but his fictional universe frees him from the constraints of having to qualify the interpretations as conjecture. Instead, it is gospel.</p>
<p>
	For instance, instead of the inevitably unsuccessful guessing game played by a critic trying to extrapolate what was going on inside Kenneth Anger&rsquo;s head when he was making <em>Scorpio Rising </em>or <em>Lucifer Rising </em>or <em>Invocation of My Demon Brother</em>, Zachary can tell us what <em>his </em>version of Anger was thinking when he made them. And, all things considered, this interpretation is much more poignant than anything published by a university press or film magazine. No matter how far off base it is from the real-life Anger&rsquo;s actual inspirations, it is an absolute truth in the alternate universe of <em>Sway</em>.</p>
<p>
	I recently worked on a project with the 87-year-old Anger, who told me he had never heard of <em>Sway.</em>&nbsp;This confirmed my suspicion that Zachary didn&rsquo;t attempt to consult the book&rsquo;s subjects directly, instead relying on biographical information and fictional interpretations of their artworks. A tricky proposition, but this is also precisely why the novel succeeds.</p>
<p>
	Furthermore, the main actions of the characters in <em>Sway </em>revolve around the collaborative process. These collaborations serve as the narrative&rsquo;s tent poles&mdash;they intertwine the characters&rsquo; lives in myriad ways. More often than not, Anger and his work are used as the connective tissue, resulting in both creative fruition and personal strife. The Stones synthesize disparate musical styles, influences, and attitudes to reinvent their sound once again; Anger uses arcane religious rituals and imagery to inform the transcendental mood of his films; and Beausoleil is a strange, shadowy figure who finds himself in the right and wrong places at crucial times&mdash;twisting the story in different directions.</p>
<p>
	What plays out largely follows the historical narrative of the characters&rsquo; real-life counterparts, but in a way that allows the reader to reconsider the truth of what actually unfolded by making the whole thing seem like an out-of-body experience. The Stones create indelible music, but Brian Jones and Keith Richards clash over a girl, and Brian Jones ends up fading away with drugs and then drowning in his pool (murdered?) after being fired from the band.</p>
<p>
	Bobby Beausoleil begins his career as a musician, eventually wandering into Anger&rsquo;s life and being cast as the principal of <em>Lucifer Rising</em>. But living up to the mythos surrounding him, Beausoleil absconds with the project&rsquo;s film reels during production and purportedly gives them to Charles Manson, who buries them in the desert.</p>
<p>
	The reader follows Anger&mdash;a true practitioner of Sergei Eisenstein&rsquo;s montage theory&mdash;as he discovers a groundbreaking approach to film that incorporates personal homoerotic material, documentary-style footage, and occult imagery that relies on visuals rather than dialogue-driven narrative to tell a story. He is, in turn, celebrated by such avant-garde figures as Cocteau but mostly ignored by the greater public. He gains the attention and respect of cultural juggernauts like Mick Jagger while the performers in his films berate him with charges that they are owed payment for their contributions.</p>
<p>
	It&rsquo;s almost as if Zachary uses this carefully select continuum of art and creative figures at a specific cultural moment as outlines for figures in some weird coloring book, in which he has intricately added colors that weren&rsquo;t reflected in real life. At its core, <em>Sway </em>gets to the truth&mdash;or a truth&mdash;about what it takes to make true art and to be a true creator. In the end, it isn&rsquo;t exactly pretty. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299524</guid>
<author>James Franco</author>
<category>stuff, Rolling Stones, kenneth anger, manson family, Manson, zachary lazar, sway, Franco</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nobody Wants to Talk About Bestiality Until Someone Fucks a Horse</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/they-fuck-horses-dont-they</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 20:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140763/bestialresize.jpg" style="width: 642px; height: 420px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Illustration by Julia Gfr&ouml;rer</em></p>
<p>
	On July 2, 2005, Kenneth Pinyan was dropped off by an unidentified man in the emergency room of the sleepy Enumclaw Community Hospital, about 25 miles outside of Tacoma, Washington. By the time doctors reached him, he had died of a perforated colon. When police began to investigate the death, following the trail of events that had led Pinyan to the hospital that summer day, they found themselves balls deep in a ring of bestiality the likes of which Washington State had never seen.</p>
<p>
	As it turned out, Pinyan had sustained his injury while letting a horse have sex with his ass on a farm outside of Enumclaw. After tracking down the man who dropped Pinyan at the hospital, authorities found and searched the farm where he&rsquo;d sustained his injury and discovered a videotape of the act, along with more than a hundred others depicting men having sex with or receiving sex from various farm animals (aside from horses, there were violations of goats, sheep, and chickens), taken by a man named James Michael Tait, who lived nearby. Confronted with the sheer scale and duration of the videos, police and reporters alike swallowed their discomfort and dived into the world of zoophile chatrooms and websites. After a little digging, it became clear that the Enumclaw farm was known in the community as a major bestiality brothel.</p>
<p>
	But when police tried to charge Tait with a crime, they realized that Washington didn&#39;t have any laws on the books prohibiting the ungodly union between man and beast. The best they could tag him with was trespassing, resulting in a year of probation, a $300 fine, and a day of community service.</p>
<p>
	This is a tired story in American law. Over the past two decades, numerous high-profile bestiality cases have popped up from state to state, and prosecutors have often found it hard to prosecute them. It&rsquo;s such an obscure crime, and a case&mdash;like Enumclaw farm&mdash;making it into the national spotlight is so rare that we have largely forgotten to legislate the matter. And the offenses that <em>were </em>in place were stricken from the books in the 1970s, when &ldquo;Crimes against Nature&rdquo; laws that had lumped bestiality in with consensual sexual acts between adults once labeled as illegal&mdash;like sodomy&mdash;were deleted wholesale.</p>
<p>
	Many legislators assume that anti-animal cruelty laws can be used to prosecute bestiality, but that&rsquo;s often not the case. Most of it flies under the radar, occurring in private homes, and involves no prosecutable harm to the animals involved. The cases involving sex with animals that are prosecuted usually occur quietly under other charges, like trespassing or tampering with private property. Then an odd case catches a bit of media attention and prompts a law.</p>
<p>
	The cases that spark laws usually tend to the sad rather than the absurd, like <a href="http://www.care2.com/causes/move-for-anti-bestiality-laws-in-u-s-following-sad-story.html">the case of a pit bull pup in North Carolina</a> that died from internal injuries sustained from sex with a teenage boy, which prompted a local advocate to launch a nationwide campaign. That scenario has played out in a fair number of states from 1999 until now. In Washington, a law was passed outlawing bestiality in all forms less than six months after Pinyan&rsquo;s death. (If you&#39;re keeping track&mdash;as of the last count, in 2013, by the Michigan State University College of Law&mdash;Alabama, Colorado, Connecticut, DC, Hawaii, Kentucky, Louisiana, Nevada, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New Mexico, North Dakota, Ohio, Oklahoma, Texas, Vermont, West Virginia, and Wyoming still lacked anti-bestiality laws.)</p>
<p>
	But the Washington case is a little more complex. The scope of the operation (a brothel as opposed to a farmer and his goat) and the men involved (Pinyan was a seemingly well-adjusted and well-liked Boeing engineer) don&rsquo;t match up to the common patterns and narratives of bestiality. To complicate matters further, five years after the 2005 incident, a second animal brothel was discovered in Washington. That one, in Whatcom County on the Canadian border, was based in Exitpoint Stallions Limited, a horse breeding company operated by onetime cocaine smuggler Douglas Spink. Police arrested Spink alongside a Welsh tourist, Stephen Clarke, when they found videos of the latter sexually abusing three dogs. Also found were several mice with their tails cut off, covered in Vaseline, with strings tied around them. Let that image sink in for a minute. Evidence later emerged that showed Spink had been running a full-on brothel using his dogs, horses, and mice and was producing hard-copy bestiality porn, either as souvenirs or to get patrons warmed up, presumably.</p>
<p>
	There isn&#39;t a whole lot of experts on bestiality law in the United States, but the few there are tend to agree that it&rsquo;s mainly a solitary crime. &ldquo;Most of these cases involve individuals,&rdquo; says Scott Heiser of the Animal Legal Defense Fund&rsquo;s Criminal Justice Plan. &ldquo;Especially juveniles who like to put these photos up on Facebook and the Internet... they just think no one will care.&rdquo; Dr. Randall Lockwood, senior vice president of the American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals&rsquo; Forensic Sciences and Anti-Cruelty Projects, adds that most often bestiality comes bundled with some other offense, like overt cruelty. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s not a disorder of its own,&rdquo; he points out, referring to bestiality&rsquo;s status in the <em>DSM-5</em>, which classifies zoophilia as an unspecified sexual preference, usually a component of some larger disorder.</p>
<p>
	The takeaway being that, as Lockwood puts it, &ldquo;these aren&rsquo;t otherwise upstanding and loving spouses&rdquo; who are going out there getting their rocks off with animals. And it&rsquo;s certainly not a social crime&mdash;Heiser and Lockwood both point out that, aside from the two Washington cases, every other rumored animal brothel they&rsquo;d ever heard of never materialized, or turned out to be a hoax or urban legend. Sure, the occasional human brothel will pop up pimping out a few animals on the side, but that&rsquo;s rare and not quite the same. &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t like to discount people who suspect things,&rdquo; says Heiser, &ldquo;but since 2005 there have been no detected brothels that I know of other than Spink&#39;s.&rdquo; In other words, it&rsquo;s not a community traditionally known for meeting up to aid and abet each other in a shared interest of fucking farm animals on film.</p>
<p>
	The discreet nature of bestiality can make the laws passed in the wake of high-profile cases feel a little futile. If most people who are into sexing up animals do it with their own pets or livestock, in private, without committing animal cruelty outright, then it&rsquo;s almost impossible to detect the crime. And even if individuals are caught, the evidence disappears quickly, says Lockwood. Only in the past four or five years have vets learned, en masse, how to use rape kits on animals. Even when detected, judges tend to be lenient and prosecutors pursue cases under other parallel violations of the law that carry a lower burden of proof. And, some point out, if there&rsquo;s no harm (read: legal cruelty) to the animals, then there&rsquo;s no reason to prosecute.</p>
<p>
	Lockwood defends the value of such laws and the prosecution of bestiality by pointing out that it&rsquo;s increasingly connected in academic literature to minds that are disturbed in more troubling ways. Just under five percent of child sex offenders, he says, openly admit to having had relations with animals, and 30 to 40 percent appear to have engaged in bestiality when questioned on a polygraph. He also points out that a common zoophile defense&mdash;that animals enjoy or do not mind sexual aggression&mdash;is eerily reminiscent of pedophilic rhetoric.</p>
<p>
	In contrast to the prevailing narrative, though, Pinyan was by most accounts an otherwise normal man. After his death, a documentary crew that started out with a critical stance on the issue produced <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zoo_%28film%29"><em>Zoo</em></a>, a 2007 film on the Washington horse sex ring that took a slightly positive approach to zoophiles and their culture. Pinyan raises serious questions about the selection bias involved in the common stories of bestiality. Given that most literature comes from those who get caught, often as a result of their more overtly devious actions, it&rsquo;s hard to say anything comprehensive and certain about the zoophile population at large.</p>
<p>
	And we are unlikely to learn anything more about it in the near future. For now, what we know is that Washington is just weird. It often records the highest bestiality rate in the US, the oddity of the two aforementioned crimes aside. Granted, that&rsquo;s just what gets caught&mdash;Washington may just be a hyper-vigilant, animal-loving state. But that bares the type of investigation that no one wants to do, as it would involve trolling around bestiality chat rooms, and whether inherently pathological or not the act still feels just too icky to touch. So rather than some groundbreaking profile of the psychology of zoophiles, the next piece of news you&rsquo;re likely to hear about bestiality is the inevitable passage of Alabama&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.leftinalabama.com/diary/10777/sb151-antibestiality-passes-senate-with-one-no-vote-many-abstensions">long-delayed anti-bestiality law</a>, which should make it through the house later this year.&nbsp;</p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299511</guid>
<author>Mark Hay</author>
<category>stuff, Bestiality, mark hay, horse sex, death by horse penis, on the farm, animal brothels, sex</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Would Free Public Transport Improve a Country&#039;s Economy?</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/public-transport-in-spain</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140743/800px-Barcelona-metro-pl-Catalunya.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 360px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>Barcelona Metro photo courtesy of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Barcelona_metro_pl_Catalunya.JPG">Wiki Commons</a></i></p>
<p>
	Over the past few weeks, protesters in Barcelona have united <a href="http://www.demotix.com/news/3972892/protest-against-price-public-transport-barcelona" target="_blank">against yet another public-transport fare increase</a>. Using the slogan &quot;<a href="https://twitter.com/StopPujades" target="_blank">Stop Pujades</a>&quot; (Stop Increases) and supported by a bunch of other organizations&mdash;including the Barcelona Metropolitan Transport workers themselves&mdash;demonstrators have blocked several metro, bus, and commuter train stops in the hope that authorities will revert to the pre-increase prices.</p>
<p>
	But is Barcelona&#39;s&mdash;and any other city&#39;s&mdash;public transport system even worth protesting over? Is there an alternative, more socially beneficial model we should switch to? Or should we just screw the subways?</p>
<p>
	To shed some light on the situation, I spoke to writer and sociologist Jorge Moruno, who has written about the issues surrounding the current protests and cofounded a couple of student and activist movements.</p>
<p>
	<iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/rOBKr3i_V2U" width="640"></iframe></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Protests against fare increases for Barcelona&#39;s public transport</em></p>
<p>
	<strong>VICE: Hi, Jorge. So do you think we should all boycott the subways?</strong><br />
	<strong>Jorge Moruno:</strong> That involves certain risks that must be taken into consideration. It can be done individually or as a collective, in a more politically organized way. If Rosa Parks hadn&rsquo;t refused to give up her seat, for example, the civil rights movement would probably not have been unleashed in the way it was. I&rsquo;m not comparing these situations; I&rsquo;m just trying to apply the political logic of civil disobedience&mdash;what is legal isn&#39;t necessarily legitimate. Democracy isn&#39;t a petrified animal. It&#39;s always on the move.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Yeah. But there&#39;s good reason to jump the turnstiles, right?</strong><br />
	The disparity between wages, income, and ticket fares is distressing. There are so many people out of work or with low-paying jobs who need to use public transport to commute, meet other people, or go job-hunting. And access to mobility is a basic requirement; otherwise we&#39;re risking social exclusion.</p>
<p>
	There&#39;s no legitimacy in not being able to move about the city or in having to spend the little money one has on it. Collective disobedience to condemn the situation contributes to laying the foundations of a future right. Law is not democracy&rsquo;s lynchpin, but the other way around: democracy is the foundation of law.</p>
<p>
	<strong>So what&#39;s the solution? Taking control of public transport away from the authorities?</strong><br />
	The use of civil disobedience to ensure collective access to mobility is precisely about making sure transport remains public and unrestricted. &quot;Public&quot; implies everyone can have access to it. There is a paradox here, because we tend&mdash;they make us tend&mdash;to think that a civic stand is to pay your ticket regardless of your social situation.</p>
<p>
	Those who never travel in a crammed underground subway car or who cut back on public services and social rights are the same ones who tell us to pay as many fare increases as needed. It doesn&#39;t take a revolutionary to consider the right to rebel a popular right. It was even foreseen by John Locke, the father of classical liberalism, and it&#39;s stated in the Declaration of Human Rights. It&rsquo;s just common sense.</p>
<p>
	<strong>So how could this updated mode of transport be financed?</strong><br />
	As Lester Freamon said in <em>The Wire</em>: &quot;You have to track the money trail.&quot; Although employment is scarce and precarious, money doesn&rsquo;t evaporate; it just changes hands. The number of millionaires in Spain <a href="http://www.thelocal.es/20130619/spains" target="_blank">rose by 5.4 percent</a> between 2011 and 2013. When wages and tax-funded contributions go down, when debt takes up all the wealth, and when there&#39;s a demand for privatization, public money ends up in a few private pockets.</p>
<p>
	A tax reform is necessary so that those who have more pay more taxes. Tax evasion must be done away with, and the process that&#39;s leading us into economic underdevelopment must be reversed.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140380/111.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 449px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>A couple of posters for the Stop Pujades protests (<a href="https://twitter.com/StopPujades" target="_blank">via</a>)</em></p>
<p>
	<strong>The cost of using public transport keeps rising, but do you think there&#39;s any link between the increased fares and the cost of running the services?&nbsp;</strong><br />
	We&#39;ll be told that these ticket fare increases won&#39;t cover the cost of public transport and that state subsidies are needed. With all the debt involved, perhaps it would be more rational to argue that we don&rsquo;t need to have the world&rsquo;s second largest high-speed railway system, while the local network&mdash;used by millions of people yearly&mdash;has suffered substantial cutbacks. Public transport, like water, health care, energy, or education, can&rsquo;t be a business. The aim should be to maximize society&rsquo;s well-being, rather than benefitting themselves. It&#39;s a fundamental right that we are paying for with our taxes.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Do you think a free public transport would be beneficial to the economy?</strong><br />
	Firstly, we should ask whose economy it would be beneficial to. Economics is politics&mdash;its rules aren&#39;t natural. The core of the issue isn&#39;t about public transport being free, but the ethical and political conviction that people&rsquo;s needs and well-being must be placed above all else, ensuring their access to public transport. A better-living society with no fear of tomorrow is a healthier, more innovative, smarter one.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Do you know of any examples where free public transport has worked?</strong><br />
	In Tallinn, Estonia, public transport has become a free service through the elimination of direct payment and by funding it solely through taxes and state subsidies. Another prime example is Freiburg, Germany&mdash;a model that allows accessible and ecologic mobility. They promote the use of public transport, and monthly tickets for all commuters working in the industrial area are entirely or partially financed by their employers.</p>
<p>
	But mobility isn&#39;t just limited to transport. A global change is needed in public and urban policies, in the production model, in democratic culture, and in the tax model. Speaking of public transport means speaking about a whole model of coexistence.</p>
<p>
	<strong>How do you interpret the protests against fare hikes in Barcelona?</strong><br />
	They are yet another sign of the general impoverishment of the population, barring them from their rights as citizens. Managing to stop the increase of transport fares or the privatization of public health services&mdash;these are all expressions of the same democratic aspiration: the defence of life against the dictatorship of financial servitude. These struggles develop a democratic popular unity against the political project of the rich and powerful, who are trying to enforce the rule of debt and austerity.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Thanks, Jorge.</strong></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299502</guid>
<author>Juanjo Villalba</author>
<category>stuff, Barcelona, protest, spain, Public Transport, fare increases, subway</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to Turn Any Glasses into Google Glass</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/how-to-turn-any-glasses-into-google-glass-mb-test</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	Google&#39;s new wearable tech device, <a href="http://www.google.com/glass/start/">Glass</a>, has a lot going for it. Sure, it&#39;s ridiculously expensive and poses any number of profound ethical concerns. But it also promises to bring augmented-reality technology into the mainstream.</p>

]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299517</guid>
<author>Yannick Lejacq</author>
<category>tech, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Meet the Nieratkos: Pro Skater Leo Romero Is the Mexican Johnny Cash</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/pro-skater-leo-romero-is-the-mexican-johnny-cash</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/vAxL_oWk6Fk?list=UUtmU6euep0ehxk85iaBRO7Q" width="640"></iframe></p>
<p>
	Professional skateboarding has a lot of downtime. Injury, rainy days, hangovers&mdash;all are valid reasons for a skater not to do his or her job on a given day. So most people in this profession have hobbies to make their lives of leisure a bit more fulfilling when they are off their boards. Leo Romero is no exception, and he has started a band with his bros called Travesura.</p>
<p>
	I&rsquo;ve loved the quick-witted, sharp-tongued Leo ever since 2003, when he <a href="http://www.chrisnieratko.com/pics/Big-Brother-April-2003--95-Damn-AM-Leo-Romero-High.jpg">told me he&rsquo;d never had a hand job</a>. Since that interview 11 years ago, he has become one of the gnarliest, most respected skateboarders in history, and I imagine he has received many hand jobs. His band recently dropped its first EP (which you can <a href="http://www.scionav.com/2014/01/28/travesura-ep-download/">download for free</a>), so I decided to interview him for the 100th time in our long friendship to find out about becoming a rock star, fights, groupies, and folk-music mosh pits.</p>
<p>
	<iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/O4lTM0gTL7s" width="640"></iframe></p>
<p>
	<strong>VICE: When did you decide to become a rock star, Leo?<br />
	Leo Romero: </strong>I haven&rsquo;t really decided to be a rock star, but I started playing in front of people a few years ago just by going to open-mic nights.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Were you nervous at all? You&rsquo;ve skated demos in front of large groups of people, but this is a whole different monster. The first time I tried stand-up I had to go in the bathroom and puke before I took the stage.</strong><br />
	I was at first, but I tried to psyche myself up by thinking of it like a demo. But it&rsquo;s definitely not. It&rsquo;s way more personal than a demo. So I just got drunk the first couple times. There were little butterflies in my stomach at first, but it got easier. Sometimes you get too drunk and think you sound awesome, but you&rsquo;re just shit-faced and sound like crap.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140736/travesura-and-jared-hagerresize.jpg" style="width: 642px; height: 426px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Photos by <a href="http://granthatfield.blogspot.com/">Grant Hatfield</a></em></p>
<p>
	<strong>How does playing music differ from skating?</strong><br />
	There are a lot of similarities in it, actually. Like you mentioned, I&rsquo;ve skated demos in front of a lot of people. You&rsquo;ve seen guys kill a demo and have a great day, and you&rsquo;ve seen them bomb a demo. That&rsquo;s how it is performing live. I like that because I can relate to that feeling of, <em>OK, today fucking sucks. I&rsquo;ll try again tomorrow</em>. Playing music is the same way&mdash;if it&rsquo;s a shitty night you just say, &ldquo;Fuck it, there&rsquo;s nothing I can do. I&rsquo;ll restart tomorrow.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	<strong>Do you smash guitars like boards? Is that part of your act?</strong><br />
	No. I never smash them because I really enjoy my instruments. I just beat them up a little bit when I&rsquo;m playing.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Have you ever pulled a <em><a href="http://www.thrashermagazine.com/articles/videos/king-of-the-road-2013-webisode-1/">Thrasher </a></em><a href="http://www.thrashermagazine.com/articles/videos/king-of-the-road-2013-webisode-1/">King of the Road</a> move and smashed other people&rsquo;s guitars?</strong><br />
	No, because that&rsquo;s kind of fucked up. People enjoy their instruments. That would be fucking lame to do something like that to somebody.</p>
<p>
	<iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="361" mozallowfullscreen="" src="//player.vimeo.com/video/82326561" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="642"></iframe></p>
<p>
	<strong>What if they sound super shitty?</strong><br />
	Then that just means we&rsquo;re going to sound way cooler.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Are you a better skater or musician?</strong><br />
	I&rsquo;d say I&rsquo;m a better skater. Then again I am getting older so I could just be saying that to toot my own horn.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Are you a better musician than <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0GRkI609uQk">Jereme Rogers is a rapper</a>?</strong><br />
	I don&rsquo;t know. He&rsquo;s pretty fucking cool.</p>
<p>
	<strong>You&rsquo;re a liar. How would you describe the band and your sound?</strong><br />
	Every song sounds crazy and different. Some are a lot folkier than others and some are rockier, but it&rsquo;s a rock/folk/blues type band.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140737/travesura-shotski.jpg" style="width: 642px; height: 426px;" /></p>
<p>
	<strong>You said in an interview that the three musicians you would have most liked to tour with were Elvis, Johnny Cash, and Jerry Lee Lewis&mdash;three of my favorites. Are they big influences on your sound?</strong><br />
	Yeah. I would say Johnny Cash, for sure. I wouldn&rsquo;t say I sound anything like that, but I&rsquo;ve written songs in that vein. Elvis didn&rsquo;t write shit, but he killed. Everyone who plays music wants to be Elvis no matter who the fuck they are.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Are you working on becoming a pill addict in the tradition of Elvis and Johnny Cash?</strong><br />
	No, not at all. I think I might be getting a little too old for that shit. I mean, I don&rsquo;t think you&rsquo;re ever too old; I just think you can cause some serious damage if you start doing it late.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Good. I was going to warn against it. I can tell you from experience it makes you very constipated, and I think your scrawny ass would look silly with a potbelly full of impacted feces.</strong><br />
	Yeah. I think I&rsquo;ll pass on that, as cool as it sounds.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140738/leo-tour-van.jpg" style="width: 642px; height: 426px;" /></p>
<p>
	<strong>Who gets more groupies? Leo Romero the pro skater or Leo Romero the musician?</strong><br />
	Neither, actually. The guy who gets all the ladies is the drummer, Mark Moros. I think that&rsquo;s usually the case in every band. Drummers are the crazy ones fucking shit up and doing chicks. Mark gets drunk and starts acting the fool. We went to a bar after the first show I ever played with him, and he pissed on the bar. When they tossed him he said, &ldquo;What the fuck? We just nailed a show down the street! Fuck you!&rdquo; The bouncer was so confused, like, &ldquo;You just played a show somewhere else? Who cares?&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	I don&rsquo;t have any groupie stories about myself, but my friend Eric Evans licked a girl&rsquo;s butthole on the staircase once. She was leaving the show and he was like, &ldquo;Can I go down on you real quick before you leave?&rdquo; She bent over, pulled her underwear to the side, and he went to brown town.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Are there lots of fights at your shows?</strong><br />
	There aren&rsquo;t fights, but there are mosh pits.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Folk-music mosh pits? What are those like?</strong><br />
	Fucking crazy, man. They go off with a bunch of our friends. Sometimes it&rsquo;s a mosh pit, and sometimes it&rsquo;s like a wresting match. I&rsquo;m a big wrestling fan, and a lot of our friends are big wrestling fans. Sometimes when we&rsquo;re playing it&rsquo;s like WrestleMania&mdash;people getting pinned and choke-slammed and shit. It&rsquo;s pretty rad.</p>
<p>
	<iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/WIjl2dbkU5A" width="640"></iframe></p>
<p>
	<strong>Your dad was never a big fan of your skateboarding. Is he a bigger fan of your music?</strong><br />
	I don&rsquo;t think he likes our music, but I think he&rsquo;s mellowed out and respects the fact that I like doing it.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Where can people buy your EP?</strong><br />
	You can <a href="http://www.scionav.com/2014/01/28/travesura-ep-download/">download the EP for free</a>. And if you go to our shows we give out CDs for free.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Free? How the hell are you going to make any money like that?</strong><br />
	First we have to get ourselves out there; then we make the money. I&rsquo;m going around to record stores and asking if they&rsquo;d mind giving out our CD, and they&rsquo;re like, &ldquo;Well, let me give it a listen first.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s like I&rsquo;m on flow again.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Dude! You&rsquo;re Leo Romero. You gotta walk in those record stores with your pants off and your dick out!</strong><br />
	Into a record store that knows nothing about skateboarding? I&rsquo;ll try that.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140739/leo-basement-show.jpg" style="width: 642px; height: 426px;" /></p>
<p>
	<strong>Be like, &ldquo;Do you know who the fuck I am?&rdquo;</strong><br />
	&ldquo;No, sir. Get the fuck out of my store.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	<strong>&ldquo;And put some pants on!&rdquo; So is this your retirement plan? After skateboarding, do you plan on being a professional folk singer?</strong><br />
	It&rsquo;s funny, because I was at a show in San Diego and some kid was like, &ldquo;Hey, dog. You still skate, fool?&rdquo; I was like, &ldquo;Fuck. How long ago did <em>Made</em> [Emerica video] come out? That was only a few months ago.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s funny, because I&rsquo;m obviously still skateboarding and I&rsquo;m actually filming for the full-length Toy Machine video now. All I do is play music and skateboard.</p>
<p>
	<strong>A lot of skateboarders are also talented musicians. Who are some of your favorites?</strong><br />
	I like Ray Barbee and Josh Harmony a lot. I like the way they play. When you watch someone play and they&rsquo;re boring, you can&rsquo;t get into them. It&rsquo;s like watching a tech guy skate a demo, like, &ldquo;He&rsquo;s good, but he&rsquo;s fucking boring.&rdquo; You watch someone like Ray Barbee play, and he&rsquo;s always nailing it. But Josh Harmony is my favorite because he&rsquo;s a singer-songwriter.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Who is the most boring skateboarder out today?</strong><br />
	I don&rsquo;t know, man. Probably me if people are asking me if I still skate.</p>
<p>
	<em>Download the Travesura album for <a href="http://www.scionav.com/2014/01/28/travesura-ep-download/">free here</a>.</em></p>
<p>
	<em>For show dates go to <a href="http://travesuramusic.com/">travesuramusic.com/</a></em></p>
<p>
	<em>More stupid can be found at <a href="http://chrisnieratko.com/">Chrisnieratko.com</a> or <a href="https://twitter.com/Nieratko">@Nieratko</a>.</em></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299490</guid>
<author>Chris Nieratko</author>
<category>music, leo romero, skateboarding, music, Chris Nieratko, Travesura</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Epicly Later&#039;d: Ed Templeton - Part 3</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/epicly-later-d/ed-templeton-part-3</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	In part three of Ed&#39;s&nbsp;<em>Epicly Later&#39;d</em>, Ed looks back what was arguably the peak of his skate career&mdash;when he dropped out of high school to conquer Europe in 1990, landing the covers of&nbsp;<em>Thrasher</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>Transworld</em>&nbsp;in the process. He also tells the story of how he met his wife, Deanna, and what led him to leave New Deal to start a new company with Mike Vallely.</p>
<p>
	<em>For more info on the 1990 M&uuml;nster Contest, check <a href="http://Titus.de/history">this</a> out.</em></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299435</guid>
<author>VICE Staff</author>
<category>sports, epicly, ed templeton, thrasher, transworld, skateboarding</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>NASA&#039;s Going to Try to Lasso an Asteroid Before Congress Can Stop It</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/nasas-going-to-try-to-lasso-an-asteroid-before-congress-can-stop-it-mb-test</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	NASA&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/files/FY15_Summary_Brief.pdf" target="_blank">new budget</a> calls for an acceleration of its plan to <a href="http://motherboard.vice.com/blog/nasa-s-actually-thinking-about-capturing-an-asteroid-and-bringing-it-home" target="_blank">capture an asteroid and bring it into lunar orbit</a>, making the controversial idea more likely to happen.</p>
<p>
	&nbsp;</p>

]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299477</guid>
<author>Jason Koebler</author>
<category>tech, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Britain&#039;s King of Adultery Helps Married People Cheat</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/do-you-want-to-have-an-affair-call-this-man</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140321/cheat.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 485px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>Photo via Flickr user <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denharsh/" target="_blank">Harsh Agrawal</a></i></p>
<p>
	Are you bored of monogamy? Do you just have an uncontrollable urge to have sex with someone other than the person you sleep next to every night? If so, I have some excellent news: A matchmaking service is offering husbands and wives seeking a fling the opportunity to shit all over their marriage vows in the most secretive and expensive way possible.</p>
<p>
	In fact, UK-based <a href="http://www.infidelities.co.uk/" target="_blank">Infidelities</a>&mdash;a &quot;discreet one to one private client personal and bespoke introduction service for men and women who are in a committed relationship but seek an affair&quot;&mdash;has been around since at least 2009, but David, the 70-year-old founder of Infidelities (who didn&#39;t want to disclose his real last name as he thought it might damage his other businesses), hadn&#39;t done any press about the site until I met with him recently in the lounge of the Ritz hotel in London.</p>
<p>
	When I arrived, David was taking a break between meeting clients, who he told me are generally pretty well-off. He mentioned that they&#39;re occasionally related to famous people and said that he once arranged an affair for the sister of a well-known author. &ldquo;When she gave me her name, it was quite an unusual surname,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;Later, I picked up a book from the library, and it had the same surname as the woman I&rsquo;d met that morning.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Besides that vague snippet, the rest of David&rsquo;s consultations, understandably, are strictly confidential. He also refuses to discuss how much he charges, saying it&rsquo;s a matter for him and his clients.</p>
<p>
	He would tell me about how he started this business, however. Having run mainstream dating services for the past 15 years&mdash;and corporate networking services before that&mdash;David took the next logical step and branched out into arranging affairs for married people about five years ago. &ldquo;I thought, <em>There&rsquo;s a niche market here&mdash;why not develop it?</em>&rdquo; he told me. &ldquo;It was kind of on a whim, really.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	David divides his time between East Anglia, where he lives, and meeting clients in fancy hotels in London. He told me that he enjoys walking, cycling, classical music, reading and cooking, and said he helps as many as 50 people a year have affairs. Understandably, he strongly rejects the idea that cheating is always bad for a relationship&mdash;he even got angry when I said the word <em>cheating</em> and forbade me from using it again.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;I never use the word <em>cheating</em>,&rdquo; he said with disdain. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s just common currency. It&rsquo;s a conspiracy of a certain middle-class, middle-England Protestantism. If you go to France, I&rsquo;m sure they don&rsquo;t call it cheating. It&rsquo;s the wrong description; it&rsquo;s much more nuanced than that. There are so many different reasons why people want to have a relationship outside their marriage.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Continuing, he launched into what I believe could be an entirely original conspiracy theory. &ldquo;This whole idea of cheating&mdash;it&rsquo;s all a con; it&rsquo;s helping the divorce industry,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;The lawyers make a lot of money out of divorce. People all have different reasons why they want to do certain things; it doesn&rsquo;t just come under the category of cheating.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	One example he drew my attention to was of a woman whose husband was ill and could no longer perform sexually. With the husband&rsquo;s consent, the wife consulted with David and he arranged an affair for her.</p>
<p>
	Another case involved a wife who was much younger than her husband and wanted to experience sex with a man more her age. This time, the husband didn&rsquo;t know about the affair, which David said was usually the case. He still insisted his service is doing more good than harm.</p>
<p>
	David is married himself and told me his views on marriage stem from reading a lot. One book, which he cites on his website, appears to have been slightly more inspiring to him than others: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/When-Good-People-Have-Affairs/dp/0312563442" target="_blank"><em>When Good People Have Affairs</em></a>, a self-help book by therapist Mira Kirshenbaum that was targeted at people who think of themselves as moral, upstanding individuals but want to have sex with someone they aren&#39;t married to.</p>
<p>
	The book was released in 2008 and attracted so much controversy that <a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cheating-partners-aren-t-good-people-no-matter-what-the-experts-say-1-1263600" target="_blank">one opinion piece</a> in the <em>Scotsman</em> had the author describing how she wanted to fly across the Atlantic and &ldquo;[hunt] her down and [beat] her with my bare fists, turning all my hurt of being cheated on in the past into powerful blows.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	David insisted to me that Infidelities is strictly about business and is in no way a political or moral statement. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s not philosophical,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m not looking to have a fight&mdash;I&rsquo;m running it as a business. I&rsquo;m making a living, and that&rsquo;s bread on the table for my wife and family.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	He told me that he doesn&rsquo;t understand why a marriage should fall apart based on one little case of infidelity. &ldquo;You&rsquo;ve built a house, a family,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;You&rsquo;ve worked hard together. You&rsquo;ve built the financial stability. Is an affair a reason to knock down the whole house of cards? [My clients] have no inclination to set up a home with this new person.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	In that case, I asked him, why don&rsquo;t these people&mdash;especially the men&mdash;just visit a prostitute?</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;We do want a relationship where we want someone we have a rapport with, who we can talk to,&rdquo; he replied. &ldquo;Men especially are much more into casual relationships&mdash;as many as possible without any commitment. Women aren&#39;t looking for multiple partners in the main; they want some sort of commitment.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	As our interview came to an end, an elderly man wearing a long coat entered the lounge and started milling around as though looking for somebody. David excused himself, and I left him to it.</p>
<p>
	<em>Follow Michael Allen on <a href="http://twitter.com/Michael_K_Allen" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.</em></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299453</guid>
<author>Michael Allen</author>
<category>stuff, Infidelities, cheating, unfaithful, how to cheat, cheating service, how do I cheat on my husband</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spark the Bong and Listen to Some Motherfucking Wizard Rock</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/spark-the-bong-and-listen-to-some-motherfucking-wizard-rock</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Spark the Bong and Listen to Some Motherfucking Wizard Rock
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299478</guid>
<author>J. Bennett</author>
<category>music, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Kiev&#039;s Elite Vigilante Group Is Still Ready to Fight </title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/the-euromaidan-iron-hundred-are-still-ready-to-fight</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 16:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140300/Sergei-men.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>The Iron Hundred pay tribute to fallen fellow protesters. All photos by the author</i></p>
<p>
	The protesters who occcupied Kiev&#39;s Independence Square may have deposed hated president Viktor Yanukovych, but they don&#39;t believe that the fight is over. In particular, the &ldquo;Iron Hundred&rdquo; (or <em>Zalizna Sotnia</em>), the self-&shy;declared elite of Euromaidan&rsquo;s volunteer defense force, are still ready to battle Yanukovych supporters or even&nbsp;the Russians if need be.</p>
<p>
	Members of the Iron Hundred were involved with the protests since the very first clashes on Hrushevskoho Street in January. &ldquo;We were all in different squads, but we recognized each other by face,&rdquo; a young fighter told me. &ldquo;Eventually we veterans came together in this unit. Some of our comrades were killed from February 18 to 20, and a few more are still missing.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Kiev was in mourning when I joined the Iron Hundred on their way to pay their respects to the fallen. Just about every spot where protesters had fallen in the fight against government forces was covered by flowers, candles, religious icons, and pictures of the dead, who have been dubbed the &ldquo;Heavenly Hundred.&rdquo; At one of site on Hrushevskoho Street that saw some of the fiercest battles, a woman broke into a distraught rant: &ldquo;Where were all of you when these kids got killed? What were all of you doing?&rdquo; She was met with an awkward silence. A few girls in the crowd tried to fight back tears. The squad leader, a man named Sergei, prayed with his men. They laid flowers down and moved on to the next site.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140301/2.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 425px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>One of the many memorials to fallen Euromaidan protesters</i></p>
<p>
	The mood in Kiev in the days immediately after Yanukovych fled was not the post-revolution party that you might expect. If anything, the atmosphere had become more tense and somber. The revolutionary pop rock playing from radios was gone, replaced by broadcasts from Parliament on the latest votes and ministerial appointments. Few faces in the crowd seemed happy with the results. For many activists, the changes amounted to a reshuffling of participants in a system that should be completely purged.</p>
<p>
	I met with the Iron Hundred when they had just returned from the city of Dnipropetrovsk, where they had been on a mission with an outfit called AutoSich. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s kind of like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AutoMaidan" target="_blank">Automaidan</a>&nbsp;[a group of drivers involved in the Euromaidan protests], but more radical,&rdquo; the young fighter said. &ldquo;We managed to make some contacts with local militants who will join us in our fight.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	The Iron Hundred have lately been riding in columns of cars to combat the <em>titushki&mdash;</em>thugs, originally hired by the Yanukovych regime to beat up and terrorize protesters, who have now gone freelance. &ldquo;They&rsquo;re not even following their original orders anymore and have joined forces with local gangsters,&rdquo; Sergei said. &ldquo;Just terrorizing people, robbing, and looting. Though Yanukovych&rsquo;s government has fallen apart, they are still paid by some [pro-Russian] Party of Regions members of parliament&mdash;and possibly Russia, but we can&rsquo;t confirm this yet.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Many law-enforcement officers have neglected their duties since Yanukovych fled the country, allowing these bandits to roam the eastern cities of Ukraine. &ldquo;Maybe Odessa is next,&rdquo; Sergei speculated. &ldquo;We don&rsquo;t know where we&rsquo;re going for sure yet, but we&rsquo;ll be where we&rsquo;re needed most.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140299/O3.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 425px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>A masked member of the Iron Hundred</i></p>
<p>
	The Iron Hundred&rsquo;s banner is the red-and-&shy;black flag of the Ukrainian Insurgent Army (UPA), a paramilitary force that fought against the Soviet Union during World War II. The flag has generated controversy&mdash;Russian state media has seized on the association to brand Euromaidan as a neo&shy;-Nazi uprising, since the UPA collaborated with Nazi Germany at times. (They also fought against the Germans and anyone else who stood in the way of Ukrainian nationalism.)</p>
<p>
	Sergei said that the Euromaidan&rsquo;s Iron Hundred adopted the name of a legendary UPA squad that was never defeated. &ldquo;Even when the UPA was losing in 1949, they fought their way through the Russians, Poles, Slovaks, and Hungarians into western Germany and were eventually taken in by the Americans,&rdquo; he said. Despite this sense of nationalism uniting them, the Iron Hundred has divided itself into two separate squads. &ldquo;They brought in all these new guys from Lviv, and many of us didn&rsquo;t feel like being the Iron Hundred of Lviv,&quot; Sergei told me. &quot;So we split up, and now we share the same floor here in the City Hall.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Sergei showed me around the other floors of Kiev&rsquo;s occupied City Hall. Swastikas and other right&shy;-wing imagery had been erased from the walls, except on the seventh floor, where the Right Sector, credited with giving Yanukovych the ultimatum on February 21 that is said to have prompted his flight the following day, has set up shop. A giant swastika and the number 1488 (which is associated with white supremacy) adorned their area. &ldquo;We don&rsquo;t talk with the Right Sector anymore at all,&rdquo; Sergei said. &ldquo;We just can&rsquo;t agree on our ideas. They are too radical.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Sergei explained that the Iron Hundred isn&#39;t politically unified; its members support varying parties. He is a supporter of Yulia Tymoshenko, who was embraced by the Euromaidan movement after being released from prison, where she spent three years. &ldquo;Some say she is also corrupt, but her party (Fatherland) has a good program for economic, political, and social reform,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;I think she can bring change to our country.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140302/1.jpg" style="width: 425px; height: 640px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>Another memorial to a protester killed in the violence</i></p>
<p>
	Later, we stood outside City Hall, and Sergei pointed to a collection box with a sign that read, &ldquo;for weapons.&rdquo; According to Sergei, they are trying to raise some serious firepower. &ldquo;Many young guys here are ready to fight. I too want to fight. The Ukrainian people are strong and brave, and we have a long history of guerrilla warfare.&rdquo; I personally witnessed how resistance fighters charged up the hill on Instytutska Street on February 20&mdash;the deadliest day of Euromaidan&mdash;into a rain of shotgun pellets and sniper fire, against which their metal shields were about as useful as cardboard. It didn&rsquo;t prevent them from recovering ground that in previous days had been lost to Berkut special forces and building new, bigger barricades while still under fire.</p>
<p>
	With a Russian occupation of Crimea currently underway, the thought of a civil war doesn&rsquo;t seem far-&shy;fetched. &ldquo;Throughout our history, we have always been fighting for independence,&rdquo; Sergei said. &ldquo;Now we might have to fight again.&rdquo; If Russian forces persist in invading Ukraine, these fighters could end up in many situations in which they would be outnumbered and outgunned.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140538/5.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 425px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>Katya</i></p>
<p>
	Amid the posturing and talk of war stood Katya, who was helping the Iron Hundred and other Euromaidan activists as a medic. Although she sounded tough when talking or joking with the others, the violence had clearly taken its toll on her. The 19-year-old student joined the movement during the earliest protests, in November. Since then, she&rsquo;s seen many people shot, wounded, and killed. A man saved her life and lost his eye as a result. &ldquo;I was crying for hours after that,&rdquo; she recalled. &ldquo;I can&rsquo;t sleep at home, because when I close my eyes I keep seeing the dead people.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	She tries to spend as much time as she can in Independence Square, because it&rsquo;s where she feels most comfortable. &ldquo;I&rsquo;ve missed my exams, but hopefully I can retake them sometime,&rdquo; she said. She was not alone among those who have suffered from the violence. Some of the fighters in the Iron Hundred looked barely out of their teens, but exhaustion was visible on their faces. Like Katya, they occupy a space between their previous lives and the post-revolutionary Ukraine they want to see develop. Talking to them, it became clear to me that the revolution is far from over.</p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299452</guid>
<author>Alan Turgutoglu</author>
<category>news, euromaidan, Ukrainian Insurgent Army, Iron Hundred, ukraine, kiev, titushki</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sriracha Aged in Whiskey Barrels Is Better Than the Original Sauce</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/whiskey-barrel-aged-sriracha-sauce-is-better-than-the-original</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140507/Lisa-Murphy.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	When I first wrote about how I was dealing with the now-lifted <a href="http://www.vice.com/read/how-im-dealing-with-the-sriracha-ban">sriracha ban</a>, I got the strangest emails, tweets, and ideas on how to enjoy the sauce. Weirdly enough, too many of them involved whiskey. One guy suggested that I try a sriracha pickle-back shot: Fill an empty sriracha bottle with pickle juice, let it marinate, and use that as your whiskey-back. (He promised it would &ldquo;burn so good,&rdquo; which I&rsquo;m assuming refers to the inevitable heartburn-back.)</p>
<p>
	A couple of weeks ago, I got an email from Lisa Murphy, a woman who offered to send me a jar of her whiskey-barrel-aged sriracha. The day after I got her version of the chili sauce, I put a spoonful of it on my morning sandwich: a whole-wheat sandwich with a slim slice of cheddar, a handful of fresh spinach, and an egg over easy. It was everything she had promised. A sweet and spicy sauce with just the right hint of smoked-whiskey flavors. It made the plastic-bottle stuff look like a pansy.</p>
<p>
	When I got on the phone with Lisa, I realized that she wasn&rsquo;t just another person trying to capitalize on the put-sriracha-on-everything craze. This woman was very serious about sauces. She was even more serious about ketchup&mdash;and trust me, she is a lover, fanatic, and historian of ketchup&mdash;which she assured me is a sauce and not the $3 goo you keep in your fridge to mask the taste of overcooked burgers.</p>
<p>
	She used to throw &ldquo;ketchup parties&rdquo; for her friends as a hobby when she was still working for a high-tech startup. Her ketchup is orange, not red, because she uses local tomatoes that came in a variety of colors. As a side gig, she experimented and sold her orange&mdash;jarred, not bottled&mdash;ketchup in local specialty stores in San Francisco. At $7.50 a pop, the stuff sold out. When the storeowners reordered, she quit her job, spent the three months before tomato season in California traveling throughout Southeast Asia, and returned to start her sauce company,&nbsp;<a href="http://sosusauces.com/">SOSU</a>.</p>
<p>
	She used what she learned in Cambodia and Thailand to add sriracha ketchup as a complement to her orange ketchup, and now, her company has a <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/657999288/sosu-barrel-aged-sriracha">Kickstarter</a>&nbsp;to bring a better version of sriracha to the masses and fulfill her mission of reinventing condiments as healthy, delicious sauces. She believes that using jars instead of bottles will get people to think of condiments as sauces they can cook with, too.</p>
<p>
	Then, I tried to get her to tell me all her secrets about the whiskey sriracha that now completes my breakfast.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140506/2-1-copy.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 960px;" /></p>
<p>
	<strong>VICE: First, why don&rsquo;t you tell me about your process and how you make this?</strong><br />
	<strong>Lisa Murphy: </strong>We combined our philosophy of using fresh, locally sourced ingredients with the age-old craft of fermentation. We age our secret pepper mash in whiskey barrels for between one and three months. The sriracha takes on complex flavors from the oak barrels and the natural fermentation process. Absolutely no preservatives or additives go into our sriracha. Each bottle is handcrafted and made in small batches to ensure the most intense flavors.</p>
<p>
	<strong>I&rsquo;m a little confused. How does the company feel about this? Are they trying to shut you down?<br />
	</strong>Actually, you&#39;re not the only one confused. Many people think that &quot;sriracha&quot; is a brand or a trademarked name because we have all become accustomed to only one brand of sriracha. It&rsquo;s actually just the name of a Southeast Asian chili sauce that is prevalent in many parts of Southeast Asia, including Thailand, Laos, Cambodia, and others. Many families have their own recipe of how sriracha should taste.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	<strong>Why sriracha? Is there something that drew you to the condiment?</strong><br />
	We decided to make our own sriracha sauce for a few reasons. First, we were already making our own sriracha<strong>. </strong>We had already been making our own sriracha for our Srirachup, a spicy combination of our own sriracha and ketchup for the past year. Our fans asked us to make a stand-alone sriracha to complement the Srirachup. Also, sriracha is great, but we felt it could be better. SOSU&rsquo;s mission is to take everyday sauces and make them better. We felt that sriracha can be improved by using the old-age craft of fermentation and barrel aging to create complex layers of flavor without the addition of preservatives.</p>
<p>
	Lastly, when I was traveling in Southeast Asia, I discovered that there are different varieties of sriracha in different countries. For example, in Thailand, I discovered that they make a sriracha with fermented fish as a base. In Cambodia, because flavors tend to be sweeter, their sriracha was sweeter. The different variations inspired me to make my own sriracha with the flavors I enjoy.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	<strong>What other sauces do you plan on making?</strong><br />
	We have ketchup, sriracha, and are also planning to launch a barrel-aged hot sauce and sriracha cumin spice rub. We have thought about barbeque sauces, but no firm plans.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Have you ever read Malcolm Gladwell&rsquo;s essay &ldquo;</strong><a href="http://www.newyorker.com/archive/2004/09/06/040906fa_fact_gladwell?currentPage=all"><strong>The Ketchup Conundrum</strong></a><strong>&rdquo;? It basically explains why mustard comes in different varieties but Heinz ketchup continues to dominate, because it hits all the different tastes: sweet, sour, salty, bitter, and umami. What makes sriracha different from, say, ketchup?</strong><br />
	Yes, I have read that essay. I disagree with Malcolm Gladwell. We have had many fans tell us that after they have tasted and tried our ketchups, they never go back to Heinz. When a consumer tastes a fresh tomato versus a paste, fresh tomato ketchup always tastes better. I think the main reasons why Heinz has succeeded in holding onto its market share is its price point and also because people are used to their idea of ketchup should taste like, but they haven&rsquo;t tasted how ketchup can really taste when it is made with fresh ingredients. We are going back to the basics of making ketchup the old way and encouraging people to &ldquo;rediscover ketchup&rdquo; again.</p>
<p>
	When Heinz started making ketchup, it was made with fresh tomatoes. He was a pioneer and entrepreneur in incorporating high-quality ingredients in his ketchup. When he was around in the 1800s, a lot of the ketchup brands&mdash;and his wasn&rsquo;t the only ketchup brand&mdash;came in this amber, pharmaceutical-type packaging, and the amber color would hide what&rsquo;s inside so you wouldn&rsquo;t see what stuff they were using. So Heinz stepped up and said, &ldquo;I focus on quality. I use fresh tomatoes that I source from farmers, and I&rsquo;m going to choose a clear bottle, because I want to show people what&rsquo;s really inside my ketchup.&rdquo; I admire the guy a lot. But if you look at ketchup now, it&rsquo;s changed completely. It&rsquo;s become ingrained in our mind that it&rsquo;s just something that you have around in your fridge, that it shouldn&rsquo;t cost more than $2.99, and when you look at the ingredients, it should have high-fructose corn syrup. That&rsquo;s why when you taste ketchup, it just tastes very sweet, very processed, very glossy. You don&rsquo;t even taste the tomatoes any more. Ketchup can be improved quite a bit.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Thanks, Lisa. Best of luck! </strong></p>
<p>
	<em>You can&rsquo;t get the whiskey-barrel-aged sriracha in stores yet, but you can get a jar if you contribute to SOSU&rsquo;s Kickstarter </em><a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/657999288/sosu-barrel-aged-sriracha"><em>here</em></a><em>. </em></p>
<p>
	<em>Follow Angelina Fanous on <a href="http://www.twitter.com/notsovanilla">Twitter</a></em><em>.</em></p>

]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299325</guid>
<author>Angelina Fanous</author>
<category>food, Sriracha, whiskey, whiskey-barrel-aged, California, San Francisco, homemade, Cambodia, Thailand</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Did Satoshi Nakamoto, Bitcoin&#039;s Elusive Creator, Just Get Unmasked?</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/did-satoshi-nakamoto-bitcoins-elusive-creator-just-get-unmasked-mb-test</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	Nakamoto&rsquo;s identity has been a mystery since the beginning of Bitcoin, with plenty of wild theories fuelling the puzzle&rsquo;s fire. Was he a Japanese mathematician? A cryptography student? A government conspiracy? After two months of reporting, <em>Newsweek</em>&#39;s Leah McGrath Goodman says she&rsquo;s uncovered the truth.</p>

]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299432</guid>
<author>Victoria Turk</author>
<category>tech, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>An Interview with North Korea&#039;s UK Spokesman</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/an-interview-with-north-koreas-uk-spokesman</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140682/londinium1679d-1.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 428px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>Image via <a href="http://friendsofkorea.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">Friends of Korea</a></i></p>
<p>
	North Korea has been getting some fairly rank press in recent years. And in times of such deplorable&nbsp;slander from the &ldquo;monopoly capitalist media of the West,&quot; we must seek to heal these wounds of&nbsp;persecution, these sores of injustice, and hereby mount a unified resistance.</p>
<blockquote>
	<div>
		Oh worthy warrior of Mt Paekdu</div>
	<div>
		leading the stout hearted partisans of</div>
	<div>
		the mighty KPRA to shatter the chains</div>
	<div>
		of Japanese imperialism, shock brigade of</div>
	<div>
		world fascism, to dispatch</div>
	<div>
		the murderous Japs to their doom</div>
</blockquote>
<div>
	&nbsp;</div>
<div>
	Or so Dermot Hudson might think, the UK&rsquo;s delegate for the DPRK&rsquo;s cultural-liaison wing, the Korean Friendship Association (KFA). Hudson is also the poet of the subtle words you just read (but probably didn&#39;t). Now, it&rsquo;s pretty hard to imagine such dubious sermonizing to come from&nbsp;a white guy brought up in England, and you&rsquo;d be forgiven for thinking these words are lifted directly&nbsp;from an early Kim Il-sung essay, or even a revered piece of Kim Jong-un cinema. But Hudson&nbsp;is truly impassioned by the unity of the people, the enrichment of the &quot;Juch&eacute;&nbsp;idea,&quot; and the resistance&nbsp;to &quot;Jap&quot; and US imperialist aggressors. He is equally enamored of the Eternal President Kim&nbsp;Il-sung; of Dear Leader, Respected Leader, Great Leader, Wise Leader, Unique Leader, Great Marshal, Amazing Politician, Savior, Invincible and Ever-Triumphant General Kim Jong-il; and of Marshal, Dear&nbsp;Leader Kim Jong-un (he&rsquo;s young, and the titles come with time).</div>
<div>
	&nbsp;</div>
<div>
	In other words, this guy is up shit creek. Naturally,&nbsp;I decided to contact him.&nbsp;He told me about the times he saw Kim Jong-il, the famine, Western media, and the attitude&nbsp;toward weed. I learned, among other things, that Kim Jong-il moved with a &ldquo;very fast, dignified bearing,&quot; that North Korea is strictly not like Ethiopia in the 70s, and that the Pyongyang metro <em>only</em> costs three cents!</div>
<div>
	&nbsp;</div>
<p>
	<strong>VICE: How did you acquire your position as UK spokesman for the KFA?</strong><br />
	<strong>Dermot Hudson: </strong>I had been the chairman of Juche Idea Study Group of England and the vice president of the old Society for Friendship with Korea. I joined KFA in 2001, about six months after it was formed, and was appointed official delegate for the UK by the KFA International Organization Committee.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Have you met either Kim Jong-il or Kim Jong-un?</strong><br />
	I did not meet them in person but saw them in the distance. I was within a couple 100 feet of Dear Respected Marshal Kim Jong-un, and I saw great comrade Kim Jong-il at a national meeting in April 2002. He looked younger than he was and moved very fast, with a dignified bearing. I have seen Marshal Kim Jong-un in the distance about four or five times. In April 2012, at a military parade, he waved at the crowd. He looked like a very happy person.</p>
<p>
	<strong>What kind of relationship do you have with the government of the DPRK? How do they perceive their place in the international community?</strong><br />
	KFA works with the Korean Committee for Cultural Relations, with which foster relationships with foreign countries. The DPRK sees itself as an independent and nonaligned member of the international community.</p>
<p>
	<strong>You have visited the DPRK on several occasions. What kind of policies did you see that Western countries should imitate?</strong><br />
	Free housing, cheap food, and low-cost public transport. It only costs three cents to use the Pyongyang metro, compared with a $5 minimum fare for London&#39;s subway. Also, free nursery education and free higher education.</p>
<p>
	<strong>The most surprising of policies for many Westerners is the apparently liberal approach to weed. What is the legal status of pot in North Korea?</strong><br />
	I actually think that this is not true. I have never seen anyone in the DPRK under the influence of drugs. Also, there is not room to grow drugs, as all available land is used for rice, maize, wheat, potatoes, and fruit.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Scotland has just legalized gay marriage. What is the attitude toward LGBT people in the DPRK?</strong><br />
	The DPRK has not legalized gay marriage, but it does not have laws prohibiting homosexuality. In the past, DPRK publications have made critical remarks about homosexuality, but it is not seen as a big priority either way.</p>
<p>
	<strong>In the West we hear many differing perceptions of the Juche idea. The most popular is probably that it&#39;s a sinister tool to fuel and empower the unremitting nationalism. What are your views on this?</strong><br />
	I would strongly dispute this. Juche means that man is the master and can decide everything. It means that the popular masses are the masters of the revolution and construction. Yes, Juche does mean independence, but why should this be seen as something negative? I always find it contradictory and strange that some big countries like to complain about the nationalism of small countries. I am sure many Scottish people will agree with me.&nbsp;Juche embraces both national and international tasks. It has spread beyond the borders of the DPRK and is studied in many countries throughout the world. There are over 1,000 Juche Idea Study Groups in different countries.</p>
<p>
	<strong>We hear a lot about the DPRK in the West&mdash;strong elitism, famine, poverty, and dubious executions of dissidents and defectors. How much of this is distorted to suit the intended Western perception?</strong><br />
	Strong elitism does not exist in the DPRK . Everyone enjoys equality of opportunity. Officials are bound by law to do one day of manual labor per week&mdash;if you notice, Kim Jong-un and high officials all wear ordinary workers clothes.&nbsp;There have been food shortages in the past, but there&#39;s no famine; no one is starving.&nbsp;The situation is not like Ethiopia in the 1970s.</p>
<p>
	The only recent execution was that of Jang Sung-thaek, the counter-revolutionary traitor. He was not a dissident but a very corrupt man who&nbsp;tried to carry out a military coup and restore capitalism. It was the demand&nbsp;of the people that he be executed.&nbsp;Some so-called defectors are not really from the DPRK but South Korean&nbsp;agents posing as &quot;defectors.&quot; &quot;Shin whatever&quot; (Shin Dong-hyuk, undeserving of a name I imagine), the author of <em>Escape from Camp 14</em>, was found by a Russian expert on South Korea to speak with a South Korean accent. Those defectors who did really come from the DPRK are often people who committed serious crimes like murder, rape, and theft and have run away to the South to avoid punishment. Of course, some innocent people have been tricked or lured to South Korea with the promise of big money.&nbsp;So yes, a lot of these things are distorted and are false perceptions created by&nbsp;the monopoly capitalist media of the West.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Marcus Noland, the deputy director of the Peterson Institute for International Economics, in Washington, DC, has spent much of his time analyzing the DPRK and has observed that per capita income today is &quot;lower than it was 20 years ago and by some reckonings is only now attaining the&nbsp;level it achieved in the 1970s.&quot; Would you put this in line with the distorted media perception, or is North Korea really struggling to negotiate economic hurdles?</strong><br />
	This is a rather silly statement from a very right-wing pro-austerity think tank in the US. The DPRK&#39;s peak year was 1993. During the 1990s the DPRK went through the &quot;arduous march,&quot; due to natural disasters and imperialist sanctions, so there were definitely problems; however, the DPRK recovered and reached peak production a few years ago. To say that income is lower than 20 years ago is ludicrous. How on earth could the DPRK carry out massive construction projects if its income was lower than 20 years ago?</p>
<p>
	<strong>There have been reports that Kim Jong-un is interested in experimenting with economic reform. How likely is it that North Korea will be forced to succumb to the creeping globalizing nature of capitalism, particularly considering China&#39;s growing hostility toward the DPRK?</strong><br />
	Marshal Kim Jong-un is determined that the DPRK will follow its own road and rejects copying other countries. Comrade Kim Jong-il said, &quot;The imperialist reactionaries are now slandering our Republic, the motherland of Juche, claiming that it is &lsquo;closed&rsquo; and &lsquo;isolated&rsquo; and are making futile attempts to lead us to reform and openness.&quot; Our country has never closed its doors, and it maintains good relations with many countries, home to billions of people, around the world, based on mutual respect. As for reform, we reformed the outdated social system in a revolutionary fashion decades ago, and have been constantly creating the new and renovating what is old and backward. In actual fact, the imperialists and reactionaries are hostile towards our country and are blockading it and trying to&nbsp;isolate it. The &quot;reform&quot; and &quot;openness&quot; they are advocating represent a move to destroy and put down our style of socialism. Such moves will only worsen their relations with us and are doomed to failure.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Are the North Korean people not confused by the contradictory nature of Kim&nbsp;Jong-un&#39;s hearty public welcome to the US when we visited with Dennis Rodman, considering the well-documented contempt for American imperialism?</strong><br />
	No, because the DPRK&#39;s quarrel is with US imperialism and rulers of the&nbsp;US empire, not ordinary American people.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Does the continuation of the DPRK&#39;s nuclear program conflict with the original principles of Kim Il-sung, who once said the DPRK &quot;would&nbsp;never have nuclear weapons&quot; and who also wrote, in his engaging essay <em>For a Free and Peaceful World</em>, that &quot;the testing and production of nuclear weapons must be banned, the number of existing nuclear weapons must be reduced and then, nuclear weapons must be completely abolished&quot;?</strong><br />
	The situation has moved on a lot since 1991, when that particular speech of President Kim Il-sung&#39;s was made. The main factor that decided the issue of developing weapons was the fact that the US declared the DPRK to be a target of a US first nuclear strike. Also, you had the aggression by the&nbsp;US against Afghanistan and Iraq, so the DPRK decided to use all means to deter US aggression. The DPRK is still committed to the denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, but the US must make the first move and withdraw the 1,000 nuclear weapons that they have in South Korea. The DPRK would dismantle its nuclear weapons when the US and all other nuclear powers do the same.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Finally, it has been announced that families split by the Korean War will be given the opportunity of reunion. Reunification seems to be a salient feature of North Korean policy. How long do you think this will this take to achieve?</strong><br />
	A question that is both difficult and easy to answer. I guess that if the US pulled out of South Korea tomorrow, then reunification will come quickly. If the Korean people unite as one and fight the US, then reunification will not take long.</p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/297252</guid>
<author>Angus Blair</author>
<category>stuff, DPRK, Korea Friendship Association, Dermot Hudson</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Putin Will Get Everything He Wants in Crimea</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/why-putin-will-get-everything-he-wants-in-crimea</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 15:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<iframe frameborder="0" height="587" scrolling="no" src="//embed.gettyimages.com/embed/476758727?et=v-6IgFLYaEOoiCEKxZMI_Q&amp;sig=yo3UguzfrNwWdm8ikoxEKfJivFAE4ucWzzYoCCY-QDM=" width="640"></iframe></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>This story is from VICE News, our new news website. See more at <a href="http://www.vicenews.com">vicenews.com</a>. </i></p>
<p>
	Even before the Crimean parliament voted unanimously today to ask Moscow for permission to become a part of Russia, Russian forces had all but completed the process of establishing a new reality on the ground in Crimea&mdash;that the region simply isn&rsquo;t under the control of the central Ukrainian government in Kiev anymore. And so, barring a major military response by the Ukrainian Army or a massive Russian excursion into Eastern Ukraine, it looks like Putin&rsquo;s endgame is about to unfold.</p>
<p>
	Many analysts have made mention of the Russian naval base at Sevastopol and how, as Russia&rsquo;s main warm-water naval installation, it is of key importance to Russia. Negotiations with Ukraine over Russia&#39;s continuing operation of the base have gotten tense in the past, although a 2010 agreement gave Russia a lease until 2042.</p>
<p>
	Just to be safe, however, Russia has been quietly building a potential replacement at Novorossiysk, a commercial port a couple hundred miles east that has the notable distinction of actually being in Russia. It could house the Black Sea Fleet if Russia were to lose Sevastopol, and further expansion of naval facilities there could reduce or even eliminate Russian dependence on Crimea.</p>
<p>
	If the Russian Navy stays in Sevastopol, and Crimea stays in Ukraine, Ukraine would almost certainly be blocked from joining NATO. Ukraine has been trying to join for years to protect itself from&hellip; well, from this. But a country can&rsquo;t join NATO if it has a foreign military base on its soil. So, if Russia stays in Sevastopol and Crimea stays in Ukraine, it means Ukraine can&rsquo;t join NATO. This is a positive for Russia, because it makes it easier to lean on Ukraine in the future, especially if Kiev gets a little too buddy-buddy with Europe.</p>
<p>
	A Crimean vote on whether or not to join Russia is now scheduled for March 16. If Crimeans vote in favor of it, there&rsquo;s a chance the region could become a &ldquo;frozen territory,&rdquo; typically the result of a cease-fire announcement during hostilities, which freezes boundaries to match areas of military control. Frozen countries are usually considered by much of the world to be under military occupation, and few such zones ever receive formal diplomatic recognition as independent states. This is what happened in the aftermath of the 2008 Russia-Georgia War, which gave birth to the Republics of Abkhazia and South Ossetia. Those zones are recognized as countries by Russia, Nicaragua, Venezuela, Nauru, Tuvalu, and no one else&mdash;aside, of course, from other frozen states.</p>
<p>
	The frozen-state scenario would put the West in a delicate position. If the West were to recognize Crimean independence, it would open the gates for a closer Ukraine-NATO relationship, thanks to Sevastopol no longer being an issue. But it would do so at the risk of ticking off Ukrainians by legitimizing Crimea&rsquo;s secession. If the West were to make a stand and refuse to recognize what will inevitably be billed as Crimea&#39;s &ldquo;legitimate democratic vote of determination&rdquo; for independence, it would do so at the risk of putting a legal barrier between itself and Ukraine, thanks to Sevastopol still being an issue.</p>
<p>
	In addition, if the West recognizes Crimea, it creates a more complex situation regarding diplomatic recognition of all the other frozen territories that have been hatched out of Russian military intervention: Abkhazia, South Ossetia, Transnistria, and Nagorno-Karabakh. This could serve to help usher in a new 21st Century form of conflict, in which moving a border via invasion is highly discouraged, but chipping off a chunk of a country in the name of self-determination is fairly acceptable. That debate will be very relevant as the international community decides how to move forward with ethnic separatists following the creation of new countries like East Timor and South Sudan.</p>
<p>
	When it comes down to it, the few diplomatic carrots that the West is willing to offer or withhold from Russia have only as much value as Putin is willing to assign them. His ability to not give a shit exceeds the West&#39;s capacity to do anything he gives a shit about. The fact is that Russia cares a lot more about Crimea than anybody else does&mdash;except for Ukraine.</p>
<p>
	And that&#39;s not to mention the two cards Putin has yet to play. The first: He could cripple the already fragile European economy. Europe is heavily dependent on Russian gas and oil to keep the lights on, and Putin can cut it off&mdash;about 40 percent of Europe&rsquo;s oil and gas supply&mdash;with a phone call. The global economic consequences from that would be ugly.</p>
<p>
	The second: Efforts to get Bashar Assad to come to heel and to convince Iran to ditch its nuclear-weapons program are basically doomed without Putin&rsquo;s help (though, to be fair, the prospects for both of these negotiations are pretty grim anyway). Without any Russian support, the US would probably have to chalk both efforts up as losses.</p>
<p>
	And so the question becomes whether the West cares more about a worldwide economic downturn, Syrian chemical weapons, and Iranian nukes&mdash;or about an historically prickly peninsula in the Black Sea full of people who, however misguidedly, sound like they&#39;d rather be Russians anyway.</p>
<p>
	Many in the West have been making some grievous miscalculations in framing these events. Wonk chatter has been about preventing further escalation, reducing tensions, and providing an &ldquo;off-ramp&rdquo; allowing Putin to back down. Some talking heads have tried to stuff these events into a traditional nation-vs.-nation, Cold War mold. Others have tried to attribute the ineffectiveness of the Western response to the fact that Putin is insane. These approaches do little but make Westerners feel better about themselves.</p>
<p>
	The reality is that Crimea is all but a done deal. Putin saw something he wanted and an opportunity to take it. So he sent in troops and set about establishing that new reality on the ground. The bulk of negotiations in the coming days and weeks will involve Western officials trying to prove that Russia hasn&rsquo;t gotten the better of them&mdash;the &ldquo;compromise&rdquo; reached will be almost exactly what Putin wanted all along, in the guise of a diplomatic victory preventing an armed conflict&mdash;so they can try to preserve Western credibility. They know they&#39;ll need it for the next crisis that comes along.</p>
<p>
	<em><a href="http://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZaT_X_mc0BI-djXOlfhqWQ">Subscribe to VICE News on YouTube</a>.</em></p>
<p>
	<em><a href="https://twitter.com/vicenews" target="_blank">Follow VICE News on Twitter</a>.</em></p>
<p>
	<em><a href="https://www.facebook.com/vicenews" target="_blank">Like VICE News on Facebook</a>.</em></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299444</guid>
<author>Ryan Faith</author>
<category>news, Vladimir Putin, Crimea, Russian Politics, ukraine, ukraine protests</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>American Art Needs More Holes</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/american-art-needs-more-holes</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140476/hyesoon.jpg" style="width: 642px; height: 353px;" /></p>
<p>
	The biggest hindrance to American art is the inability to see anything outside our own walls. We&rsquo;re proud of being a &ldquo;melting pot,&rdquo; but when it comes to culture not inherently American (Wendy&rsquo;s, baseball, crime drama, pop music, fences), it&rsquo;s hard to convince us that we should care. In literature, as opposed to other media, introducing work to a US audience requires translation, an undertaking that brings with it a bag of problems most profit-oriented American publishers won&rsquo;t approach unless it&rsquo;s a ready-made bonanza, like the books of Roberto Bola&ntilde;o. Imagine, then, the continuum of masterworks we&rsquo;re missing out on from every language we don&rsquo;t speak.</p>
<p>
	In the introduction to Kim Hyesoon&rsquo;s <em>All The Garbage of the World, Unite!</em>, translator Don Mee Choi recounts a great example of the type of problem translated works often run into. An American literary journal, after showing interest in one of Choi&rsquo;s Korean-to-English translations of a Kim poem, requested that the word &ldquo;hole&rdquo; be replaced with something else, on the grounds that &ldquo;hole has negative connotations in our culture.&rdquo; Choi had used the word in reminding her reader that, during the Korean War, 250,000 pounds of napalm were dropped by the American military each day, turning her country into a mass of holes where once there had been houses, mountains, rice fields. She told the magazine she &ldquo;didn&rsquo;t have time to think about it.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Kim is no stranger to stodgy literary types. At the time she began writing, classical forms in the hands of aristocratic men had long dominated Korean poetry. &ldquo;I often felt as if my tongue were paralyzed,&rdquo; Kim has said. &ldquo;For me the vast open field of the unknown and the prison existed simultaneously.&rdquo; Over time, poetry in her country has slowly opened up with the rise of free verse, feminism, and activism.</p>
<p>
	Reading Kim&rsquo;s most recent translated work, <em><a href="http://www.actionbooks.org">Sorrowtoothpaste Mirrorcream</a></em>, one finds a swarming body of imagination and ideas, which, given the book&#39;s social context, could hardly be more rebellious. Any traditional mythos of &ldquo;the woman&rdquo; has been completely shattered into a body teeming with imagery that mutates from line to line, melding everyday roles such as mother and teacher into phantasmagoric collages of rats wearing black bras, a house with hands buried in chocolate cake, aspirin hatching into more aspirin. The limits of creativity here are so wide that very quickly we find we&rsquo;ve fallen through the holes old wars blew open, into something like the endless dreams of millions dead.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140475/sorrowtoothpaste.jpg" style="width: 642px; height: 856px;" /></p>
<p>
	<strong>Two Poems from Kim Hyesoon&rsquo;s <em>Sorrowtoothpaste Mirrorcream</em></strong></p>
<p>
	&quot;Blood Blooms&quot;</p>
<p>
	It runs to avoid a streak of rain that follows like the needle of a sewing machine then</p>
<p>
	turns at the corner and pulls out red bricks from its body and builds a wall then</p>
<p>
	runs off with even more zeal when the street lamps come on prick-prick as they chase<br />
	after it &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	listens carefully to the anxious cicadas slicing up the road then</p>
<p>
	when the windows of the building in the distance are lit up as I get cramps in my ankle</p>
<p>
	watches the red nostrils of a white cat spilling blood beneath the wall then</p>
<p>
	coagulates on the whitest white wall that&rsquo;s like a bolt of cotton unrolled</p>
<p>
	when the needle enters the body and exits pulling out a tiny vein</p>
<p>
	the blood vessel swells then spurts unable to hold back one blossom two blossoms then</p>
<p>
	the thorns poke through every sweat pore ah it&rsquo;s prickly ah it&#39;s prickly then</p>
<p>
	a tiny bird gets its head chomped by the white cat&rsquo;s mouth<br />
	a tiny red heart in my hand flutters then says<br />
	The road ahead miles long is a field of roses<br />
	I got caught after running away, shedding a blood-filled stem<br />
	I&rsquo;ve finally bloomed after a hundred years a thousand years<br />
	yet the red silk that I step on with a pair of white socks is a puddle of blood<br />
	I&rsquo;m endlessly dizzy after a lifetime of transfusions and so<br />
	I wither around the corner<br />
	Spurting up red every single day makes me turn blue</p>
<p>
	&mdash;the roses were blooming<br />
	but they had spilt blood then left &nbsp;</p>
<p>
	<br />
	<strong>&quot;All the Rats of the World, Unite!&quot;</strong></p>
<p>
	As I run towards the school gate, wet from the rain, I hear footsteps behind me tap tap tap<br />
	tap</p>
<p>
	Dearteacherdearteacherhowareyou?inmydreamlastnightItookaplanefromthe<br />
	cloudtothemoonthentotheratnation</p>
<p>
	The dark wet metallic mirror shatters beneath my feet and a pack of rats climbs all over<br />
	me</p>
<p>
	My wrist that myfathermymothermyteacher used to pull, the wrists cling on</p>
<p>
	and braid their long hair, the pack of rats climb up my pants like barbarians drenched in rain</p>
<p>
	<em>Even while I&rsquo;m running in rain a pair of rats mate. My male rat and my female rat copulate about twenty times a day, and if capable the male mates with other female rats. The female&rsquo;s gestation period is 21 days. 8 or 10 rats are born from a single belly. Give birth then get pregnant then give birth then get pregnant. They give birth twelve times a year. Baby rats give birth to more baby rats, then give birth again, so then I&rsquo;m able to give birth to myself 15000 times per year.</em></p>
<p>
	Black words are written on a white face, K H S scrawled faintly with a finger, my name<br />
	in black, the consonants and vowels splashed onto my face by a tail dipped in ink</p>
<p>
	The speeding bus splatters memories, a schoolgirl in a wet summer uniform lies down in<br />
	the bus and weeps. The rat hidden inside her skirt pregnant with a litter of ten, twenty rats<br />
	cries like a crazy cat</p>
<p>
	The smelly pigtails drenched in rain, the raging barbarians<br />
	I have enough holes in my body to sink the sky</p>
<p>
	Tails are attached to countless rain-splattering shoes&nbsp;<br />
	The filthy garden beneath the black asphalt fills up with water</p>
<p>
	Hey kids, don&rsquo;t gnaw on the wires, turn off the lights in the classroom</p>
<p>
	<em>When I leave the basementsflocktogether. Storagesflocktogether. Shedsflocktogether. Womenintheshedswiththeirskirtsliftedflocktogether. Sewersflocktogether. Septictanksflocktogether. Garbagebinsflocktogether. Horsestablesflocktogether. Prisonsflocktogether. Disappearedwomenflocktogether. Lungs fly off like rats, intestines slip out like rats, tongues elongate like rats, chins fall out like rats, ears buzz like rats, muscles crumble like a pack of rats. Knees give out like rats and feet run off like rats. </em></p>
<p>
	A horde of rats runs spitting out blood after being wacked by a broom woven with streaks<br />
	of rain</p>
<p>
	I feel like crying so don&rsquo;t look at me! I&rsquo;m a teacher but inside why am I always a<br />
	pigtailed schoolgirl?</p>
<p>
	A rat as big as a house lifts and ignites a heart as small as an infant&rsquo;s fingernail and runs<br />
	off</p>
<p>
	<em>Buy Sorrowtoothpaste Mirrorcream and other books that you should have on your shelf at <a href="http://www.actionbooks.org/">actionbooks.org</a>.</em></p>
<p>
	<em>Follow Blake Butler on <a href="http://twitter.com/blakebutler">Twitter</a></em></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299302</guid>
<author>Blake Butler</author>
<category>stuff, Blake Butler, poetry, korea, art, literature, translations, read this, Literary, Kim Hyesoon</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Examining the Pull of Group Masturbation Parties</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/examining-the-pull-of-group-masturbation-parties-</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 15:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<iframe frameborder="0" height="502" scrolling="no" src="//embed.gettyimages.com/embed/JB4796-001?et=e05IMBw3FUmNmXprkacouA&amp;sig=O_Qyui66oGY_JcWcf8UEnstUe-mBHb-rMjOZEjeMDn8=" width="640"></iframe></p>
<p>
	Of the various group masturbation parties 30-year-old nudist Kyle Rudd has attended over the years, the biggest one drew a dozen-odd men, predominantly over 50. He was the third to arrive that night, and when he walked inside, the host and another guy were already naked. As the remainder of the guests sauntered in, conversation centered on things like work, how the week had been, and the bodies and penises on display. Rudd did most of his masturbating&mdash;a blend of group and solo&mdash;from the vantage point of the organizer&rsquo;s couch and managed to ejaculate on himself three or four times in six hours. In the breaks between these bouts of industry, Rudd, a Melbourne-based arts-sector employee, spent his time socializing, drinking beer, and eating pizza.</p>
<p>
	While some men might prefer to spend their weekends watching the game or relaxing with the family, Rudd says he had a great time.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;I find genitals to be very erotic&mdash;ten out of ten,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;For me, I think being exposed and on display is very erotic. It&rsquo;s knowing that others are admiring your genitals as they mutually get off on it.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	For anybody entertaining the idea of attending a group masturbation party, the grassroots DIY scene is a fertile field of opportunity, according to Rudd.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;My participation is always privately organized groups through masturbation networking sites. They are pretty common. There&rsquo;s definitely one big one every weekend that I could go to, and smaller groups. Even one-on-one ones are happening every day that I&rsquo;m aware of.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;And we have online wanking groups too, where guys wank on group cam. I do this a few days a week.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	While a lot of these parties are one-off DIY affairs informally staged in homes, long-standing jerking institution <a href="http://www.melbournewankers.com.au/home.html" target="_blank">Melbourne Wankers</a> lays claim to being Australia&rsquo;s only formally organized group masturbating &ldquo;club&rdquo; (it used to keep a database of members, but these days anybody can rock up), according to organizer Peter Benn. The club, known to play host to up to 100 men furiously masturbating at once, stages its parties at a sauna on the second and fourth Monday of every month. For the $20 admission fee, participants have access to a bar, towels, and lockers, and the lubricant of choice, grape-seed oil, is freely available in squeeze-pack form.</p>
<p>
	A military tarp and sheets blanket the floor of the main room, where dozens of men will unabashedly wax their dolphins together. These sheets go into an industrial washing machine to help simplify the cleanup job that follows the three-hour-long events.</p>
<p>
	&quot;Having 30 guys in the room all at once is a pretty good number,&quot; Benn says, sitting cross-legged on an armchair in his bookish inner-city living room. &ldquo;You generally get small groups of two guys, three guys, or four guys. You won&rsquo;t get more than four or five, but as you play you&rsquo;ll move from little group to little group. It&rsquo;s much more chatty. Conversation is really important. The lights are up, the music is soft, and there&rsquo;s a lot of oil on bodies, so it&rsquo;s a very touchy-feely event. It&rsquo;s a more intimate relationship between the men... It&rsquo;s the feeling of being in a group and looking at other guys and talking to other guys, and it works because it&rsquo;s all in the one room. Therefore you&rsquo;re hearing everything, you&rsquo;re seeing everything, and everybody&rsquo;s a part of it.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Group masturbation clubs emerged in the 1980s, when public fear of AIDS was in overdrive. They were conceived as environments where men could meet up to manually gratify one another without running the risks associated with penetrative sex. Several clubs such as the New York Jacks and San Francisco Jacks continue to thrive internationally (kindred clubs operate everywhere from France to Finland to Mexico) but getting a club off the ground and building traction is no easy feat.</p>
<p>
	Benn says a couple of men used to run a club out of their Canberra, Australia farmhouse every Thursday night, but the party ended when they sold the property a couple of years back. Another Sydney club folded after six months because of low numbers, and other attempts to start under-30s parties have failed dismally.</p>
<p>
	Yet Melbourne Wankers continues to pull men, so to speak.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;At a meeting the other night, there were three guys from Perth. It&rsquo;s amazing how they find you; it&rsquo;s just word of mouth,&rdquo; says Benn.</p>
<p>
	Benn estimates two thirds of the participants at Melbourne Wankers are married. His book, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Versatile-Husband-Peter-Benn-ebook/dp/B008GMT61S" target="_blank"><em>The Versatile Husband</em></a>, a so-called practical guide for men in heterosexual relationships who are interested in sex with other men, explores how these men make the decision to have sex with other men.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;Men get isolated and don&rsquo;t have touch in their lives. Touch is banned by everybody, and these men get more and more isolated in their marriage.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;They lose that intimacy that you have at the start of your marriage where you can&rsquo;t keep your hands off each other. Ten years on, where has it gone?&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Many of the men identify as heterosexual, which makes perfect sense to sexologist Dr. Carol Queen, an advocate for the destigmatization of masturbation.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;One explanation would be that this is a guy who could also identify as bisexual but doesn&#39;t, maybe because he only has relationships with women, or maybe because he&#39;s never actually done sexual stuff with a cock but just likes to see them.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;The other way I can see it working is that he likes his own cock, and it&#39;s a sort of positive identification/fellow-feeling he experiences being around other cocks.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	In the book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Everything-Know-About-Wrong-Disinformation/dp/1932857176" target="_blank"><em>Everything You Know About Sex is Wrong: The Disinformation Guide to the Extremes of Sexuality</em></a>, Martha Cornog, one of the authors in the collection, highlights that group masturbation clubs have historically emphasized the importance of pleasure, fellowship, and the acceptance of human diversity. Men come to express exhibitionistic and voyeuristic tendencies, to experience the religious-like synergistic energy that evolves out of the group sex experience, and to enjoy camaraderie.</p>
<p>
	But public awareness of the scene is low. Rudd says only a couple of his friends know about his involvement with group masturbation parties. &ldquo;Normal day-to-day (people) at work or with families do not know about this stuff,&quot; he says. &quot;I think the general consensus would be negative or they would find it shocking.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Benn concurs.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;It&rsquo;s a subject matter that confronts you when you find out about it. People think, <em>Fuck, that&rsquo;s not for me. I&rsquo;m not going down there</em>. It&rsquo;s so not for so many people.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	But the scene&rsquo;s taboo status bodes well for its participants, adds Benn. &ldquo;Because it&rsquo;s so odd and unusual, it drifts along quietly in its own way, and that&rsquo;s exactly what the married man and groups want.&rdquo;<br />
	&nbsp;</p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/298568</guid>
<author>Joshua Jennings</author>
<category>stuff, masturbation, parties, Pull, Beating Off, nudists, penis, erotic, sex, naked, fetish, orgasm, Melbourne Wankers</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>We Called Ordinary Russians and Tried to Broker World Peace</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/trying-to-broker-world-peace-with-ordinary-russians</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en">
	<p>
		Been speaking to ordinary Russians about the situation in Ukraine. We are united in confusion <a href="http://t.co/Oc8n145SJo">http://t.co/Oc8n145SJo</a> <a href="http://t.co/MYNt7JUEda">pic.twitter.com/MYNt7JUEda</a></p>
	&mdash; Gavin Haynes (@gavhaynes) <a href="https://twitter.com/gavhaynes/statuses/441557794039136256">March 6, 2014</a></blockquote>
<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script><p>
	In case you hadn&rsquo;t noticed yet, the Russians are going to kill us all. If you are reading this, it probably means they haven&rsquo;t killed us yet, but make no mistake&mdash;since Monday we have been teetering on the brink of World War III. One gun-cleaning error <a href="http://www.vice.com/en_uk/vice-news/russian-roulette-the-invasion-of-ukraine-dispatch-2" target="_blank">at a military base in Sevastopol</a>, and the whole house of cards could come tumbling down by the weekend: the Russian flag fluttering not for the first time over the Reichstag, the &quot;Song of the Volga Boatmen&quot; blasting from Tannoys at Milan Central Station, war, apocalypse, death, and bad times.</p>
<p>
	Unfortunately, Vlad Putin is no longer in touch with reality. But even the most absolute of monarchs is still to some degree a servant of the people. Surely, if we could just get through to ordinary Russians, and convince them of the rightness of getting the hell out of Ukraine and not killing everyone, then they&rsquo;d stop him, take to the streets, and all us Western liberals would be saved?</p>
<p>
	<a href="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140550/1622483-10153918866075195-333393841-o-2.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140550/1622483-10153918866075195-333393841-o-2.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 231px;" /></a></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Click to enlarge</em></p>
<p>
	So, while David Cameron was busy serious-facing himself to Twitter ridicule, and <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/mar/05/ukraine-crisis-russia-nato-talks-live" target="_blank">the international community</a> was failing to persuade a poxy Russian envoy to talk to Ukraine&#39;s new, Western-approved president, a translator and I spent an afternoon mashing our fists against the phone keypad, plugging unknown Russian phone numbers into our switchboard, in an attempt to get a message of peace through to the other side.</p>
<p>
	We wanted dialogue, peace, a collective consciousness of our common humanity. We got about 20 phones slammed down instantly, another ten who hung up at exactly the point in any conversation with an &quot;unknown number&quot; where you suspect someone might be about to try to sell you car insurance, and three or so who didn&rsquo;t seem to be able to operate a mobile phone despite possessing one. In between those, we got through to a few Russians who were at least prepared to listen to our pleas, even if they had far more difficulty giving a flying fuck.</p>
<p>
	The first was a restaurant in the southeast of Moscow: Art Kafe. Seemed nice. A blini and chai kinda place. Judging by <a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/@55.647669,37.736779,3a,37.5y,358.45h,98.88t/data=!3m4!1e1!3m2!1sEsCFoJeXIGfBtd3ircJPdQ!2e0!6m1!1e1" target="_blank">Street View</a>, I imagined that it might make a nice Central Perk in a sitcom about hip Russian twenty-somethings.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140553/burgermeister-22-2-big.jpg" style="width: 538px; height: 640px;" /></p>
<p>
	<em>Translations by Ksenia Vashchenko</em></p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Hello. Am I talking with a real Russian?</strong><br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong>      ?<br />
	<strong>Real Russian Man:</strong> Da.<br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: You&rsquo;re sure of that?</strong><br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong>  ?<br />
	<strong>Real Russian:</strong> Da.<br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Great. I bring a message of peace from the West.</strong><br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong>        .<br />
	<strong>Real Russian:</strong> Allo?</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: We are from the West.</strong><br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong> <em>[&ldquo;We are from the West. We are from a magazine. We would like to talk about the crisis in Ukraine?&rdquo;]</em><br />
	Phone:<em> [Click]</em></p>
<p>
	Clearly, this was going to be more difficult than we&rsquo;d anticipated. What was with these Russians? The Russian people seemed, well, not exactly nice, but they had vocal cords, and that was a good start. So we dialed a library in St. Petersburg. St. Petersburg is hip. Librarians are soft, pudgy people with tote bags who have a lot of time on their hands to talk to randoms. Right?</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140554/DSC-0796.jpg" style="width: 450px; height: 300px;" /></p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Hello. Sorry to trouble you. We are from a magazine, talking to people about Crimea&hellip;</strong><br />
	<strong>Real Russian woman:</strong> Da.<br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong> Yes?<br />
	<br />
	<strong>Me: So Crimea... We are wondering when Russians are going to get out of Ukraine. Because, to be frank, we were rather hoping they&rsquo;d be gone by now&hellip;</strong><br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong> She says she cannot speak on behalf of anyone. It is a question that gives her many thoughts, but she is at work now.<br />
	<br />
	<strong>Me: Well perhaps you could possibly tell all the Russians that you know that you spoke to a man from the West, and despite all the propaganda, we are not all twisted heartless monsters.</strong><br />
	<strong>Phone: </strong><em>[Click]</em></p>
<p>
	We tried a few random mobiles by jiggling the digits of real Russian numbers that our translator had pulled off her phone.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140556/9171372009-c80ae94212-z.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 403px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Photo by <a class="owner-name truncate" data-track="attributionNameClick" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/m1key-me/" title="Go to Micha Huniewicz's photostream">Micha Huniewicz</a></em></p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Zdtravstvuytye</strong>.<br />
	<strong>Real Russian: </strong>Allo?<br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong> <em>[&ldquo;We are from a magazine. We would like to talk about the conflict in Ukraine?&rdquo;]</em></p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Hello. I bring a message of peace from our land. We would like to know what real Russians feel about Crimea.</strong><br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong> She says she doesn&rsquo;t know what&rsquo;s going on in Ukraine.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Doesn&rsquo;t she? It&rsquo;s very, very bad. I mean, it&rsquo;s appalling. Which is why we would like ordinary Russians, if possible, to try to prevent World War III?</strong><br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong> She says she doesn&rsquo;t know anything about this.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Do you think you could ask Mr. Putin to get his troops out of Ukraine?</strong><br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong> She doesn&rsquo;t understand the question.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Perhaps you could&mdash;</strong><br />
	<strong>Phone:</strong> <em>[Click]</em></p>
<p>
	So it went. Russian after Russian refusing our olive branch, ignoring the hand of friendship with a brusque &ldquo;<em>nyet</em>,&rdquo; or a more fearful excuse about being &quot;at work,&quot; or &quot;in a hurry.&quot; Vlad had knobbled them. No doubt. We had begun to despair at the fecklessness of the common people. It was time to go all the way to the top. In most countries, this would mean the presidency. In Russia, however, their oligarchical model of government means that the tippermost-of-the-toppermost is actually the biggest oil company. Gazprom press office it was, then:</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140569/w750-img-04-1.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 417px;" /></p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Hello. Do you speak English?</strong><br />
	<strong>Gazprom press officer: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Amazing. Could you please tell us about Russia&rsquo;s plans in Ukraine?</strong><br />
	<strong><strong>Gazprom press officer:</strong></strong> Sorry, can you introduce yourself please?</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Yes. We&rsquo;re calling from VICE magazine. We&rsquo;re trying to get a Russian perspective on Ukraine and whether we&rsquo;re all going to die.</strong><br />
	<strong><strong>Gazprom press officer:</strong></strong> All news was out yesterday. For today we have no updates.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Do you think Ed Miliband&rsquo;s position on Ukraine is justified?</strong><br />
	<strong><strong>Gazprom press officer:</strong></strong> Sir, I am not an official spokesman. I am only working in the press office.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Can you put me on to a spokesman, then?</strong><br />
	<strong><strong><strong>Gazprom press officer:</strong></strong> </strong>Can you speak loudly in the tube? Because I cannot hear you.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Sorry, in &quot;the tube&quot;?</strong><br />
	<strong><strong>Gazprom press officer:</strong></strong> Because it&rsquo;s noisy here and I cannot hear you.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Is this better?</strong><br />
	<strong><strong>Gazprom press officer:</strong></strong> I think so.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: OK. Right. So what about David Cameron? Do you think Russian people like him? Could they give him a chance, maybe? He has very soft skin.</strong><br />
	<strong><strong>Gazprom press officer:</strong></strong> I&rsquo;m sorry, but we can only talk about the situation with gas in Ukraine. Other information we don&rsquo;t give out. We are not a political organization.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: OK. Well, is there going to be more gas in Ukraine tomorrow or less gas?</strong><br />
	<strong><strong>Gazprom press officer:</strong></strong> I&rsquo;m sorry, you didn&rsquo;t ask your question about supplying gas. Otherwise not at all.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: But if there&rsquo;s World War III, there&rsquo;ll definitely be less gas.</strong><br />
	<strong><strong>Gazprom press officer:</strong></strong> Well, you see, we don&rsquo;t comment the situation also. We comment only about amount of gas. All your information you can find to news agencies.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Or maybe&hellip; more?</strong><br />
	<strong><strong><strong>Gazprom press officer:</strong></strong> </strong>You are asking me prohibited questions. Thank you for your calling, goodbye.</p>
<p>
	Maybe Russia&rsquo;s largest bank, the only slightly embarrassingly named Sberbank, would be able to offer us a firmer fix on whether Muscovite savers were even now withdrawing their last roubles as Putin set the seal on orders for his crack regiments to cross the border of a sovereign country and rain unholy fire down upon it in &quot;self-defense,&quot; much like he already had in South Ossetia, etc, etc.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140567/big.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 438px;" /></p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Zdtravstvuytye. We&rsquo;re just calling to check with Russian citizens about the situation in Ukraine. Does Sberbank have a line on that?</strong><br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong> She asks if you have a concrete question.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Yes. Right. Are you preparing for World War III down there?</strong><br />
	<strong>Translator: </strong>She can&rsquo;t express an opinion on that, because they only deal with questions on email.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Perhaps you will be able to tell us whether the tyrant Putin will be overthrown soon?</strong><br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong> She says they only deal with questions on email, so you cannot ask her anything specific.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Well, in that case, I would like to send a message of peace from the West to the people of Russia, saying, &quot;Please don&rsquo;t kill us.&quot; We have a lot to live for here. I know we gripe about our lives a lot of the time, but actually it&rsquo;s really great here. I mean, I have an iPhone 5 and I only earn a moderate salary. That&rsquo;s something to be grateful for. So we would like to not be killed, if that is OK?</strong><br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong> She says, &quot;Yes, thank you, goodbye.&quot;</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Do you have a reciprocal message of peace for me?</strong><br />
	<strong>Translator:</strong> She says &ldquo;Yes, of course. Thank you so much for your call, please find our email online and contact us. We will deal with your question.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: That&rsquo;s not quite what I&mdash;</strong><br />
	<strong>Phone:</strong> <em>[click]</em></p>
<p>
	It appeared that the culture gap was too broad for us to leap across. We might&rsquo;ve gotten over the era when a simple pair of Levi&rsquo;s would be enough to make any Russian sell you really high-quality no-messing sexual favors. But they still had a lot to learn about why the West is the awesomest place ever.</p>
<p>
	Last gasp&hellip; It was time to go for the doomsday weapon.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140558/217.jpg" style="width: 480px; height: 640px;" /></p>
<p>
	<strong>Ordinary Russian: </strong>Allo?</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: GET OUT OF UKRAINE!</strong><br />
	<strong>Phone: </strong><em>[click]</em></p>
<p>
	Sorry, guys. We tried. Pretty soon Vlad Putin will be laughing maniacally as he tumbles to earth astride a nuclear warhead. And it will all be the fault of the people who will only answer questions on email.</p>
<p>
	<em>&nbsp;Follow Gavin Haynes on <a href="http://twitter.com/gavhaynes" target="_blank">Twitter.</a></em></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299414</guid>
<author>Gavin Haynes </author>
<category>stuff, Russia, world peace, phoning people, ukraine, World War 3, Gavin Haynes</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Imagining &#039;Game of Thrones&#039; Characters as Rappers</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/imagining-game-of-thrones-characters-as-rappers</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Imagining 'Game of Thrones' Characters as Rappers
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299413</guid>
<author>Skinny Friedman</author>
<category>music, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wootton Bassett Is a Paradise</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/your-town-is-a-paradise-wootton-bassett</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	This&nbsp;<a href="http://www.vice.com/en_uk/read/is-a-paradise-uk" target="_blank">must-visit destination</a> is Wootton Bassett, a town somewhere between Bath and Oxford in England, where the locals&#39; love of superb postmodernist architecture is surpassed only by their love of sick and dead animals.</p>
<p>
	If you think your town could use a little tourism boost, do not hesitate to send your pictures to us at <a href="mailto:ukphotoblog@vice.com?subject=Your%20Town%20Is%20a%20Paradise">ukphotoblog@vice.com</a>.</p>
<p>
<!--recommended--></p>

]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299408</guid>
<author>Anis Ali</author>
<category>photo, Is A Paradise, Wootton Bassett, photos</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>LA Banned Smoking E-Cigarettes in Public Places</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/la-banned-e-cigarettes-because-children-or-something</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 22:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140306/ecig-lady.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 360px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>Screencap via CNN on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_ug9J4E5epE" target="_blank">Youtube</a></i></p>
<p>
	Last month, in a piece about third-hand smoke being potentially deadly, <a href="http://www.vice.com/read/thirdhand-smoke-could-kill-you" target="_blank">I said</a>&nbsp;banning e-cigarettes &quot;would be a fucking stupid thing to do.&quot; Well the Los Angeles City Council is <a href="http://clkrep.lacity.org/onlinedocs/2013/13-1204-S1_RPT_ATTY_01-08-2014.pdf" target="_blank">officially fucking stupid</a>.</p>
<p>
	Like five states and the District of Columbia before it, Los Angeles has passed an ordinance banning the use of e-cigarettes anywhere you can&#39;t smoke regular cigarettes. The law just adds &quot;Oh, and also e-cigarettes&quot; to existing bans on smoking in public. In Los Angeles, that means obvious places like your desk at work and in Starbucks, but also outdoor dining sections of restaurants and city-sponsored farmers&#39; markets.</p>
<p>
	The ordinance is the handiwork of Councilman Mitch O&#39;Farrell, whose rationale, according to&nbsp;<a href="http://www.latimes.com/local/lanow/la-me-ln-la-other-cities-cracking-down-on-ecigarettes-20140304,0,6189760,full.story#axzz2v3B34QPj" target="_blank">David Zahniser and Marisa Gerber</a> of the <em>LA Times,&nbsp;</em>was that he breathed a lot of secondhand smoke back when he was a waiter, so to hell with the evidence that e-cigarette vapor <a href="http://ntr.oxfordjournals.org/content/early/2013/12/10/ntr.ntt203.short" target="_blank">doesn&#39;t harm bystanders</a>. Council President Herb Wesson was a big backer of O&#39;Farrell&#39;s efforts, and he said to the <em>Times</em>,&nbsp;&ldquo;I&rsquo;m telling you, the high percentage of kids that smoke, smoke because it&rsquo;s cool. And when you&rsquo;re 15 you want to be cool,&rdquo; and &ldquo;I will not support anything&mdash;anything&mdash;that might attract one new smoker.&rdquo; Mr. Wesson did not provide the testimony of any 15-year-olds who agreed that sucking fog out of a severed <a href="https://twitter.com/kibblesmith/status/439797323405606913" target="_blank">robot penis</a> looks &quot;cool.&quot;</p>
<p>
	Councilman Joe Buscaino attempted to exempt bars and other places where kids are not allowed. He said, &quot;I don&rsquo;t think they should be regulated exactly the same way. And I&rsquo;ve heard from so many people, including my cousin Anthony, that they&rsquo;ve stopped smoking from the help of e-cigarettes.&quot; In the end, he still voted for the ordinance anyway, and his exemption failed. In fact, the ordinance passed unanimously.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140312/Screenshot-2014-03-04-18-40-18.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 365px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>Screencap of Jeff Stier via Youtube user&nbsp;</i><em><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kIGnT6LOX4o#t=29" target="_blank">SunnyDayAmerica</a></em></p>
<p>
	Jeff Stier, a lobbyist who made a name for himself opposing the iron regulatory fist of former mayor Michael Bloomberg in New York (where <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2013/12/19/255582225/new-york-extends-smoking-ban-to-e-cigarettes" target="_blank">e-cigarette regulations already exist</a>), showed up to voice his opposition to the ordinance. He spun a yarn about a hypothetical ex-smoker having a nicotine fit in a bar, forced out into the cold with the old-school plant-and-paper smokers, who tempt him or her back into their diabolical fold.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	Elected officials like those on the Los Angeles City Council don&#39;t seem to hear the message about e-cigarettes helping people quit, despite people like former American Lung Association CEO Charles D. Connor coming out in favor of their use as a <a href="http://articles.chicagotribune.com/2014-01-15/opinion/ct-ecigs-restrictions-chicago-tobacco-smokers-pers-20140115_1_conventional-cigarettes-e-cigarettes-electronic-cigarettes" target="_blank">smoking-cessation tool</a>. They&#39;re doing a cost-benefit analysis in their heads. Voting no on this ordinance, and then having it turn out that e-cigarettes turn your lungs into raspberry jam, would make them look horrible later, so they&#39;re taking a ban-first-and-ask-questions-later approach. As Councilwoman Nury Martinez put it, &quot;If this device turns out to be safe, then we can always undo the ordinance. But if this device proves not to be safe, we cannot undo the harm this will create on the public health.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Perhaps in an effort to upstage the LA City Council, Long Beach, the second biggest city in Los Angeles County, passed an even stricter ban on e-cigarettes Tuesday night. We attempted to reach Councilman Paul Krekorian and Mr. Busciano&mdash;who both expressed doubts about the ordinance while still voting for it&mdash;for comment, but Busciano&#39;s head of communication said they would &quot;get back to us&quot; at a later date. Krekorian&#39;s office did not answer the phone.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	Ordinarily, new technologies don&#39;t have to be proven safe. They&#39;re just allowed until someone proves they&#39;re harmful. This hasn&#39;t been the case for e-cigs, even though their major ingredient besides nicotine, <a href="http://abcnews.go.com/Health/things-cigarettes/story?id=22782568#1" target="_blank">propylene glycol</a>, is the same stuff found in your garden-variety smoke machine.&nbsp;If one can go to a concert and inhale this stuff with impunity, why not be able to vape too?</p>
<p>
	The precedent for this carcinogenic-until-proven-innocent doctrine is likely from the World Health Organization&#39;s <a href="http://www.who.int/tobacco/communications/statements/eletronic_cigarettes/en/">official press release</a> on the subject last year. It says that consumers should wait for word from a&nbsp;national regulatory body before considering them safe and effective. The release came about a month after the UK&#39;s National Health Service concluded that e-cigarettes should be <a href="http://www.nhs.uk/news/2013/06June/Pages/e-cigarettes-and-vaping.aspx">dispensed and regulated</a> as medication for quitting smoking.</p>
<p>
	Last fall, the FDA proposed a rule to regulate e-cigarettes that is currently being reviewed by the White House Office of Budget and Management. The public has now been waiting a few weeks for the two organizations to release a proposal for regulation, but no one knows quite when it will happen or why they&#39;re dragging their feet. It isn&#39;t likely that the FDA will declare e-cigarettes harmless.&nbsp;You&#39;re sucking chemical gas into one of your body&#39;s air holes. We can all be adults, though, and see that even if e-cigarettes aren&#39;t as medically unimpeachable as a handful of blueberries, vapor is still probably a hundred times better than breathing grandpa&#39;s Pall Malls. And for that we should let the office neckbeards use them while they code our websites.</p>
<p>
	<em>Follow Mike Pearl on <a href="https://twitter.com/MikeLeePearl" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.</em></p>
<p>
	<em><!--recommended--></em></p>

]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299119</guid>
<author>Mike Pearl</author>
<category>news, smoking, e-cigarettes, cancer, Los Angeles</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scientists Are (Finally) Studying LSD Again</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/scientists-are-finally-studying-lsd-again-mb-test</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Scientists Are (Finally) Studying LSD Again
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299312</guid>
<author>DJ Pangburn</author>
<category>tech, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Sardonic Protest Art of the Ukrainian Revolution</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/the-art-of-the-ukrainian-revolution</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	The media and medical reports aren&#39;t the only documentations of the revolutionary events in Ukraine these past four months. Local visual artists, both professional and amateur, have also been trying to capture, react to, and sometimes even influence the sudden social and political shifts they have witnessed and are still witnessing in their country. This has led to a wave of political cartoons, graffiti, stencils, and artworks in any other medium you can think of that can prove resistant to freezing temperatures.</p>
<p>
	Amid the chaos, there have even been street exhibitions, the most recent having taken place in the protest hub of Kiev&#39;s Independence Square&mdash;also known as the Maidan&mdash;and riot hotspot Hrushevskoho Street. Generaly speaking, you could find the drawings anywhere and everywhere&mdash;in the tents of activists, on the walls of nearby buildings, even on the city&#39;s Christmas tree. Almost as a rule, their subject is the AWOL (and perhaps former) president of Ukraine, Viktor Yanukovych.</p>
<p>
	For the past few months I have been traveling to and from Kiev, reporting on the situation. It is during that time that I have assembled these photos of Ukrainian protest art.</p>
<p>
	<em>See more of Sergei&#39;s work <a href="https://www.facebook.com/sergei.stroitelev" target="_blank">here</a>.</em></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299285</guid>
<author>Sergey Stroitelev</author>
<category>photo, ukraine, kiev, Yanukovych, protest art, art, revolution, graffiti</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Abolish Prison!</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/abolish-prison</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 19:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140383/abolish-prison.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 457px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>Illustration via Flickr user <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/donkeyhotey/" target="_blank">DonkeyHotey</a> </i></p>
<p>
	Prisons are terrible, torturous places where people&mdash;who are usually poor and disproportionately of color&mdash;are subjected daily to crimes more horrific than the ones that probably sent them there. The vast majority of individuals behind bars are there for nonviolent drug and property offenses. Now, which is worse, do you think: Stealing a late-90s Honda or putting someone in a cage for years where <a href="http://www.vice.com/read/is-prison-rape-on-the-rise" target="_blank">we know</a> they will be physically and emotionally abused? We ask whether criminals can be reformed, when we think of them as people at all, but maybe we should stop to consider whether the idea of prisons and jails can be rehabilitated in the wake of all the injustice they have wrought.</p>
<p>
	Perhaps the evils of incarceration outweigh the good. Maybe the goal shouldn&rsquo;t be reform, as welcome as that may be, but something more radical: release.</p>
<p>
	That&rsquo;s sort of what a federal court wants California to do. In 2009, it was ordered to improve conditions at its overcrowded prisons by freeing <a href="http://www.salon.com/2014/01/16/our_demented_public_safety_priorities_how_non_violent_offenders_attract_more_concern_than_natural_disasters/" target="_blank">tens of thousands of inmates</a>. The court didn&rsquo;t buy California&rsquo;s claim that it could improve conditions any other way, because the state had claimed that before and failed to deliver. The situation had gotten so bad that every week a prisoner was dying a preventable death because he or she didn&rsquo;t have adequate health care; hundreds of mentally ill inmates continue to be stashed away in mind-destroying solitary confinement for no reason other than that they are mentally ill and authorities don&rsquo;t know where else to put them.</p>
<p>
	We&rsquo;re still waiting for California to comply with the court order&mdash;Governor Jerry Brown, a Democrat, would rather <a href="http://www.vice.com/read/corporations-are-cashing-in-on-californias-prison-overcrowding-crisis" target="_blank">send inmates to private prisons</a> than release nonviolent offenders&mdash;but the idea that the only way to address the evil of prison is by putting fewer people in prison has been circulating for a while.</p>
<p>
	Activist Isaac Ontiveros is the communications director for <a href="http://criticalresistance.org/" target="_blank">Critical Resistance</a>, a national grassroots organization that seeks to stop mass incarceration by ending the system&rsquo;s reliance on prisons altogether and by devising alternative, community-based methods of resolving conflict and delivering justice. He is a prison abolitionist who likens his organization&rsquo;s work to the fight against another one of America&rsquo;s peculiar institutions (incidentally, more black people are <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/10/12/michelle-alexander-more-black-men-in-prison-slaves-1850_n_1007368.html" target="_blank">in American prisons</a> than ever worked on American plantations).</p>
<p>
	I asked Isaac to explain himself, and he was kind enough to do so.</p>
<p>
	<strong>VICE: What does it mean to be a &ldquo;prison abolitionist&rdquo;?</strong><br />
	<strong>Isaac Ontiveros: </strong>What we mean is that we want to end the whole system of mutually reinforcing relationships between surveillance, policing, the courts, and imprisonment that fuel, maintain, and expand social and economic inequity and institutional racism. So, not just prisons.</p>
<p>
	By &ldquo;abolition,&rdquo; we mean that we are interested in doing away with the system rather than finding ways to make it work better or for it to be kinder and gentler. We don&rsquo;t see the prison-industrial complex as broken; we see it working very, very well at surveilling, policing, imprisoning, and killing exactly who it targets. As abolitionists, we work to diminish the scope and power of the prison-industrial complex while simultaneously increasing the ability of those communities targeted by it to be stronger, healthier, and more self-determined.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140455/Col-Johnson-Liberating-an-Unfortunate-Debtor.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 449px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>A sketch of Richard Mentor Johnson, the ninth vice president of the US, freeing a man from debtors&#39; prison. Johnson was a 19th-century advocate of ending the practice of locking up people who couldn&#39;t pay their debts. Image via <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Col-Johnson-Liberating-an-Unfortunate-Debtor.jpg" target="_blank">Wikimedia Commons</a></i></p>
<p>
	<strong>Why do you think imprisonment came to be the dominant means of delivering &ldquo;justice&rdquo; in America?</strong><br />
	The US government, along with state and local governments, has always been involved one way or another in enforcing racial inequities&mdash;whether through social codes, laws and statutes, policing policies and practices, encouragement of vigilante violence, or outright domestic warfare against certain segments of the population. And poor people of color have borne the brunt of this violence&mdash;and, importantly, they&rsquo;ve also been at the forefront in fighting back.</p>
<p>
	Think about the incredible political repression that goes on in this country; think about the FBI&rsquo;s Counter Intelligence Program (COINTELPRO), unleashed against organizations like the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Panther_Party#Conflict_with_COINTELPRO" target="_blank">Black Panther Party</a>. Think of the massive cuts to social and health services, massive job loss, attacks on organized labor, and de facto permanent unemployment. Think of the war on drugs, the war on gangs, the war on terror. Think of the thousands of new offenses added to the criminal codes&mdash;the equivalent of one federal offense <em>a week</em> between 2000 and 2007. Think of the positively virulent anti-black racism that goes along with this. Think of the militarization of the US-Mexican border and immigrant detention. Think about even small towns having a SWAT team and zero-tolerance policing and of the largest prison-building project in world history in the state of California. Think about the disenfranchisement and dispossession of formerly imprisoned people. Think of the absolute pervasiveness of surveillance as well as media images that perpetuate some of the basest and most racist stereotypes imaginable of who is a criminal, or an undesirable, or a terrorist. And now think of the instability created by such violence and the need to control that instability&mdash;and the need to keep people from fighting back.</p>
<p>
	<strong>The US doesn&rsquo;t actually imprison all that many violent people. Most of those behind bars committed nonviolent drug or property offenses. But what about the violent ones? Aren&rsquo;t we better off having murderers and rapists off of the streets?</strong><br />
	Well, I think an interesting part of that question is that even as the US has managed to lock up more people than any other country in the world, and has built probably the most massive and repressive policing, legal, and imprisonment system in history, we still tend to be pretty terrified in this country. This is not to say that violence&mdash;including sexual violence and murder&mdash;isn&rsquo;t a real thing or a real fear. But I think in order to build up any hope of moving beyond the bleak situation we are in&hellip; we have to ask a few tough questions, and we have to change quite a few things. How do we relate to violence in our communities vis-&agrave;-vis the terrible violence that is wrought by the US government on a global scale, or by the prison-industrial complex domestically on a daily basis? How do we understand violence in relationship to the devastation caused by racism and economic inequity? How do we relate to sexual violence when we are inundated with horrendously misogynistic, homophobic, and transphobic images? Our fears might be real, but our fears are also being produced and exploited. And then, of course, how do we think of anything else but prisons and police when we&rsquo;ve be indoctrinated with this idea that all problems are solved by locking people up?</p>
<p>
<!--recommended-->	At the same time, violence is a very real concern, especially in the communities that are most impacted by the prison-industrial complex. I think we are better off if we can develop sustainable and transformative ways to confront, address, and intervene in situations of harm and violence. And the thing is, for the most part, especially in marginalized communities, people are already working to resolve conflict and address harm without using police or imprisonment all the time. And they are doing it around some egregious forms of harm, including murder and sexual violence. And sometimes some things work better than others. As an abolitionist, I am always interested in figuring out ways to address harm and violence that don&rsquo;t rely on using the police.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140456/stockton-jail.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 477px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>A decommissioned jail in Stockton, Utah, that is now a historical site. Photo via <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Stockton_Utah_Jail.jpeg" target="_blank">Wikimedia Commons</a></i></p>
<p>
	<strong>Sure, America may not be as violent as popularly imagined, but there is still a lot of violence in this country. What would a prison abolitionist do if they found out his next-door neighbor was a serial killer or rapist? In the absence of viable alternatives, I think I might call the cops. Is that wrong? Would it be better if I took justice into my own hands?</strong><br />
	Rather than saying, &ldquo;Is it wrong to call the cops?&rdquo; I want us to ask, &ldquo;Is there anything we can do <em>besides</em> call the cops?&rdquo; I think the more we can ask ourselves that question, and ask it among our friends, families, coworkers, neighbors, organizations, etc., and try to ask it and answer it as imaginatively as possible <em>before </em>things escalate, the more we will be able to respond swiftly and thoughtfully during crises.</p>
<p>
	If you mean, &ldquo;What could I do if an act of violence was being carried out in front of me?&rdquo; I would do everything in my power to stop it&mdash;and if I were able, this would include drawing in, as quickly and as thoughtfully as possible, the help and support of others. And then, yes, as far as all the lessons we&rsquo;ve been taught about what to do next, we are in a no-person&rsquo;s land. But the fact of the matter is, people deal with these situations all the time&mdash;sometimes they use violence, sometimes they don&rsquo;t; sometimes the person who does harm is banished from the family or the community, and sometimes they are drawn closer. I heard a story of an indigenous community where one person murdered another person. There was this long process by which it was agreed that the person who did the murder would essentially replace the person he killed as far as his social and economic responsibilities. Gacaca courts in Rwanda and conferencing circles among indigenous communities in Canada also teach us very useful lessons about the complex ways survivors of very serious violence have attempted to hold those who&rsquo;ve done harm accountable.</p>
<p>
	I would challenge the notion that there is a one-size-fits-all solution to these types of situations. That&rsquo;s the response that the prison-industrial complex has offered us, and that hasn&rsquo;t worked&mdash;except to exacerbate the social instability that fuels the violence we see in our communities. I live in a neighborhood where people are killed from time to time, but it doesn&rsquo;t help me to understand the person doing the killing to think of them as some monster or serial killer out of a movie. I hope my anger or fear or frustration about this type of violence would lead me to want to fight to change the context in which it occurs, so that it happens less and less in the first place.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Abolishing prisons seems like a pretty distant goal. What then is a prison abolitionist to do in the meantime?</strong><br />
	Like any social change, it will take time and is something that requires taking decisive and strategic steps toward the world we want to see. We have a broad vision of a world without prisons, police, surveillance, and the inequities they defend, and as we takes steps toward that world, we understand better what the path forward is going to look like.</p>
<p>
	In Los Angeles, we work with other organizations and community members to fight back the expansion of the LA County Jail, which is the largest jail system in the world. We are working to do the same in San Francisco County. In New Orleans, we were able to win a cap on the number of people that can be locked up in the notorious Orleans Parish Prison&mdash;no small feat, given that Louisiana has the highest imprisonment rate in the US&mdash;so now the challenge is to get people out.</p>
<p>
	In Oakland, we won a fight against the racist policing policy known as a civil gang injunction, which under threat of arrest and imprisonment restricts the freedom of movement and association of individuals profiled as gang members&mdash;in the US, this has never been used against a white person&mdash;and now we are working in neighborhoods to develop ways people can take care of one another without using the police. In California as a whole we&rsquo;ve been successful in winning massive cuts to the prison budget. We&rsquo;ve also worked with prisoners and their loved ones and advocates to support three massive prison hunger strikes in protest of the state&rsquo;s use of solitary confinement. We run a mail program and publish a newspaper that goes to thousands of prisoners throughout the US, aimed at working to develop our capacity as activists inside and outside prisons. All of our members are volunteers, and we do most of our work in coalition with the idea that we are think it is necessary to build a movement to both dismantle what keeps us down and to build up the world we believe is possible. At every turn, we try to put forward a vision of what we are <em>for</em> as strongly as we fight what we are <em>against.</em></p>
<p>
	<strong>Working to improve the conditions faced by those behind bars seems like a good thing, but is there a fear it could make the current system more sustainable, injecting life into an unjust system?</strong><br />
	This is a crucial challenge that doesn&rsquo;t have an easy answer. The system we are up against is not fixed, and those who work as its strategists and technicians aren&rsquo;t stupid&mdash;so it grows, changes, and adapts, and that includes accommodating and adjusting to reforms. Our organizing philosophy cautions us to try to not build up something that we have to knock down later. This is not easy, but is also part of any sustainable process of change. For example, ending solitary confinement doesn&rsquo;t necessarily mean anyone gets to come home, but it does neutralize one of the main tools prison systems use to inhibit prisoner social and political organization. So organizing against that hopefully increases the capacity of imprisoned people (and those in the communities from which they come) to fight for further gains that might lead to more freedom.</p>
<p>
	<em><a href="http://www.freecharlesdavis.com/" target="_blank">Charles Davis</a> is a writer and producer in Los Angeles. His work has been published by outlets including Al Jazeera, the</em> New Inquiry<em>, and</em> Salon.</p>

]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299227</guid>
<author>Charles Davis</author>
<category>stuff, Isaac Ontiveros, prison, prison-industrial complex, prison abolitionists, Critical Resistance, California, Orleans Parish Prison, prison alternatives</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why More People Are Murdered in Caracas than in Baghdad</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/why-more-people-are-murdered-in-caracas-than-in-baghdad</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 21:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Why More People Are Murdered in Caracas than in Baghdad
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299313</guid>
<author>Alice Speri</author>
<category>news, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blobby Boys - Part 2</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/blobby-boys---part-ii</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140494/Blobby-Boys-2resize.jpg" style="width: 642px; height: 1658px;" /></p>
<p>
	<em><a href="http://www.vice.com/read/blobby-boys-part-1">C</a><a href="http://www.vice.com/read/blobby-boys-part-1">lick here</a> for </em>Blobby Boys - <em>Part 1</em>.</p>
<p>
	<em>Keep your eyes peeled for new installments of&nbsp;</em>Blobby Boys<em>&nbsp;every Wednesday from here until the end of time. Or until Alex gets sick of working with us.</em></p>
<p>
<!--recommended--></p>

]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299304</guid>
<author>Alex Schubert</author>
<category>comics, Blobby Boys, comics, Alex Schubert, Bands</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>An Excerpt from Jailed Journalist Barrett Brown&#039;s New Book</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/heres-an-excerpt-from-barrett-browns-new-book</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140457/Barrett-Brown--BarrettBrownLOL--on-Twitter-1.jpg" style="width: 642px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>Image via Barrett Brown&#39;s <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=klvP1Xx6OH4">Youtube</a> page</i></p>
<p>
	<em>Editor&#39;s note: Barrett Brown is an activist-journalist whom VICE has covered (and </em><a href="http://www.vice.com/en_us/read/we-spoke-to-barrett-brown-from-prison" target="_blank"><em>interviewed</em></a><em>) extensively, and who is awaiting trial in an American jail. He is also, slowly, creeping into </em><em><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7nV9o2eegZY" target="_blank">mainstream</a>&nbsp;</em><a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/culture/news/barrett-brown-faces-105-years-in-jail-20130905" target="_blank"><em>consciousness</em></a><em>. His newest book, </em>Keep Rootin&#39; for Putin<em>, skewers various American mainstream media pundits, and it was </em><em><a href="http://www.vice.com/en_ca/read/barrett-browns-new-book-keep-rootin-for-putin-skewers-mainstream-media-pundits">reviewed for VICE Canada</a></em><em> last week. Below is an excerpt from </em>Keep Rootin&#39; for Putin<em>. The book will be available on the official </em><em><a href="http://freebarrettbrown.org/" target="_blank">Free Barrett Brown</a>&nbsp;w</em><em>ebsite soon. UPDATE: Earlier today, the US government filed a motion to dismiss <a href="http://www.dailydot.com/crime/barrett-brown-link-charges-dismissed/" target="_blank">11 of the 12 criminal charges against Barrett Brown.</a></em></p>
<p>
	I learned a few things from William Bennett&#39;s book, <em>The De-Valuing of America</em>. Did you know that Prohibition was a resounding success? Neither did I. Actually, I still don&rsquo;t, because it&rsquo;s not true. So I guess what I really learned is that some people still think that Prohibition was a resounding success, and that at least one of these people has gone on to help shape American drug policy.</p>
<p>
	During a wider discussion on the merits of federal fiddlin&rsquo;, Bennett drops the following bombshell, almost as an aside: &ldquo;One of the clear lessons of Prohibition is that when we had laws against alcohol, there was less consumption of alcohol, less alcohol-related disease, fewer drunken brawls, and a lot less public drunkenness. And, contrary to myth, there is no evidence that Prohibition caused big increases in crime.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	This is a pretty incredible statement to just throw into a book without any supporting evidence. Bennett hasn&rsquo;t just expressed an opinion on an ambiguous topic, like, &ldquo;Gee, the old days sure were swell&rdquo; or &ldquo;Today&rsquo;s Japanese role-playing games are all flash and no substance&rdquo; or something like that. Rather, Bennett has made several statements of alleged fact that can be easily verified or shot down by a few minutes of research. But Bennett didn&rsquo;t bother to research it, and I know this because the federal government has a tendency to keep records, and the records prove Bennett wrong.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;Less alcohol-related disease&rdquo;? In 1926, a number of witnesses testified before the House Judiciary Committee regarding the ongoing effects of Prohibition; several New York State asylum officials noted that the number of patients suffering from alcohol-related dementia had increased by 1,000 percent since 1920, the year after Prohibition had gone into effect. Also in 1920, deaths from undiluted alcohol consumption in New York City stood at 84. In 1927, with Prohibition in full swing, that number had swelled to 719.</p>
<p>
	But those are just snapshots in time. A look at the larger picture shows that Bennett is not just kind of wrong, but entirely and unambiguously wrong about every single thing he&rsquo;s just said.</p>
<p>
	In 1991, the Cato Institute commissioned a retroactive Prohibition study by Mark Thornton, the O.P. Alford III Assistant Professor of Economics at Auburn University. Citing hard data gleaned mostly from government records, Thornton concluded that Prohibition &ldquo;was a miserable failure on all counts.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Despite Bennett&rsquo;s assertion that &ldquo;when we had laws against alcohol, there was <em>less consumption of alcohol</em> [italics his],&rdquo; a cursory glance at the federal government&rsquo;s own data shows that there was <em>not</em> [italics mine, thank you very much]. Now, per capita consumption did indeed fall dramatically from 1919 to 1920, but then increased far more dramatically from 1920 to 1922&mdash;after which it continued to increase well beyond pre-Prohibition levels. So, when Bennett says that &ldquo;there was less consumption of alcohol,&rdquo; he&rsquo;s right about a single one-year period, but wrong about the next dozen or so years&mdash;or, to put it another way, he&rsquo;s entirely wrong. If I decided to reduce my drinking for a week, and I drank quite a bit less than usual on Monday but then drank the same amount I usually do on Tuesday and then drank more than I usually do on Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, Saturday, and Sunday, and if the average alcohol consumption on my part during that week was much higher than my average alcohol consumption in the previous week, then one could hardly say that &ldquo;there was less consumption of alcohol&rdquo; in my apartment that week. Or, rather, one could say that, but one would be wrong. In this case, though, one could be excused for being wrong, because I don&rsquo;t usually keep exact records on my alcohol consumption, and neither does the federal government (I think). But in the case of Prohibition, there is no excuse for ignorance, and even less for spreading it around. That allegedly noble experiment may not have been the cause of increased alcohol consumption, but it clearly wasn&rsquo;t the cause of any overall decline, no overall decline having actually occurred.</p>
<p>
	Not only didn&rsquo;t alcohol consumption decrease during Prohibition, but the American taxpayers were at that point paying quite a bit of extra coin to enforce the decrease in alcohol consumption that they were not getting. From 1919 to 1922&mdash;a period, which, as mentioned above, saw an overall increase in alcohol consumption&mdash;the budget for the Bureau of Prohibition was tripled. Meanwhile, the Coast Guard was now spending 13 million dollars a year, Customs was blowing all kinds of cash, and the state and local governments, which had been stuck with the majority of enforcement issues, were throwing away untold amounts of money to boot.</p>
<p>
	Beyond the easily calculable nickel-and-dime costs of running an unsuccessful nanny-state boondoggle, the American citizen was being screwed on other fronts, too. Unlike those umbrella-twirling, petticoat-clad temperance harpies of the time (and their equally insufferable apologists of the present day), Thornton considers other social costs of a massive government ban on non-coercive behavior. Of the alcohol consumed under Prohibition, hard liquor made a jump as a percentage of total alcohol sales that had not been seen before, that has not been seen since, and that will probably never be seen again. The sudden ascendancy of whiskey over beer can be easily explained (and could have easily been predicted): If one is smuggling something above the law or consuming it on the sly, it makes more sense to smuggle or consume concentrated versions of the product in question than to deal with larger, more diluted concoctions. A similar phenomenon occurred in the cocaine trade under William Bennett&rsquo;s watch as drug czar.</p>
<p>
	So alcohol consumption was up, and the alcohol being consumed was now of the harder, more brawl-inducing variety. But what about the savings? The aforementioned busybodies in petticoats had predicted great social gains for Americans&mdash;money spent on alcohol would now go to milk for babies, life insurance, and, presumably, magical unicorns that grant you three wishes. Of course, this didn&rsquo;t turn out to be the case. Not only was alcohol consumption up, but records show that people were now paying more for it, too. Of course, they were also paying higher taxes to aid in the government&rsquo;s all-out attempt to repeal the law of supply and demand. And don&rsquo;t even think about approaching one of those unicorns to wish for more wishes. That&rsquo;s against the rules.</p>
<p>
	What about crime? Apparently, there are some wacky rumors going around to the effect that crime actually went up during Prohibition. But Bennett clearly told us that &ldquo;contrary to myth, there is no evidence that Prohibition caused big increases in crime.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Pardon my French, but <em>le gros homme poss&egrave;de la sottise d&rsquo;un enfant humain et la teneur en graisse d&rsquo;un b&eacute;b&eacute; d&rsquo;&eacute;l&eacute;phant</em>. And if you&rsquo;ll indulge me further by pardoning my harsh language, Bennett is so full of horseshit on this one that he could fertilize every bombed-out coca field from the Yucatan to Bolivia. The idea that &ldquo;Prohibition caused big increases in crime&rdquo; is not so much a myth as it is a verifiable fact. Again, believe it or not, the feds tend to keep records on such things, and again, believe it or totally believe it, Bennett has failed to consult these records before providing his sage commentary on the subject.</p>
<p>
	In large cities, for instance, the homicide rate jumped from 5.6 per 100,000 residents in the first decade of the 20th century to 8.4 in the second, during which time 25 states passed their own localized prohibition laws in addition to the federal government&rsquo;s implementation of the Harris Narcotics Act, which in turn paved the way for the then-nascent drug war. And in the third decade, during which Prohibition was the law of the land not just in rural states governed by puritanical yahoos but in every state of the union, that number jumped to 10 per 100,000. Meanwhile, the rates for other serious crimes increased on a per capita basis by similar leaps and bounds, despite an environment of booming prosperity for which the 1920s are known to this day.</p>
<p>
	Now, a particularly stubborn statist of the William Bennett school of disingenuous argumentation might try to counter by claiming that this increase in serious crime could have been attributable to other factors, such as increased immigration; Bennett himself might be tempted to remark that things would have been different if only we had aborted every Italian baby in the country or something like that. But this hypothetical counter-argument would not hold up, because the crime rate continued to soar until 1933, when it saw a sudden and dramatic decline.</p>
<p>
	That year, 1933, was of course when Prohibition was repealed.</p>
<p>
	So, William Bennett to the contrary, Prohibition did indeed lead to &ldquo;big increases in crime.&rdquo; But Bennett is incapable of recognizing this, because he&rsquo;s already made up his mind. After all, Bennett advocates the federalization of private conduct and, as the nation&rsquo;s first drug czar, acted to implement this vision. And because Bennett is a possessor of both &ldquo;moral clarity&rdquo; and &ldquo;moral courage,&rdquo; his views must be both morally clear and morally courageous. And because America&rsquo;s failed experiment with Prohibition was an early and dramatic example of the federalization of private conduct, and thus an early version of Bennett&rsquo;s chosen ideology, Prohibition must have logically been a success, rather than a failure.</p>
<p>
	Indeed, Bennett was enthusiastic about the possibility of replicating the glorious Cultural Revolution of Prohibition. &ldquo;This is one issue, Mr. President, where I, a conservative Republican, feel comfortable in advocating a strong federal role,&rdquo; Bennett reports telling Bush senior in 1988. Putting aside the question of whether or not this is how Bennett really talks&mdash;and if so, he&rsquo;s certainly more eloquent in private than he is in public&mdash;this is a telling remark, and it&rsquo;s unfortunate that Bennett doesn&rsquo;t explain why a strong federal role would be merited here and not elsewhere. Something about the criminalization of private conduct scratches an itch that social assistance programs just can&rsquo;t seem to reach.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;Often it seems that any idea that fits the zeitgeist, that can be linked to a &lsquo;need&rsquo;&mdash;anyone&rsquo;s need, anywhere, anytime&mdash;is funded,&rdquo; he writes at one point. &ldquo;Frequently, it is funded at the costs of hundreds of millions, or even billions, of dollars without the slightest regard to whether the program will work, whether it will be held accountable, whether it is appropriate for the federal government to fund it, or whether it is something people can or ought to do for themselves.&rdquo; It does not occur to Bennett that he has just described the Office of National Drug Control Policy. Elsewhere: &ldquo;I know of no other group in America that is more cocksure of its right to full entitlement to the United States Treasury than the leadership of higher education.&rdquo; Bennett must believe the drug war to be funded by voluntary subscription and perhaps further offset by vouchers, and seems to have seen nothing &ldquo;cocksure&rdquo; in demanding that the military bomb more of Bolivia at his command. And during his no doubt Marcus Aurelius&ndash;inspired treatise on the education of children found elsewhere in the book, he tells us that if &ldquo;we want them to know about respect for the law, they should understand why Socrates told Crito: &lsquo;No, I submit to the decree of Athens.&rsquo;&rdquo; Perhaps they should also understand why Socrates was sentenced to death by the mob in the first place. The answer, of course, is that he was found guilty of &ldquo;corrupting the youth.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Like the Athenian mob, Bennett is also opposed to the corruption of the youth by way of such things as marijuana and favors the death penalty for those found guilty of it. At one point in the book, he recalls an appearance on <em>Larry King Live</em> when a caller suggested that drug dealers be beheaded. The moral clarity of the proposal seems to have excited Bennett. &ldquo;What the caller suggests is morally plausible. Legally, it&rsquo;s difficult&hellip; morally, I don&rsquo;t have any problem with it.&rdquo; But the moral plausibility of this was, as usual, lost on the nation&rsquo;s intellectuals while being perfectly understood by the common folk, who like the Russian serfs before them are in eternal adoration of their drug czar (and it is also understood by the totalitarian Chinese, who have been executing drug dealers for quite a while, no doubt due to the inherent moral clarity of its communist dictatorship). &ldquo;Many of the elites ridiculed my opinion. But it resonated with the American people because they knew what drugs were doing, and they wanted a morally proportional response.&rdquo; Bennett&rsquo;s evidence of this, seriously, is that then-chairman of the Republican National Committee, Lee Atwater, called him from South Carolina and reported that the people he had spoken to there seemed very keen on the idea. Meanwhile, as Bennett points out, the elites had the audacity to run headlines like &ldquo;Drug Czar: Beheading Fitting&rdquo; to describe an incident in which the drug czar had said that beheading is fitting. &ldquo;The reaction was illustrative,&rdquo; he writes.</p>
<p>
	Indeed, much of the book (and much of Bennett&rsquo;s public career since) follows a familiar pattern. Bennett says something wacky, the &ldquo;elites&rdquo; criticize him for it, and then Bennett either sticks to his guns or pretends he didn&rsquo;t mean what he obviously meant. Weirdly, he sometimes manages to do both at the same time. Speaking to a Baptist group during his tenure as drug czar, Bennett told attendees the following: &ldquo;I continue to be amazed how often people I talked to in drug treatment centers talk about drugs as the great lie, the great deception&mdash;indeed a product, one could argue, of the great deceiver, the great deceiver everyone knows. &lsquo;A lie&rsquo; is what people call drugs, and many, many people in treatment have described to me their version of crack, simply calling it &lsquo;the devil.&rsquo; This has come up too often, it has occurred too much, too spontaneously, too often in conversation, to be ignored.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	This time, the reaction was not simply &ldquo;illustrative,&rdquo; as had been the case with the beheading thing. Rather, &ldquo;The reaction was absurd but illustrative.&rdquo; I should have pointed out that the Bennett Pattern described above invariably ends with Bennett describing the situation as &ldquo;illustrative.&rdquo; Anyway, the reaction was illustrative of the media&rsquo;s tendency to report things that government officials say when they say something unusual, a practice to which Bennett seems to be opposed, no doubt on moral grounds. The<em> San Francisco Chronicle</em>&rsquo;s story was headlined &ldquo;Bennett Blames Satan for Drug Abuse.&rdquo; Bennett reminds us that he was simply &ldquo;reporting what I had heard from people in drug treatment and speaking of drugs in a moral context,&rdquo; but then immediately goes on to refer to this as &ldquo;my view.&rdquo; Nor would he have been very likely to report all of this and describe it as having &ldquo;come up too often, too spontaneously, too often in conversation, to be ignored&rdquo; if he didn&rsquo;t believe it had some sort of merit.</p>
<p>
	If Bennett had, for instance, gone to a number of drug treatment centers and been told that crack was invented by the CIA under the direction of George Bush Sr. in order to exterminate the black population, which is another popular piece of theology among certain drug addicts, Bennett probably would not have gotten up in front of several hundred people and began &ldquo;reporting what I had heard from people in drug treatment&rdquo; and then noted that Bush Sr.&rsquo;s alleged black-op narco-genocide &ldquo;has come up too often, it has occurred too much, too spontaneously, too often in conversation, to be ignored,&rdquo; because Bennett would not have agreed with such a sentiment, or, if he did agree, he would not have said it because he would have known all of this to be true as he had in fact helped to launder the drug money by way of his casino mobster connections, and at any rate he would not find it prudent to talk about all of these things in public.&nbsp;<br />
	<br />
	<em>Follow Barrett Brown on <a href="http://www.twitter.com/barrettbrownLOL">Twitter</a>.</em></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299296</guid>
<author>Barrett Brown</author>
<category>news, barrett-brown, internet, internet-security, prohibition, the-us-government, ronald-reagan, war-on-drugs, drugs, politics, NEWS, william-bennett, william-j-bennett</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Winklevoss Twins Are Using Bitcoins to Go to Space</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/the-winklevoss-twins-are-using-bitcoins-to-go-to-space-mb-test</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss <a href="http://winklevosscapital.com/posts/78649481042" target="_blank">announced today in a blog post</a> and tweet that they&#39;ve bought a Virgin Galactic flight to space, and they paid for it in Bitcoin&mdash;of course.</p>
<p>
	&nbsp;</p>

]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299303</guid>
<author>Meghan Neal</author>
<category>tech, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Eating Meat Might Kill Me </title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/eating-meat-might-kill-me</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140451/muellers-bbq.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>BBQ brisket from Mueller&#39;s BBQ, in Texas.&nbsp;</i></p>
<p>
	Few people would consider my job as a food writer to be a dangerous one, but I just found out that I might have a deadly meat allergy.</p>
<p>
	Here are a few meals that might kill me:</p>
<ol>
	<li>
		Corned beef and mustard on rye</li>
	<li>
		Chili con carne</li>
	<li>
		Cottage pie</li>
	<li>
		Grilled gammon steak</li>
	<li>
		Brisket</li>
	<li>
		Philly cheesesteak</li>
</ol>
<p>
	Although there&rsquo;s always the real threat of contracting a norovirus or being hunted by a crazed chef I gave a bad review, I&rsquo;m not exactly parachuting into forest fires or ice-road trucking on the work clock. But when I learned that I might have a fatal allergy to red meat, I started looking into safer career options. I can&rsquo;t confirm that I have the allergy until August, when I can order the only available test for alpha-gal antibodies, a test that is not FDA-approved and is of undetermined value in actually diagnosing allergies to meat. Like a baseball player who loses his poise at the plate, I have suffered a loss of confidence as a food writer.</p>
<p>
	As I am penning this sentence, I could be eating a hot dog from a Copenhagen street cart or a steak pie at a pub somewhere in London. If I did, my throat might close up and hives spread across my face like acne in overdrive. I&rsquo;d collapse unless I&rsquo;m quick enough to pull out the EpiPen that I ought to carry everywhere, but I never do.</p>
<p>
	The beginning of my problems with animal protein began with a mouse. Or to be precise, a drug called cetuximab, which is made from mice. In 2005, a group of cancer patients taking the drug developed urticaria (hives), angioedema (swelling of the lips and tongue), and anaphylaxis (a deadly allergic reaction). The symptoms baffled doctors. But when the patients reported similar reactions to red meat, doctors finally got a clue. Blood tests revealed that the patients had antibodies for galactose-&alpha;-1,3-galactose, a.k.a. alpha-gal, a sugar found in the muscle tissue of non-primate mammals&mdash;including mice. The reason the patients had alpha-gal antibodies remained a mystery until researchers noticed that the medical histories of affected patients included stories about tick bites. Cetuximab allergies were distributed across the habitat of the lone star tick, <em>Amblyomma americanum</em>: Virginia, West Virginia, North Carolina, South Carolina, Tennessee, Texas, Georgia, Mississippi, Kentucky, Oklahoma, Arkansas, and Missouri.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140452/chinese-rabbit.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>A Szechuan meat dish</i></p>
<p>
	Last summer, I was living alone in the Missouri woodlands, taking a break from New York City. After I had collected enough ticks to declare myself an arachnid preserve, I moved to Oxford, England, with my copy of Paula Wolfert&rsquo;s<em>&nbsp;Food of Morocco</em>. One Friday, I bought a kilo of lamb shoulder and braised it with almonds and raisins, Tiznit-style, and I spent the next day shitting out my stomach lining. When my nausea and cramping improved, I diagnosed myself with food poisoning and went to bed dreaming of a proper English breakfast. By 4 AM, I woke up covered in hives, and my lips had swollen to Pamela Anderson proportions. I called the village doctor, who immediately dispatched an ambulance. After a tablet of an antihistamine (cetirizine), the hives disappeared. I suspected that I was allergic to almonds or mushrooms, or any number of other foods I had ingested. And so I carried on in a state of continuous low-grade terror that a mouthful of anything might be my last.</p>
<p>
	In January, I took an impromptu trip to Paris, a city stuffed with tree nuts and wild mushrooms. I ate veal head, six or seven almond croissants, raw oysters, clams, a handful of foraged blue foot mushrooms, and lamb heart, all washed down with cheap red wine. The morning of my scheduled departure, I woke up in the hostel, stumbled to the wash closet, and painted every available surface with a boiling slurry of half-digested baguette. Because of the volume and variety of the food that I had consumed, food poisoning seemed likely. I hiked to Gare du Nord, boarded Eurostar, connected at King&rsquo;s Cross to Paddington, took First Great Western to Didcot Parkway (a mole on Britain&rsquo;s beautiful ass), caught the 40-minute rail-replacement bus to Oxford (which was blasting Duran Duran and 80s pop music louder than my diabolical burps), and managed the walk back to my flat before I vomited. I woke at 4 AM with hives, surprised because, in the months between episodes, I had eaten almonds and mushrooms without problems. An American allergist hypothesized long-distance that I had an allergy to alpha-gal. It would explain the delayed reaction&mdash;the allergy takes three to six hours to begin&mdash;and the months without symptoms. For unknown reasons, the allergy depends on the type and cut of meat, portion size, and processing. Beef, pork, lamb, deer, and mice can trigger the allergy. In my case, I reacted most violently to lamb.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	While I could take this as a call to vegetarianism, I think I&rsquo;m in a state of denial. Like detective stories, medical mysteries are exciting because they fulfill our need to figure it out and taste a blend of empathy and disgust. We feel compassion for the patients, even imagine the horrors of their suffering, but seek to distance ourselves. It could never happen to us. But when it does happen to you, the pleasure of the puzzle is connected to fear.</p>
<p>
	Yet I keep playing Russian roulette, knowing that one day I may end up cold and blue, eyes glazed open to the dark abyss. Pump my stomach and look for deer sausage, squirrel, and the remains of a nice prime rib still slathered in horseradish cream. In part, I keep eating meat because the danger has heightened the pleasure factor, like bareback sex, mainlining heroin, base jumping, or motorcycling sans helmet. In part, I eat meat to prove to myself that I am normal. But mostly, it is my love for my job and my passion for food that drives me toward death.</p>
<p>
	<i>Follow Jason Bell on <a href="http://twitter.com/jasonericbell" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.</i></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299289</guid>
<author>Jason Bell</author>
<category>food, Raw Meat, meat, allergy, dead, deadly, ticks, deer ticks, mice, baguette, french, London, England, norovirus, food writer</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cheers to the Revolution: Kiev&#039;s Beautiful Molotov Cocktails</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/cheers-to-the-revolution-kievs-beautiful-molotov-cocktails</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140420/DW-20140226-1189.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 960px;" /></p>
<p>
	Kiev&#39;s EuroMaidan protesters used fire to their advantage. With fire, the protesters were able to defend their barricades, extend their lines, and fortify their positions. They were mobilized throughout the city to collect as many bottles as possible, and&nbsp;thousands of Molotov cocktails were used&nbsp;to set fire to tanks, other armored&nbsp;vehicles, and buses.&nbsp;These little bombs were the only real weapon protesters had against the government&#39;s well-armed forces.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	Donald Weber spent this February in Kiev photographing for VICE. Follow our coverage of breaking events in Kiev on <a href="https://news.vice.com/video/russian-roulette-the-invasion-of-ukraine-dispatch-one">VICE News</a>.</p>
<p>
	<em>All photos by <a href="http://donaldweber.com/">Donald Weber/VII Photo</a></em></p>
<p class="p1">
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140427/DW-20140226-1199.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 960px;" /></p>
<p class="p1">
	&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p1">
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140421/DW-20140226-1216.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 960px;" /></p>
<p class="p1">
	&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p1">
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140424/DW-20140226-1233.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 960px;" /></p>
<p class="p1">
	&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p1">
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140426/DW-20140226-1234.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 960px;" /></p>
<p class="p1">
	&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p1">
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140428/DW-20140226-1231.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 960px;" /></p>
<p class="p1">
	&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p1">
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140429/DW-20140226-1238.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 960px;" /></p>
<p class="p1">
	&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p1">
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140430/DW-20140226-1187.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 960px;" /></p>
<p class="p1">
	&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p1">
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140431/DW-20140226-1260.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 960px;" /></p>
<p class="p1">
	&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p1">
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140432/DW-20140226-1195.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 960px;" /></p>
<p class="p1">
	&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p1">
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140434/DW-20140226-1197.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 960px;" /></p>
<p class="p1">
	&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p1">
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140435/DW-20140226-1243.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 960px;" /></p>
<p class="p1">
	&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p1">
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140437/DW-20140226-1246.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 960px;" /></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299270</guid>
<author>Donald Weber</author>
<category>photo, Donald Webber, kiev, Molotov Cocktails, still lives, fire</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Chiraq Part 7 - How to Make It Out of Chiraq</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/chiraq-part-6-how-to-make-it-out-of-chiraq</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Chiraq Part 7 - How to Make It Out of Chiraq
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299301</guid>
<author>Noisey Staff</author>
<category>music, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>VICE Shorts: I&#039;m Short, Not Stupid Presents: &#039;How to Keep Smoking&#039;</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/im-short-not-stupid-presents-how-to-keep-smoking</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140450/I-m-short--47-How-to-keep-smoking.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 360px;" /></p>
<p>
	I miss the days when the things I do were portrayed positively in the media. Things like being rebellious, drinking to excess, throwing caution to the wind, and smoking until my lungs gave out. Now, it&#39;s all: Fit in, drink responsibly, safety first, smoking kills you. How do I fight the good fight in this world full of fear and fascism?</p>
<p>
	First, they told us not to smoke inside. Now, we can barely smoke outside. I can&rsquo;t even impress strangers by smoking three cigarettes at once&mdash;they just sneer at me like I&#39;m a dick, as if smoking hasn&#39;t been cool in 50 years. It makes no sense. Smoking used to be <em>soooooo</em> cool.</p>
<p>
	Thankfully, we&rsquo;ve got a martyr in our midst. His name is John Wilson. Over the last who-knows-how-long, he&rsquo;s meticulously put together a video guide on how to keep smoking. Through rambling, ramshackle insights, points are formed and abandoned, but one thing is for sure&mdash;you&#39;ll want a cigarette after seeing the film.</p>
<p>
	The short is three smoked cigarettes long, so you can really get a good buzz going if you watch it right. Also, be sure to check out my equally informative interview with the filmmaker, John Wilson, below.</p>
<p>
	<iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="468" mozallowfullscreen="" src="//player.vimeo.com/video/86527457?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="640"></iframe></p>
<p>
	<strong>VICE: What&#39;s your favorite type of cigarette?</strong><br />
	<strong>John Wilson: </strong>Any cigarette that isn&rsquo;t taxed in New York City.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	<strong>What does you mom think of this movie and your dirty, nasty habit?</strong><br />
	Oh, I don&rsquo;t smoke. My mom also doesn&rsquo;t really watch anything unless my dad is watching it.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	<strong>Well, what does your dad think of your movie?</strong><br />
	I&rsquo;m pretty sure my father would be able to relate to the film, although he&rsquo;d never admit it. I haven&rsquo;t really shown it to any family yet because it might make them very sad.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Your video is chock-full of helpful tips, but if you had to choose one single takeaway for the audience, what would it be?</strong><br />
	That you really need to commit to something, if you want to do it well.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Is there a single clip in the movie that you can&#39;t believe you captured? I laughed out loud when I saw the stylish bachelor and the convertible full of smokers.&nbsp;</strong><br />
	I really knew I had a movie once I got that convertible shot. Things like that just started appearing once I decided to take this idea seriously. The bachelor moment was actually captured during a low-budget film shoot that I stumbled upon in Bushwick. It&rsquo;s really interesting how acting looks in real life when you remove the production.</p>
<p>
	<strong>You seem to shoot constantly. Do you have an idea of the film you&#39;re trying to make when you start? Or are you just gathering footage for a bunch of films at once?&nbsp;</strong><br />
	I always have a little camera on me whenever I leave the house. This project actually began over a year ago, as a film called <em>Midtown Cigarette Break</em>. It started mutating once I tried to quit smoking.</p>
<p>
	I ended up shooting other people smoking whenever I wanted a cigarette and fleshed out the rest of the film with daily observations. I&rsquo;ve been using the same camera for a while, so it&rsquo;s easy to dig up footage from three or four years ago, if I need to.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	<strong>How do you organize your footage? <a href="http://vimeo.com/50493471">John&nbsp;Baldessari</a>&nbsp;has a huge collection of images organized by subject. Do you do something differently?</strong><br />
	I organize all my footage by the date it was shot, and then arrange everything in a timeline once I begin a project. I also keep a meticulous daily log. That makes it a little easier to search by keyword when looking for a specific event.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	<strong>What&#39;s next?</strong><br />
	I want to make <em>New York Post: The Movie</em>. It&rsquo;s about a man who wakes up one morning and finds that he&rsquo;s trapped inside a copy of the <em>New York Post</em>.</p>
<p>
	<em><a href="http://www.vice.com/read/prism-index-2" target="_blank">Jeffrey Bowers</a>&nbsp;is a tall, mustached guy from Ohio who&#39;s seen too many weird movies. He currently lives in Brooklyn, working as an art and film curator. He is a programmer at the Hamptons International Film Festival and screens for the Tribeca Film Festival. He also self-publishes a super-fancy mixed-media art serial called&nbsp;<a href="http://twitter.com/prismindex" target="_blank">PRISM index</a>.</em></p>
<p>
	<em>Follow Jeffrey Bowers on <a href="http://twitter.com/prismindex">Twitter</a>.</em></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299283</guid>
<author>Jeffrey Bowers</author>
<category>film, cigarettes, short not stupid, VICE SHorts, film, john wilson</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Want to Climb Mt. Everest? You Must Bring Back 17 Pounds of Garbage</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/want-to-climb-mt-everest-you-must-bring-back-17-pounds-of-garbage-mb-test</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Want to Climb Mt. Everest? You Must Bring Back 17 Pounds of Garbage
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299287</guid>
<author>Ben Richmond</author>
<category>tech, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Facebook Censoring the Syrian Opposition?</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/facebook-and-the-crisis-in-syria</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/139646/SyrianRevolutionPage5.jpg" style="width: 642px; height: 743px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>All images via the author</i></p>
<p>
	Last December,a womanfrom the Syrian communityin Torontoreached out to mefor helpafter a Syrian opposition Facebook page, for which she was an administrator, was expunged from the internet.She told me that Facebook had deleted the page, called Likes for Syria, in mid December, by which time it had garnered more than 80,000 &quot;likes.&quot;Several Syrian Canadians had organized the page shortly after the revolution in Syria began,backin 2011, and used it as a tool for posting news stories about the crisis, spreading messages of hope, and creating awarenessin the Western world&mdash;something that many feel is desperately needed.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;We feel like our freedom of speech has been totally taken away,&rdquo; saidFarisAlshawaf, anotheradministrator forLikes for Syria. &ldquo;We have a right to talk about what is happening.&rdquo;Facebook had removed the page once before but quickly republished it after administrators made an appeal. Just days later, Facebook deletedthepagea second time.</p>
<p>
	Yet Likes for Syria is hardly alone. In the past six months, Facebook has deleted dozens of opposition pages&mdash;includingonestarted by Syrian youthroughly amonth before the revolutionbegun&mdash;because theyallegedlyviolate the company&#39;s <a href="http://www.facebook.com/communitystandards">Community Standards</a> policyand <a href="http://www.facebook.com/terms.php">Terms of Use</a>agreement.Two weeks ago, the<a href="http://bit.ly/1aojZAO" target="_blank"><em>Atlantic</em></a>reported that Facebook opposition pages were disappearing. While I was doing more research about the issue, Facebook took down another page. This time, it erased the Syrian Coalition page, amovethat shocked administrators and causedpanicin the Syrian community, as it was seen as one of the most important and safe pages of the revolution. People from the Syrian community reached out to me again and sent me screenshot images of what had been reported to Facebook.It seemed clear that many of the images would have been very hard totake offense to and were not violent in nature.</p>
<p>
	Now Facebookfinds itself in an extraordinarily complicated situation. Its role as the world&rsquo;s biggest social platform has hit a serious stumbling block and put the company in a position whereits actionsareaffecting a civil war.The<a href="http://aje.me/1cwjvUG" target="_blank">UN has reported</a>thatthe conflict has already taken more than 100,000 liveshave already been lost. Facebookhas become responsible forglobally policingits users, many of whom arenowpart ofincreasingly violent revolutionswhose messages are breaking company policies, but who have come to rely on Facebook to share information.I can attest to interviewing people in hiding over Facebook chat for stories I&rsquo;ve worked on. Last spring, we interviewed a man named Louay Sakka, who, from his home in Ontario, has played a vital role in facilitating communications for the Free Syrian Army (FSA) using social media platforms, including Facebook.</p>
<p>
	All over the country, media centers have been established where displaced Syrians and rebels can hop onto a revolutionary Facebook page and communicate what is happening and where. To me, Sakka&rsquo;s role in helping rebels unite halfway across the world seemed pretty outrageous at the time, but this is partly how the revolution has worked.<br />
	<br />
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/139647/SyrianCoaltion1.jpg" style="width: 642px; height: 856px;" /></p>
<p>
	I reached out tothe<a href="http://www.syriansupportgroup.org/" target="_blank">Syrian Support Group</a> (SSG)&mdash;one ofthefew North American groups able to provide help to Syria&mdash;tosee if they had been affected.The SSG has also relied heavily on Facebook to communicate with the moderate members of the opposition. According to Dan Layman, who works very closely with the moderate members of the FSA and the US State Department to facilitate aid to moderate members of the opposition, they had. Layman says SSG was working onthe English translation of the Supreme Military Council&rsquo;s (SMC) Facebookpage, which was previously the moderate command structure for the majority of FSA groups, but it has been taken down, while the Arab page remains posted.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;This is really affecting us, because we have used these pages to help deliver the messages of what is happeningin Syriato the Western world and to communicatewith members of the moderateoppositionin Syria,&rdquo; Layman told me. Hehad reached out to theUSState Department totry to determinewhathappened andwas told that Facebook had its own group of employees scrolling through the pages looking for red flags that might promote violence or coarse language.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;I think what is happening is that Facebook has determined that some of the things we were posting was promoting violence, when really we arejusttrying to explain what is happening.The opposition are not terrorists.&rdquo; Part of Layman&rsquo;s work is translating from Arabic to English messages such as&ldquo;In Damascus,there was four bombings andmany martyrs.&rdquo;It&rsquo;s possible that someone atFacebook thought the language was offensive, butno one knows for sure. &ldquo;The revolutionary pagewas the easiest way to get the Supreme Military Council&rsquo;s position out directly to Western media,&quot; Layman said.</p>
<p>
	Many people in this community believe that the<a href="http://bit.ly/1bXaffr" target="_blank">Syrian Electronic Army (SEA)</a>has been behind a vast majority of the reporting and are in part to blame for the removal of these pages. The SEA isbelieved to work closely with theAssad regime, though they steadfastly deny it.Regardless, they have proven to bean intelligent electronic force that hasclaimedtohacksystems such as Skype and Twitter.</p>
<p>
	Last December, the SEA posted that they would be working toward having all opposition pages deleted, though it has since deleted that message. Whether they are behind it or not, these pages are coming down at a rapid rate. An internet-securityexpert&mdash;who requested anonymity&mdash;told me that if you were to draw a line from the Facebook pages being taken down and images being reported, it wouldlikelylead to the SEA.Although the SEA clearly attempts to orchestrate mass report campaigns, which result in the review of flagged content, Facebook has improved its monitoring of mass reporting and clearly believes that the buck stops with the humans who review content for Terms of Service violations. The expert did not believe that mass reports alone couldforce page takedowns.<br />
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/139648/SyrianRevolutionPage3.jpg" style="width: 642px; height: 323px;" /></p>
<p>
	Obviously,Facebookcan&rsquo;t be blamed for what is happening in Syria, but there is nowa need for them to respond to theirrole in the revolutionand what might happennext.Could they try to shut down revolution talkscompletely?The social site is available to anyone over 13 years old, so there are obvious reasonswhytheywouldwant to keep content clean. Butmany of the images that havebeen reportedand deletedon the opposition&rsquo;s pages were warning people about the locations of reported bomb detonations. Other deleted messages included reports from the UN that notified the outside worldaboutthe state of the conflict. People likeAlshawafhave family in Syria and no real way to connect with them, except through social media.</p>
<p>
	I spoke to Linda Griffin, head of policy communicationsforFacebookin London,thesame daythe SyrianCoalitionpage was deleted.There&#39;s no doubt that Facebook is in a difficult position in this complicated situation, andshe seemedaware that these pages played a significant role for communication and connection. Griffindenied that the SEA had hacked Facebook,stating they learned early on in the platform&rsquo;s history that people would try to abuse the system this way.Sheexplained that if a page repeatedly breaches the rules, it wouldbe shut and that itdoesn&rsquo;t matter if it has been reported one time or 1,000.Shortly after our conversation, I sent the screenshotimages thatI received from theadministratorsof the Syrian Coalition pageand asked her to explain how they broke the Terms of Use for Facebook.The following morning, I received an emailletting me know Facebook had made a mistake with the Syrian Coalition page,and that they had put the page back up.</p>
<p>
	This was considered a relief for many, but administrators for Likes for Syria and theEnglish version of SMCwant their pages reinstated,too.Combined,they had over 300,000 followers andexperienced the same problems the Syrian Coalitionpagehad.They have started an online petition asking Facebook to stop its censorship. All the administratorsI spoke withareawareofwhat will break the Terms of Useagreement with Facebook andsay theyare trying to avoid this.One oftheTermsof Usethat is likely being broken isthatnudityis not allowed on the site.Many of these pages will often post pictures of emaciated children and adults, and the images are taken down. Unfortunately,these are the images of war.<br />
	<br />
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/139649/SyrianCoaltion4.jpg" style="width: 642px; height: 856px;" /></p>
<p>
	There areveryfew journalists working in Syria becauseit is too dangerous (though you can watch our <a href="http://www.vice.com/en_ca/ground-zero" target="_blank"><em>Ground Zero: Syria</em> series here</a>), and there are even fewer methods of translating to the Western world what is happening. In the absence of journalists, Facebook has become theprimary tool of communication to the outside world.When Facebook decides to delete a page, it&rsquo;s deleting one of few tunnels the opposition has to access those outside of Syria. &ldquo;In doing that, and taking down the content, they are kind of doing the moderate forces a disservice. It&rsquo;s not terrorism at all they are taking down the pages of people who are directly fighting the al Qaeda&ndash;affiliated rebels. Someone at Facebook is missing the point,&rdquo; said Layman.</p>
<p>
	At one time, Facebook saw its involvement in the Arab Spring as something to be proud of. Facebook founder and CEO<strong> </strong>Mark <a href="http://reut.rs/1j4dXVQ" target="_blank">Zuckerberg had discussed</a> his social media platform as being a useful tool. In 2012 Reuters reported that shortly after Zuckerberg filed papers to raise over $5 billion as Facebook went public, he sent an open letter to prospective investors. In it Zuckerberg wrote:</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;We believe building tools to help people share can bring a more honest and transparent dialogue around government that could lead to more direct empowerment of people, more accountability for officials and better solutions to some of the biggest problems of our time.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	It makes sense thatFacebook shouldn&#39;t be a place to fearture organized worldwide violence, and they are very clear on that. Facebookalsocannot be used as a place to support terrorism.</p>
<p>
	This could no doubt becomea PR nightmarefor the billion-dollar company, butwhile Facebook figures out how to handle what&rsquo;snext,revolutionarieswho havecome to rely on the platformforconnecting andcommunicating will need to tread very carefully andpossiblystart considering alternative options.Butthe question now is,where will the revolutiongo?</p>
<p>
	Sami says that manyfeel the world hasstarted to turn its back on them, despite the evidence of Assad&rsquo;s crimes,but that they will continue to get their messages out.&ldquo;This will not end our journey to freedom and justice; we will still rebuild our destroyed country. We are made of will and determination.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	<em>Follow Angela Hennessy on <a href="http://www.twitter.com/angelamaries">Twitter</a>.</em></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/298900</guid>
<author>Angela Hennessy</author>
<category>news, facebook, politics, Syria, war, terrorism, Syrian Electronic Army, social media, censorship, Likes for Syria</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Paris Lees: I Love Wolf Whistles and Catcalls; Am I a Bad Feminist?</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/i-love-wolf-whistles-and-catcalls-am-i-a-bad-feminist</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 16:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140441/paris-ibiza-web-spt.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>Image by <a href="https://twitter.com/SptSam">Sam Taylor</a></i></p>
<p>
	Last summer I went to Ibiza, Spain, where I was catcalled, sexually objectified, and treated like a piece of meat by men the entire week. And it was absolutely awesome. It got to the point where I couldn&#39;t even be bothered to follow any of it up. Every time some hot guy got fresh with me, I just thought, <em>OK, I could fuck you, but there might be some even hotter stud serving it up later</em>. I guess it&rsquo;s like when I used to live by the sea and never got around to going swimming. It was just always there, you know? You forget to get wet.</p>
<p>
	So as I look around the misery we call London, England, in March, forgive me for feeling a little sad that I&rsquo;m not in Ibiza, Land of Sexual Objectification. I love catcalls. I love car toots. I love random men shouting, &ldquo;Hello, beautiful!&rdquo; as if my mere presence just made their day. I like being called &quot;princess&quot; and ignoring them as I giggle inside. I like being eye-fucked on the escalator and wondering if I&rsquo;ve just made him spring a boner. That eye-fuck, by the way, is&nbsp;<a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/articles/199303/the-biology-attraction" target="_blank">an age-old mating signal</a>. I live for it.</p>
<p>
	So yeah, I&rsquo;m a bit of a slut. I also used to be a prostitute. And before that, well, a boy. Uh-huh. And I&rsquo;m a total attention junkie. So I may&nbsp;not represent all women. Who does, though? I&rsquo;m a feminist because I don&rsquo;t like men telling me how to think or behave or experience the world, and I don&rsquo;t like women doing it, either. Laura Bates recently wrote an article for&nbsp;the<em> Guardian</em>&nbsp;called&nbsp;<a href="http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/womens-blog/2014/feb/28/women-street-harassment-power-control-violence" target="_blank">&ldquo;Women Should Not Accept Street Harassment as &lsquo;Just a Compliment.&rsquo;&rdquo;</a>&nbsp;I truly admire the work Laura does with&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/EverydaySexism" target="_blank">Everyday Sexism</a>&nbsp;to highlight some horrendous abuse, and you should&nbsp;<a href="http://www.everydaysexism.com/" target="_blank">visit the site</a>&nbsp;and check out some of the shit people have had to deal with. It&rsquo;s awful. And she&rsquo;s not wrong. No one should accept harassment. Harassment, by its very nature, is unacceptable. But is catcalling always harassment?</p>
<p>
	The<em> Independent</em>&#39;s social-media editor,&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/FelicityMorse" target="_blank">Felicity Morse</a>,&nbsp;loves catcalls, and I&rsquo;m guessing she gets loads because she&rsquo;s freaking hot. Even though I&rsquo;m probably not supposed to say that. She told me, &ldquo;If I&#39;m dressed up in a sexy little something, if I&rsquo;m sashaying down the street and tossing a head of freshly washed hair like I think I&#39;m Beyonc&eacute;, I find a catcall rather appreciative. But if I&#39;m out jogging or running to the bus stop, huddling past a building site in the rain, I find it intrusive.&rdquo; It also depends on the number of men and what they&rsquo;re doing: &ldquo;If they are working on a building site or something, where they can&#39;t really leave their work, it&rsquo;s almost traditional to wolf-whistle and pretty meaningless, so I don&#39;t feel threatened. But a big gang of young men in the dark? I wouldn&#39;t even acknowledge I&#39;d heard them.&rdquo; Would she give her number to a guy in the street? &ldquo;Probably, but I wouldn&#39;t have high hopes for a relationship! That&#39;s not harassment; it&#39;s flattering. If he doesn&#39;t go away?&nbsp;<em>That&#39;s</em>&nbsp;harassment.&rdquo; She&rsquo;d still ban catcalls on the basis that they upset many women, though.</p>
<p>
	This is kind of my problem with the debate around street attention. It&rsquo;s part of a culture that infantilizes women and teaches them to be constantly afraid. I wasn&rsquo;t brought up that way, and I don&rsquo;t feel frightened when some spunky dude comes and talks to me. I hate this idea that all men are rapists-in-waiting and that all women are victims-in-waiting. It&rsquo;s patronizing and doesn&rsquo;t help anyone. Many women are sexual and like to look and feel and be seen sexual. I&rsquo;m one of those women. But if I smile next time a man wolf-whistles at me, does that make me a bad person? What if the next person he wolf-whistles at is a woman who&rsquo;s been raped? What if he ruins her day?</p>
<p>
	Nichi Hodgson, author of&nbsp;<em>Bound to You,&nbsp;</em>sex columnist for&nbsp;<em>Men&#39;s Health</em>,&nbsp;and director of&nbsp;<a href="http://ethicalporn.org/" target="_blank">the Ethical Porn Partnership</a>, said there&rsquo;s a certain kind of middle-class woman that finds catcalls particularly galling: &ldquo;There&rsquo;s a sense of being sullied if an uncouth or lower-class kind of man&mdash;a white-van man, for example&mdash;heckles. But if it&#39;s a Roger Sterling type who can just about pull it off with a certain retro-sexist panache, the offense isn&#39;t experienced the same.&rdquo; Laura said that growing up in working-class West Yorkshire and learning to hit back with witty repartee was a kind of rite of passage. The same is true where I come from, although it&rsquo;s the blokes who need the comebacks. Let&rsquo;s just say Nottingham girls aren&rsquo;t shy.</p>
<p>
	Speaking of which, I wanted to hear from some regular women, not professional feminists, so I called my sister. She&rsquo;s super hot and cool and gets loads of attention from guys, but apart from that she&rsquo;s pretty &quot;normal,&quot; whatever that means. She&rsquo;s a property-services officer in Nottingham, 28, college-educated, of mixed race, and describes her sexuality as &ldquo;straight but open-minded.&rdquo; Here&rsquo;s what she had to say.</p>
<p>
	<strong>VICE: Sista! I&rsquo;m doing an article on catcalling. What do you think about it?</strong><br />
	<strong>Natti:</strong>&nbsp;I don&rsquo;t find it offensive; I find that it can be a compliment, and I also think that the guys are brave because they&rsquo;re just there in broad daylight, shouting down the street.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Have you ever hooked up with a guy in the street?</strong><br />
	<strong>Natti:</strong>&nbsp;No, no, no, no, no! I wouldn&rsquo;t do that. If he&rsquo;s that sure of himself&hellip; well, it&rsquo;s arrogant, isn&rsquo;t it?</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Do you ever find it sexy?</strong><br />
	<strong>Natti:&nbsp;</strong>Yeah, of course, sometimes.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Me: Would you ever wear something sexy to catch men&rsquo;s attention in the street?</strong><br />
	<strong>Natti:&nbsp;</strong>Wouldn&rsquo;t every woman if she could?</p>
<p>
	I phoned my mom afterward, and she said catcalls are like periods&mdash;she hated them when she was younger but feels sad now they&rsquo;re about to dry up. Wow, mother.</p>
<p>
	One woman who emailed me in response to an enquiry I put out on Facebook&mdash;one of many who preferred to remain anonymous because they don&rsquo;t want you to, you know,<em>&nbsp;judge them&mdash;</em>takes catcalling as a compliment, too: &ldquo;I have friends who say they feel powerless and objectified when being catcalled. I think they made a choice about how it makes them feel, and I choose to feel empowered.&rdquo; She once hooked up with a guy from the street, but the sex was &ldquo;Ehhhh,&rdquo;&nbsp;so don&rsquo;t get too excited. Still, how many of you reading this wouldn&rsquo;t exist had one of your parents not made a pass at the other in the street?</p>
<p>
	The<em> Guardian</em>&rsquo;s Ellie Mae O&#39;Hagan said it doesn&rsquo;t surprise her that some women like catcalls: &ldquo;One of the ways patriarchy sustains itself is by convincing women that their worth is determined by the approval of men along a strict set of terms. Getting wolf-whistled at is a small confirmation that a woman is meeting the terms patriarchy demands of her.&rdquo; Couldn&rsquo;t you say that about pretty much anything, though? Like, if a woman tells another woman &ldquo;Great dress!&rdquo; is she letting her know that she&rsquo;s meeting the expectations of capitalism and the fashion industry and beauty culture? Or is she just telling her she likes her dress? Or is it a bit of both?</p>
<p>
	I&rsquo;ll be honest: Ideology bores the shit out of me, but Ellie does have a point about catcalls&#39; being an expression of power. There&rsquo;s a power imbalance, for example, between those who feel entitled to express their sexuality in public (straight men) versus those who don&rsquo;t (like gay men, older people, and lesbian women). Ellie goes further and&nbsp;<a href="http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention/violence/global_campaign/en/chap6.pdf" target="_blank">cites studies</a>&nbsp;that suggest sexual violence is &quot;to an extent rooted in ideologies of male sexual entitlement,&rdquo; though I struggle to see any real connection between rape and the guy who wolf-whistled at me this morning. As Nichi puts it, &ldquo;I think it&#39;s a misnomer to draw a continuum between street heckling and the paltry rape-conviction rate. Street hecklers don&#39;t go on to become rapists any more than readers of lads&#39; mags do.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	I don&rsquo;t want feminists to stop campaigning against the terrible abuse girls and women face every day in Britain, and I&rsquo;m grateful to anyone raising awareness about feminist issues. And men, for the record, I haven&rsquo;t spoken to any woman yet who likes being told, &ldquo;I&rsquo;d like to fuck you up the ass&rdquo; as you drive past her in the street. So stop it with that, you shitheads. I just wish we could make a distinction between harassment like this and harmless fun.</p>
<p>
	Because whether you like it or not, there&rsquo;s a big difference between &ldquo;Hello gorgeous&rdquo; and&mdash;as Laura Bates was, abhorrently, told&mdash;&ldquo;I&rsquo;d hold a knife to that.&rdquo; I don&rsquo;t want to make other women feel pathetic if they don&rsquo;t enjoy street attention, but I also don&rsquo;t want to feel pathetic for enjoying it. I don&rsquo;t speak for all women, and neither do you. I&rsquo;ll leave you with the words of 86-year-old Jinx Allen Craig, the woman in&nbsp;<a href="http://www.today.com/id/44182286/ns/today-today_news/t/subject-american-girl-italy-photo-speaks-out/#.Uxc4I-d_vuc" target="_blank">catcalling&rsquo;s greatest portrait</a>,&nbsp;<em>An American Girl in Italy</em>: &ldquo;It&rsquo;s&nbsp;not&nbsp;a symbol of harassment. It&rsquo;s a symbol of a woman having an absolutely wonderful time!&rdquo; Jinx, call me. We need to book our flights to Ibiza.</p>
<p>
	<em>Follow Paris Lees on&nbsp;<a href="http://twitter.com/ParisLees" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.</em></p>
<p>
<!--recommended--></p>

]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299269</guid>
<author>Paris Lees</author>
<category>stuff, cat-calling, feminism, misogyny, wolf-whistles, sexism</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Plants Are Capable of Making Complex Decisions</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/plants-are-capable-of-making-complex-decisions-mb-test</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 16:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Plants Are Capable of Making Complex Decisions
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299238</guid>
<author>Becky Ferreira</author>
<category>tech, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ultra-Orthodox Jews Are Refusing to Join the Israeli Army</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/orthodox-jews-dont-want-to-join-the-israeli-army</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 15:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140182/Daniel-Tepper---Heradim-Protest01.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	Hundreds of thousands of ultra-Orthodox Jews (Haredim) crowded into the center of Jerusalem on Sunday to protest against mandatory armed service. As things stand, they are exempt from being drafted into the military so that they can carry out their orthodox lifestyle, but a proposed bill could change that, and the Haredim are not happy.</p>
<p>
	They turned Jerusalem into a sea of black hats, white shirts, and long beards, but there were no fiery speeches and no chanting. Instead, the Haredim came in massive numbers to pray. The men carried out the Amidah, a standing prayer that&rsquo;s recited silently. They were observing Mincha, the afternoon prayer service. Bodies of all sizes swayed back and forth while their lips moved without noise. Haredi leaders had called on all males over nine to attend the protest. Even women were asked to join, though they stood apart from the men, in segregated groups along the periphery of the crowd. Around 500,000 were expected to show up. Local media later reported that the real number was between 250,000 and 400,000. Either way, it was the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VgiLVwZ1w9k" target="_blank">biggest crowd I&rsquo;ve ever stood in</a>, but it was eerily quiet.</p>
<p>
	Until last year, the ultra-Orthodox had been exempt from serving in the Israeli military since the creation of the state, in 1949. While the army has the authority to conscript any citizen or permanent resident once he or she hits 18, teenage Haredim are able to avoid conscription by studying religious texts in institutions called yeshivas. The Haredim feel that this study is a contribution to Judaism that is equal to&mdash;if not greater than&mdash;serving in the Israeli army. They see compulsory military service as a form of religious persecution, denying them the right to practice and pulling them toward a more secular lifestyle.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140183/Daniel-Tepper---Heradim-Protest05.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	A lot of Israel&rsquo;s Jewish population pretty much resents the ultra-Orthodox community. In their eyes, the Haredim are unwilling to contribute to society, place a financial burden upon the country as a whole, and exert <a href="http://www.aljazeera.com/indepth/features/2014/02/circumcision-ruling-upsets-liberal-jews-201422314430727638.html" target="_blank">cultural control</a> over secular and liberal Jews through the <a href="http://www.jewishvirtuallibrary.org/jsource/Politics/courts.html" target="_blank">rabbinical courts</a>. Haredim make up ten percent of the eight million Jews living in Israel. They receive the most financial assistance from the state while being one of the lowest-employed demographic groups in the country. They are also a rapidly growing segment of the population&mdash;it&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.hiddush.org/article-2308-0-In_2059_the_ultraOrthodox_will_make_up_between_23_and_40_of_Israel%E2%80%99s_population_says_Israel%E2%80%99s_Central_Bureau_of_Statistics.aspx" target="_blank">estimated</a> that, in 25 years, a quarter of all Israel&#39;s Jews will be ultra-Orthodox.</p>
<p>
	Haim, a teenage Haredi boy, came up to me at the protest and asked if I wanted to put on <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cKdr50iLqf8" target="_blank">tefillin</a>&mdash;two small black boxes worn on the arms that contain scrolls with verses from the&nbsp;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Torah" target="_blank" title="Torah">Torah</a>. I politely declined and asked him how he felt about the protest today. Haim was born in Jerusalem and would be compelled to serve in the military if and when the law takes effect. He feels that the state is trying to lure religious youth away from their pious lifestyle, but today&rsquo;s rally had made him hopeful for the future. &ldquo;The whole community is putting their differences aside and coming together for the good of us all,&rdquo; he said. He thinks the law will pass but says, &ldquo;This protest is about showing the world that we oppose it. We oppose the state trying to get rid of prayer.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	In <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-19492627" target="_blank">2012</a>, the Israeli Supreme Court <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/23/world/middleeast/israeli-court-invalidates-a-military-exemption.html" target="_blank">declared</a> the exemption illegal on the grounds of inequality. The government proposed a bill last month that would call for strict numbers of yeshiva students to be drafted into the military while still allowing a certain amount of exemptions. Those who refused to serve in the military could face jail time. Even though the bill is expected to be passed into law later this month, it wouldn&rsquo;t take effect for three years, which is a long time in Israeli politics. The Haredi community plans to keep the pressure up, through <a href="http://www.timesofisrael.com/thirteen-haredi-protesters-to-be-indicted/">protests</a>&nbsp;and prayers, in an effort to stop the law.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140184/Daniel-Tepper---Heradim-Protest04.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	The demonstration was an impressive display of the sheer numbers that the ultra-Orthodox can muster when they need to. The major roads leading into the city were blocked off. The main bus station and the light-rail system were shut down. Thousands of police were stationed in the area to prevent any of the violence that has recently&nbsp;<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gn5mrHS08hw">erupted</a>&nbsp;at ultra-Orthodox protests. But on Sunday, the cops were conspicuously absent from the throng, choosing to hang back.</p>
<p>
	Flyers with protest slogans littered the streets, and young boys held up signs that declared in English and Hebrew, &ldquo;The Israeli Government harshly persecutes and tramples observant Jews!&rdquo; and &ldquo;You created the problem by establishing the State of Israel. Don&rsquo;t ask us to fix it by joining the IDF!&rdquo; This second statement is evidence of a strong anti-Zionist sentiment held by some sections of the Haredi population, most notably Hasidic Jews.</p>
<p>
	Hasidic Jews believe in a form of ultra-Orthodox Judaism that originated in 18th&nbsp;century Europe. They are easy to spot by their traditional dress and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Payot" target="_blank">payot</a> (long, curly sidelocks). Early Zionism was actually <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haredim_and_Zionism#Early_opposition_to_Zionism" target="_blank">opposed</a>&nbsp;by Hasidic Jews because of what they see as Zionism&#39;s tendency to champion secularism, and the belief that Jews made a promise with God not to establish a state in Israel using force. So <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_wars_involving_Israel" target="_blank">obviously</a> they&rsquo;re not all that happy with how things have gone since Israel&rsquo;s formation.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140185/Daniel-Tepper---Heradim-Protest03.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	One of the largest anti-Zionist sects, the Satmar, has large communities in Williamsburg, Brooklyn, and Stamford Hill, London. The Satmar are so thoroughly opposed to the Israeli state that they accept no monetary aid from the government. One of their religious leaders recently declared a &ldquo;<a href="http://jpupdates.com/2014/02/23/audio-satmar-rebbe-kj-idf-draft-bill-survived-auschwitz-well-defeat-israeli-govt/">jihad against the Israeli government</a>.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	I met Yakov, a 20-year-old Hasidic Satmar from the UK, before the protest began. He told me that &ldquo;it&rsquo;s better to convert to Islam than join the army.&rdquo; He explained, &ldquo;At least then you&rsquo;re still monotheistic. In the army, you&rsquo;re worshipping the state.&rdquo; Yakov is against any interference in what he calls a &quot;pure&quot; way of life. For him, being Hasidic means living a life full of prayer. He says that he has a closer connection to God by abiding to strict rules and daily rituals that fill his life with deep satisfaction and meaning.</p>
<p>
	He sees no hypocrisy in being anti-Zionist and living in Israel. &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t have any other choice. I want to live in an environment where I can be immersed in a religious lifestyle. Living in Mea Shearim [a Hasidic enclave in Jerusalem] keeps me pure. I can go outside and not see anything secular.&rdquo; While being a relatively idyllic place for a Hasidic Jew to live, tensions against the state in Mea Shearim frequently <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FjTLBTCNsII">boil over</a>&nbsp;into full-scale riots. This past July, a Haredi soldier who was visiting his family in the neighborhood had to be <a href="http://www.ynetnews.com/articles/0,7340,L-4402982,00.html">rescued</a>&nbsp;from an angry mob by police.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140186/Daniel-Tepper---Heradim-Protest02.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /><br />
	<br />
	Because Yakov is not an Israeli citizen, he wouldn&rsquo;t need to serve in the military. Yet he is a strong opponent to the idea and doesn&rsquo;t think the government can back up its threat to imprison those who choose not to serve. &ldquo;They can&#39;t arrest every yeshiva student,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;They&rsquo;re going to have to build detention camps for them and what&#39;s that going to look like? Putting Jews in camps?&quot;</p>
<p>
	He had a fair point.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;Even if they started doing that, we&#39;d start yeshivas in the jails. Wherever they put us, we&#39;ll study; there&rsquo;s no difference.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	After the prayer service had concluded, religious music blared from towering racks of speakers that had been set up around the area. The mood was festive, and young Haredi men began to dance, arm-in-arm, in large circles. As the sun set, tens of thousands of Haredim crowded the streets. Encouraged by their sheer weight of number, they seemed confident that God would answer their prayers. Whether it&#39;s through political <span class="st">maneuvering</span> or divine intervention, Yakov told me, &ldquo;One thing is for sure: We won&#39;t be serving in the Israeli army.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	<em>Follow Daniel Tepper on <a href="http://twitter.com/daniel_tepper">Twitter</a>.</em></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299228</guid>
<author>Daniel Tepper</author>
<category>news, Haredim, orthodox jews, conscription, Hasidic Jews, Israel, IDF, protest, prayer</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Future of MMA Could Be RoboCop Suits</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/the-future-of-mma-could-be-robocop-suits</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[The Future of MMA Could Be RoboCop Suits
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299232</guid>
<author>Michael Hresko</author>
<category>sports, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dont Listen to the Republican Warmongers Shouting About Ukraine </title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/dont-listen-to-republicans-warmongers-shouting-about-ukraine</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140272/john-mccain-ukraine.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 360px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>John McCain is one of the prominent Republicans using the crisis in Ukraine to call Barack Obama weak, again. Photo via Flickr user <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/gageskidmore/" target="_blank">Gage Skidmore</a></i></p>
<p>
	The millennial generation is often accused of being narcissistic, of inhabiting an imaginary world where events and actions are only real and important insofar as they touch on <em>us</em>, the super special ones who actually matter. There&rsquo;s probably a kernel of truth to that stereotype&mdash;hey, young people can be shitty and self-centered. But even the most hashtagging, selfie-taking, Thought Catalog&ndash;contributing 20-something can&rsquo;t match the sheer ego of Republican foreign-policy hawks, who think that there&#39;s no problem that American bombs can&#39;t solve.</p>
<p>
	In case you need some background: Late last week, Russia <a href="https://news.vice.com/video/russian-roulette-the-invasion-of-ukraine-dispatch-one?trk_source=homepage-lede" target="_blank">sent troops to Crimea</a>, which is a big deal because Crimea is in Ukraine, a country that has recently gone through the <a href="http://www.vice.com/vice-news/ukraine-burning" target="_blank">bloody process of overthrowing its government</a> and getting a new one. According to <a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2014/03/hawks-ukraine-president-obamas-fault-104196.html" target="_blank">some prominent GOP politicians</a>, this is Barack Obama&rsquo;s fault.</p>
<p>
	Onetime presidential candidate John McCain said that the crisis in Ukraine is &ldquo;the ultimate result of a feckless foreign policy where no one believes in America&rsquo;s strength anymore.&rdquo; Senator Jim Inhofe got on his high horse to announce that the president&rsquo;s &ldquo;disarming of America over the past five years limits our options in Ukraine today.&rdquo; House Intelligence Committee chairman Mike Rogers <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2014/03/02/mike-rogers-russia_n_4884922.html" target="_blank">went on Fox News</a> to say that Putin was playing chess while Obama was playing marbles. And Lindsey Graham, a sack of skin currently serving in the Senate, thinks that if we had killed more Libyans in response to the Benghazi embassy attack Vladimir Putin would have stayed away from Russia&rsquo;s weakened neighbor:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en">
	<p>
		It started with Benghazi. When you kill Americans and nobody pays a price, you invite this type of aggression. <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23Ukraine&amp;src=hash" target="_blank">#Ukraine</a></p>
	&mdash; Lindsey Graham (@GrahamBlog) <a href="https://twitter.com/GrahamBlog/statuses/440920315292811264" target="_blank">March 4, 2014</a></blockquote>
<p>
	Obviously this is just a repetition of that old Republican narrative about Obama&#39;s being a weak president. Sure, he sent a lot of young soldiers to <a href="http://cnsnews.com/news/article/ali-meyer/74-us-afghan-casualties-came-after-obama-ordered-troops-increased" target="_blank">fight and die</a> in Afghanistan, he oversaw the expansion of using <a href="http://www.motherjones.com/politics/2013/10/obama-drone-counterterrorism-war-legacy" target="_blank">drone strikes</a> to kill people in Pakistan and Yemen, he bombed Libya <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/06/21/opinion/21Ackerman.html?_r=0" target="_blank">without Congressional approval</a>, he sent a SEAL team to assassinate Osama bin Laden in Pakistan <a href="http://www.economist.com/blogs/newsbook/2011/05/pakistan_and_osama_bin_laden" target="_blank">without the cooperation</a> of the Pakistani government (supposedly a US ally), and he&rsquo;s continued the long-standing American practice of spending a <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/wonkblog/wp/2013/01/07/everything-chuck-hagel-needs-to-know-about-the-defense-budget-in-charts/" target="_blank">staggering amount</a> of money on the military (though he just proposed some <a href="http://www.upi.com/Top_News/US/2014/03/04/Obama-scales-back-military-spending-requests-defense-budget-cuts/9611393958680/"><span class="s1">cuts to defense spending</span></a>)&mdash;but he&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.frontpagemag.com/2013/dgreenfield/obama-bows-shakes-hands-with-cuban-dictator-raul-castro/" target="_blank">bowed</a> to dictators and other foreign leaders when greeting them, so he must be a pussy! He won&rsquo;t even <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2014/01/the-hawks-hypocrisy-on-the-iran-sanctions-bill/283287/" target="_blank">go to war with Iran</a>!</p>
<p>
	Sometimes these hawkish critiques of Obama veer into territory that is legitimately terrifying, like when the <em>Wall Street Journal </em>editorial board <a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702304026804579413900968932702" target="_blank">wrote that</a> the US Navy should deploy some ships near Russia. (As transparent, empty militaristic muscle flexing? As an actual precursor to maybe potentially getting into a war with Russia? Just because it&rsquo;s no fun to have these big ole battleships if you don&rsquo;t use them?)</p>
<p>
	More often, the Republican hawks are just kind of vague. Putin is clearly winning this game of chess/marbles&mdash;he&#39;s basically a genius, as far as Republicans are concerned&mdash;but it&#39;s not clear what moves Obama needs to make to decisively beat him at whichever board game is being played. &ldquo;Do something,&rdquo; Graham helpfully <a href="http://cnnpressroom.blogs.cnn.com/2014/03/02/sen-lindsey-graham-president-obama-needs-to-do-something/" target="_blank">suggested on CNN</a>, adding that maybe Russia&rsquo;s membership in the G8 should be suspended.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;You&rsquo;ve got to exert energy,&rdquo; former NSA director Michael Hayden <a href="http://www.newsmax.com/newsfront/ukraine-russia-conservatives-putin/2014/03/01/id/555507" target="_blank">told conservative media outlet Newsmax</a>. &ldquo;We just can&#39;t pontificate and condemn Russian activity.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Except the White House is already <a href="http://www.motherjones.com/kevin-drum/2014/03/obamas-response-russia-begins-unfold" target="_blank">doing a bunch of stuff</a>, including canceling a G8 meeting in Sochi and considering freezing the assets and banning the visas of some Russian officials, which is exactly what some Republicans have suggested. Meanwhile, <a href="http://www.google.com/hostednews/afp/article/ALeqM5g98fUr-sGcOPWuSGj6bWm55ny42w?docId=c6e3bd02-4165-43fb-b2f8-fbebc930def8&amp;hl=en" target="_blank">investors are panicking</a> about the invasion of Ukraine, damaging Russia&rsquo;s economy, and the US is coordinating with European countries to <a href="http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2014/03/02/inside-obama-s-plans-for-economic-war-on-russia.html" target="_blank">impose sanctions</a> on the country. It sure seems like Putin&rsquo;s aggression was a terrible idea. But don&rsquo;t take my word for it&mdash;here&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2014/mar/03/obama-ukraine-russia-critics-credibility" target="_blank">the <em>Guardian</em>&rsquo;s Michael Cohen</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
	<p>
		Putin has initiated a conflict that will, quite obviously, result in greater diplomatic and political isolation as well as the potential for economic sanction. He&rsquo;s compounded his loss of a key ally in Kiev by further enflaming Ukrainian nationalism, and his provocations could have a cascading effect in Europe by pushing countries that rely on Russia&rsquo;s natural gas exports to look elsewhere for their energy needs. Putin is the leader of a country with a weak military, an under-performing economy and a host of social, environmental and health-related challenges. Seizing the Crimea will only make the problems facing Russia that much greater.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>
	If the GOP acknowledged that Russia&#39;s actions are more of a problem for Russia than the US, it would problematically leave the party with nothing to yell at Obama about. It would also fly in the face of the Republican tendency to see geopolitics as a high-stakes dick-measuring contest: If America isn&#39;t constantly threatening to go to war with multiple countries, it means Obama is telling everyone he&#39;s weak; if Obama had only <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/marc-thiessen-obamas-weakness-emboldens-putin/2014/03/03/28def926-a2e2-11e3-84d4-e59b1709222c_story.html" target="_blank">bombed the shit out of Syria</a>, Putin would have been too scared of America&#39;s big guns to threaten Crimea.</p>
<p>
	The last time a Republican was in charge of foreign policy was during the administration of George W. Bush, who disastrously invaded Iraq and Afghanistan (and who <a href="http://crooksandliars.com/2014/03/george-w-bush-putin-i-looked-his-eyes-and" target="_blank">was once buddies with Putin</a>). The politicians and talking heads telling Obama to &ldquo;do something&rdquo; are the same ones who have yet to meet a war they didn&rsquo;t like: Graham, for instance, has <a href="http://www.ontheissues.org/international/Lindsey_Graham_War_+_Peace.htm" target="_blank">gone on the record</a> as wanting to intervene in Syria while keeping troops in Iraq and Afghanistan. In their view of the world, whoever is doing the most posturing is winning. No wonder they seem to admire Putin&#39;s tactics so much.</p>
<p>
	<em>Follow Harry Cheadle on <a href="https://twitter.com/HCheadle" target="_blank">Twitter</a>. </em></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299092</guid>
<author>Harry Cheadle</author>
<category>news, ukraine, john mccain, Lindsey Graham, Barack Obama, US politics, US foreign policy, warmongering</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Behind the Scenes of Avey Tare&#039;s Muppet-Filled Debut Video with His New Band, Slasher Flicks</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/behind-the-scenes-of-avey-tares-insane-debut-music-video-with-slasher-flicks</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 15:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Behind the Scenes of Avey Tare's Muppet-Filled Debut Video with His New Band, Slasher Flicks
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299229</guid>
<author>The Creators Project</author>
<category>music, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>VICE Loves Magnum: Humans Become More Honest When We&#039;re Pushed to Our Limits</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/michael-christopher-brown-vice-loves-magnum</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140206/Congo07-edit.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 640px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Democratic Republic of the Congo. An FARDC soldier poses for a portrait near Lake Kivu.</em></p>
<p>
	Photographer Michael Christopher Brown documents places and people in transition&mdash;occasionally eschewing a camera for a camera phone. From Libya and Russia to Broadway and his current base in Goma, in the Democratic Republic of the Congo, Brown said he explores the &ldquo;relationship between distance and honesty.&rdquo; To paraphrase, Brown believes that as we are pushed to our limits, we become more honest.</p>
<p>
	His work in Libya in the aftermath of the fall of Qaddafi was the subject of the HBO documentary <em>Witness: Libya</em> and will appear in his forthcoming book,&nbsp;<em>Libyan Sugar</em>, to be published in 2014 by Twin Palms. With the phone lines failing us, I caught up with Michael over email.</p>
<p>
	<strong>VICE: What do you think of the work that you do? Do you see yourself more as an artist or a journalist?<br />
	Michael Christopher Brown:</strong> I always made a living from photojournalism, but ultimately it was too rigid in structure to allow for much growth. I never identified with photojournalism and was always more inspired by street or documentary photographers. Then, a few years ago, I found that I could express things better while writing than taking pictures, and through the writing realized the photography lacked definition. I entered a transition that continues to this day, aiming to use photography more as an individual, a citizen, than as just a photographer working to illustrate or report something. It was a big shift, from solely documenting the outward to documenting and analysing the outward and inward.</p>
<p>
	<strong>How did your career as a photographer begin?</strong><br />
	The photojournalism career really took off after I was given an internship at<em> National Geographic </em>magazine. Partially thanks to those jobs at <em>NG</em>, I was able to begin getting consistent work soon after moving to New York City in the winter of 2006.</p>
<p>
	<strong>When you are working in conflict zones, do you worry that your photography will end up being dominated by pictures of guns and injuries? How do you find art in conflict?</strong><br />
	Well, I live in east Democratic Republic of the Congo, which is an active conflict zone, but I&#39;m not covering the frontlines of armed conflict. I have the itch but avoid it because it is more related to addictions than beliefs. I need to identify with whatever is happening before planting myself on a frontline. I need to feel involved to a great extent&mdash;as if I were a participant. I felt this in Libya but not since then, except briefly at the beginning of the Syrian war. Not in Congo, however, because, although I am beginning to understand it, it is a conflict based on ethnicity and power and I cannot strongly identify with race or with the powerless or powerful. At the end of the day, I am just an average white boy from the Skagit Valley&mdash;an alien.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140208/Congo48-edit.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 640px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Rwindi, Democratic Republic of the Congo. 2012</em></p>
<p>
	<strong>I see.</strong><br />
	Finding art in conflict, as you say, seems to be about finding a way to identify one&rsquo;s situation with the situation on the ground, and to do it in a personal way that others can identify with. That is what makes work inspiring, because it is about more than just great pictures. It is about having a vision, which seems to be, beyond adding to history, all we really have to share with the world. We can enable viewers to leave this type of work feeling inspired, not shitty, about what they have just seen, even if the work contains brutality. Maybe this is far-fetched, but I think that it&#39;s tough for say, the average American to look at pictures of foreign conflict and identify with them. But that&#39;s what we are hoping to do with the Libya project.</p>
<p>
	<strong>How did you hope to accomplish that? It&#39;s a tough ask.</strong><br />
	Libya was about having an experience and recording it using the same tool the Libyans used during their revolution&mdash;a mobile phone. But the complete work is more than that. There is a lot of writing and more than 400 pictures in the book, as well as a 20-minute installation of my videos from 2011, being put together by some friends at <a href="http://screenprojects.org" target="_blank">screenprojects.org</a>. I hope to exhibit those items, along with dozens of artefacts, in New York later this year.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140209/09kashgar-4538.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 426px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Kashgar, China. 2009. </em></p>
<p>
	<strong>How do you feel about the Arab Spring now?</strong><br />
	After Libya, I was not interested in following the rest of the Arab Spring, though in early 2012, I did seriously plan a trip to Syria. I had just returned from Lebanon, was following the news every day and emailing folks to figure out a way in, until Remi Ochlik and others were killed. Then the questioning began again: Why am I doing this? I decided to wait and was glad I did. Though it appeared to be like Libya in the beginning, it quickly became nasty in all sorts of ways, turning into something that for me, as an outsider, is now unrecognizable.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Can you tell me about being kidnapped in Benghazi</strong>?<br />
	I was kidnapped briefly after the war was over. It was bizarre. We were filming drifters in Benghazi and then hopped in a pickup that drifted and flipped. A big crowd surrounded us as we crawled out, and the mood shifted when some militia saw the driver pull out his AK-47 and fake a shot into the air to scatter the crowd. He drove off without us but they thought we were his crew, or at least that was their excuse to take us at gunpoint. According to another driver who was with us, they had plans to drive us out of town to their base and steal our equipment, perhaps more. There was a gun to that driver&#39;s head, several militia vehicles involved, and they confiscated our phones.</p>
<p>
	It was months after the official end of the revolution, and the mood was sketchy and unpredictable, as the frontlines were not as clear any more. Eventually, as our vehicle moved through traffic, I was able to break out of the door at an intersection, walk through standing traffic, and yell for help until people got out of their vehicles and came to our aid. The militiamen sped off.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140212/09kashgar-7164.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 426px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Kashgar, China. 2009. Street life in Kashgar&#39;s Old City.</em></p>
<p>
	<strong>Jesus, that sounds stressful. In some of your series, particularly the one based on the old city of Kashgar in China, I&#39;ve been struck by recurring colors. With the Kashgar photos, it was blue and red. Is this something you are conscious of?</strong><br />
	Not really. Those were just the colors of the place, whether during the day or at night. With some of those images, the colors were tweaked by the camera, due to noise, because they were made in minimal light.</p>
<p>
	<strong>What brought you to the Democratic Republic of the Congo?</strong><br />
	I proposed a story on conflict minerals in DCR to <em>TIME </em>magazine in 2012, for their wireless technology issue. I stayed on after the story and have made several trips since then, up to now, where I have been living in Goma since November.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140211/1211CongoTwo-6133.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 640px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Rwindi, Democratic Republic of the Congo. 2012</em>.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Your Olympics photos seemed to show a different side of your work. Did you approach sports photography differently?</strong><br />
	I went to Beijing for <em>ESPN </em>magazine, and I was their only photographer, so there was a big responsibility to try to capture everything, and often with longer lenses. I did not sleep or eat much and lugged around a big glass for the first week before the editor finally told me to just do what I wanted. Which was to wander and do what other photographers were not doing, though the access was tough. There is a reason why photographers from, say, Getty or<em> Sports Illustrated</em> or AP get all the best pictures: They have the best access, called pool access. If you don&rsquo;t have pool access you&rsquo;re stuck on the sidelines. So I walked around the crowd and tried to focus behind the scenes.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Many of your series&mdash;particularly in Kashgar and Alaska&mdash;deal with remote places. Is there a particular attraction to these places?</strong><br />
	There is no longer an attraction, but at the time it was either just for assignments (Alaska for <em>National Geographic </em>magazine or Kashgar for <em>Smithsonian</em>), or because I was looking to photograph some aspect of people in transition. Sometimes they blended together, which was the case with both Alaska and Kashgar.</p>
<p>
	The Alaska piece was about a young adventurer, Andrew Skurka, and his solo trip through the wilderness. But it was really about a young man facing nature while totally exposed to the elements. Humans are so disconnected with the natural world; we don&rsquo;t live in nature any more. And nature becomes very scary when one realizes they are no longer in control. With Kashgar, it was about a city initially of Uighur people that was being dominated&mdash;or one could say &quot;occupied&quot;&mdash;by the Chinese. It was about the transition of the Uighur existence, which was vanishing in certain ways and being modernized in others.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140210/MM7934-100822-04442.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 426px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Andrew Skurka and Roman Dial on a four-day hike through Alaska in 2010</em></p>
<p>
	<strong>Do you think the rise of citizen journalism is endangering your profession? Are you worried at all that people can just record what&#39;s happening on their phones?</strong><br />
	As Chuck Close said, &ldquo;Photography is the only art in which there are accidental masterpieces.&rdquo; Anybody, at the right place and time, is able to make a great picture, and even mechanized photography like Google Street View is able to capture great street scenes. But consistency is important if it is to be a profession, so the random great images Joe Public takes will never add up to the legacy of good pictures left by a professional.</p>
<p>
	What is endangering photojournalism is hardline photojournalist attitudes. But I think the more imagery, the better. Sure, more editors and curators are needed to comb through this vast trove of information (thank God for hashtags?), but really, perhaps we are entering the golden age of photography, because it is finally and instantly available to nearly everyone.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Thanks, Michael.</strong></p>
<h3>
	<em>Click through for more of Michael Christopher Brown&#39;s photographs.</em></h3>
<p>
<!--nextpage--></p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140213/-MG-5581.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 426px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Kashgar, China. 2009. Day and night, convoys of Chinese soldiers continually circle Kashgar&#39;s Old City. The poster on the side of some of their vehicles says (roughly): &quot;Police and people join forces as close as brothers.&quot;&nbsp;</em></p>
<p>
<!--nextpage--></p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140214/09kashgar-3828.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 426px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Kashgar, China. 2009. </em></p>
<p>
<!--nextpage--></p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140215/09kashgar-4559.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 426px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Kashgar, China. 2009. </em></p>
<p>
<!--nextpage--></p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140219/09kashgar-7475.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 426px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Kashgar, China. 2009. Street scene in Kashgar&#39;s Old City, located in the Xinjiang Uighur Autonomous Region of China.</em></p>
<p>
<!--nextpage--></p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140220/09kashgar-8115.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 426px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Kashgar, China. 2009</em></p>
<p>
<!--nextpage--></p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140222/1211CongoTwo-3527-copy.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 640px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Goma, Democratic Republic of the Congo. December 14, 2012. Abandoned planes are a common sight at airports in Africa. At Goma Airport, planes left due to wars and volcanic eruptions over the past two decades have become a playground for street children, some of whom sell the parts, which are made into stoves and other items to be sold on the streets of Goma. </em></p>
<p>
<!--nextpage--></p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140218/Congo66-edit.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 640px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Democratic Republic of the Congo. 2013.</em></p>
<p>
<!--nextpage--></p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140223/1211CongoTwo-5176.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 640px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Rwindi, Democratic Republic of the Congo. 2012. In Rwindi, a savanna located in the North Kivu province of the DRC, the military occupies a defunct, Mobutu-era safari hotel, called Hotel Invest. In 2012, with the permission of several DRC colonels, Michael spent ten days at and around this decrepit hotel, documenting the daily lives of soldiers during a lull in fighting the M23 rebel forces. </em></p>
<p>
<!--nextpage--></p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140227/Congo59-edit.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 640px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Democratic Republic of the Congo. 2013.</em></p>
<p>
<!--nextpage--></p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140230/MM7934-100416-01218.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 426px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<em>Alaska. 2010. Andrew Skurka skis up the Tatina River and into the Kichatna Mountains.</em></p>
<p>
<!--recommended--></p>

]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299208</guid>
<author>Oscar Rickett</author>
<category>photo, VICE Loves Magnum, Magnum Photos, Michael Christopher Brown, interview, Photography, Congo, Libyan Sugar</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rick Ross&#039;s &#039;Mastermind&#039;  The Kid Mero Review</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/rick-ross-mastermind---the-kid-mero-review</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Rick Ross's 'Mastermind'  The Kid Mero Review
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299047</guid>
<author>The Kid Mero</author>
<category>music, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>The VICE Report: Immigrants Are Walking Hundreds of Miles from Greece to Germany</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/the-vice-report/walking-into-europe</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	As one of the gateways to mainland Europe, Greece is home to thousands of immigrants&mdash;but at the moment, it&#39;s not a particularly happy home. Many spend their days trying to escape the xenophobia and erratic immigration policies that characterize present-day Greece. More often than not, the immigrants look westward to countries like the UK or Germany, where, they feel, they will be able to lead richer, happier lives.</p>
<p>
	But even if certain sections of Greek society would welcome a mass exodus of foreigners, especially the ones who have entered the country illegally, the laws of the European Union mean that this would be easier said than done. What do you do when you&#39;re trapped in a country that doesn&#39;t want you? You can&#39;t just walk from one country into another that suits you better.</p>
<p>
	Actually, as we discovered, you <em>can</em>&nbsp;just walk from one country to another&mdash;VICE discovered that many immigrants who wanted to get out of Greece traveled on foot along an increasingly well-worn path from Greece into Macedonia, Serbia, and Hungary.</p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299049</guid>
<author>George Moutafis</author>
<category>news, Greece, illegal immigration, immigration, Macednia, Hungary, Serbia</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Russian Roulette: The Invasion of Ukraine - Part 2 </title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/russian-roulette-the-invasion-of-ukraine-part-2</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 23:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Russian Roulette: The Invasion of Ukraine - Part 2 
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299098</guid>
<author>Simon Ostrovsky</author>
<category>news, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sexual Abuse Has Become a Huge Problem for America&#039;s Bible Colleges</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/sexual-abuse-has-become-a-huge-problem-for-americas-bible-colleges</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 18:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140239/20121109happy-friends-hc07-613x408.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 426px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>Students at Bob Jones University, where administrators recently relaunched an investigation into the mishandling of sexual-abuse cases. Photo courtesy of Bob Jones University</i></p>
<p>
	Samantha Field was a student at Pensacola Christian College in 2009, when she claims to have suffered repeated physical and sexual assaults&mdash;including two alleged rapes&mdash;by her ex-fianc&eacute;, a fellow student. Thanks to the school&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.pcci.edu/pathway/PCCPathway.pdf">strict morality code</a>, which doesn&rsquo;t allow men and women to use the same elevators, much less be alone in the same room, Samantha was reluctant to report her story to the school for fear of inviting suspicion and scrutiny, if not expulsion. Eventually, other students and faculty members noticed something was wrong, and Field was called in to meet with college administrators, including the school&rsquo;s dean for women, who, Field says, told her that &ldquo;confession [is] good for the soul.&rdquo; When she remained silent, having nothing to confess, Field was sent to the school counselor.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;I started to tell her that my boyfriend had made me do things that I didn&rsquo;t want to do, but she interrupted me and asked what I needed to repent of, and told me that I needed to forgive him, because otherwise I would have bitterness in my heart,&rdquo; said Field, now a writer who <a href="http://defeatingthedragons.wordpress.com/">blogs about her experience</a>&nbsp;leaving the Christian fundamentalist movement. &ldquo;I was trying to tell her that my boyfriend had raped me, and her reaction was to tell me that I needed to repent for my sins and not worry about my rapist&rsquo;s sins.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	A spokesperson for Pensacola Christian College, Amy Glenn, declined to comment on Field&rsquo;s claims, citing the school&rsquo;s policy of keeping student records confidential. She added that the college follows a &ldquo;well-developed set of procedures&rdquo; for students seeking counseling, but she could not offer specifics on PCC&rsquo;s policies regarding sexual abuse.</p>
<p>
	Sadly, Field&rsquo;s story is neither surprising nor uncommon in the world of Christian fundamentalism, where sexual contact is strictly forbidden outside of marriage and total submission to religious authority figures is required of all believers. Even though the Catholic Church has been home to the most high-profile pedophilia scandals, Evangelical churches, schools, and missionary groups have proven to be <a href="http://netgrace.org/wp-content/uploads/final_report_and_recommendations.pdf">similarly susceptible to sexual and physical abuse</a>, and <a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2010/05/27/pregnant-teen-victim-recalls-publicly-shamed-church-relocated-colorado/">equally adept at shielding perpetrators from punishment.</a></p>
<p>
	The issue of how Evangelical groups&mdash;and particularly fundamentalist Bible colleges&mdash;deal with allegations of abuse has come to the fore at Bob Jones University, where school officials recently fired, and then rehired, the outside Christian consulting firm Godly Response to Abuse in the Christian Environment, or GRACE, to investigate the school&rsquo;s handling of sexual abuse. Led by Basyle Tchividjian, an associate law professor at Liberty University and the grandson of Reverend Billy Graham, GRACE has caused a stir among evangelicals for having the audacity <a href="http://boz.religionnews.com/2014/02/22/public-statement-concerning-sexual-abuse-church-jesus-christ/">to point out</a>&nbsp;the rampant rape and abuse among fundamentalist Christian groups. <a href="http://www.religionnews.com/2013/09/26/billy-grahams-grandson-evangelicals-worse-catholic-church-sex-abuse/">In remarks to journalists last year</a>, Tchividjian said that the Christian mission field is a &ldquo;magnet for sexual abusers,&rdquo; and that he believes evangelicals are worse than the Catholic Church in the way that they deal with abuse in their congregations. (Tchividjian declined to speak with me until after GRACE issues its report on BJU.) At least <a>two other Christian groups have terminated</a>&nbsp;their relationships with GRACE, including the Association of Baptists for World Evangelism&mdash;<a href="http://netgrace.org/wp-content/uploads/GRACE-Response-February-10-2013.pdf">which fired GRACE just weeks before the group was scheduled to release its final report on a two-year inquiry into allegations of sexual abuse by a former missionary in Bangladesh.</a>&nbsp;New Tribes Mission, another Christian missionary group, ended its relationship with GRACE after the organization completed a <a href="http://usa.ntm.org/mission-news/2475/fanda-report-response-summary">2010 report on abuse at an NTM missionary school in Senegal during the 1980s</a>. (Although both NTM and GRACE say the parting was amicable,&nbsp;<a href="http://usa.ntm.org/mission-news/56891/ihart-update">subsequent NTM investigations</a> have been conducted by other outside consulting groups.)</p>
<p>
	The Bob Jones investigation, initially launched in late 2012, has been pretty earth-shattering for fundamentalist Christians. Although BJU <a href="http://www.bju.edu/about/answering-questions.php">publicly stated</a>&nbsp;that the GRACE inquiry was just to &ldquo;<a>make certain that BJU&rsquo;s policies and procedures for handling reports of sexual abuse both fully comply with every aspect of the law and ensure a loving, scripturally based response</a>,&rdquo; many saw the investigation as an implicit acknowledgement that sexual abuse is a reality, even among the godly students and faculty at Bob Jones.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140250/20130405mentoring-dc01-613x407.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 425px;" /></p>
<p class="photo_caption">
	<i>Photo courtesy of Bob Jones University</i></p>
<p>
	BJU isn&rsquo;t your run-of-the-mill Bible college. Located in Greenville, South Carolina, Bob Jones University is the mother ship of American fundamentalism, with a network of alumni-founded congregations, seminaries, and Bible colleges that adhere to a brand of Christianity so strict it makes Jerry Falwell look like Dorothy Day. Students are banned from watching movies on campus, drinking alcohol, unmarried handholding, and socializing in parking garages, among other various forbidden pleasures <a href="http://www.bju.edu/life-faith/student-handbook.pdf?utm_medium=Link&amp;utm_content=%2Fstudent-life%2Fstudent-handbook.pdf&amp;utm_campaign=Redirect">outlined in the student handbook</a>.&nbsp;Any sexual contact before marriage is grounds for expulsion.</p>
<p>
	In a culture that fetishizes chastity to the point of <a href="http://generationsoflight.com/html/index.html">throwing father-daughter Purity Balls</a>&nbsp;celebrating virginity, women bear a disproportionate amount of responsibility for upholding these strict social mores and are often instructed not to tempt male &ldquo;urges&rdquo; with their low-cut shirts and tight clothes. It is a way of thinking that implies men only do bad things to bad women who tempt them.</p>
<p>
	Of course, all of this pious moralizing requires a heavy dose of denial. BJU administrators <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2012/05/08/us/bju-student-suspension-irpt/">have allegedly</a>&nbsp;ignored or punished students who bring up the issue of sexual assault. <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/12/education/christian-school-faulted-for-halting-abuse-study.html?_r=1">Victims of abuse have claimed</a>&nbsp;that school administrators called them liars and sinners and told them not to report their attacks to the police because it would hurt Jesus. &nbsp;</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;When I finally reported my assault to the school, the first questions they asked me were, &lsquo;What were you wearing?&rsquo; &lsquo;Was it tight?&rsquo; &lsquo;Was it low?&rsquo;&rdquo; said Erin Burchwell, a BJU alumna who claims that she was assaulted more than 40 times over the course of two years by a male graduate student while she was an undergraduate. &ldquo;The assumption was obviously that it was my fault, that I had done something wrong by putting myself in that situation.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Burchwell said that the investigation initially gave her hope that she could end 15 years of silence about her abuse. Then, abruptly and without explanation, BJU announced last month that the yearlong inquiry had been terminated, just weeks before GRACE was scheduled to release its final report. Officially, BJU&#39;s president, Stephen Jones, said that the school was concerned that GRACE had gone beyond the &ldquo;originally outlined intentions&rdquo; of the investigation. But the subtext was that GRACE had found something that the school didn&rsquo;t want people to see. Unsurprisingly, the backlash was immediate and intense. After two weeks of criticism from former students, and a scathing story in <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/12/education/christian-school-faulted-for-halting-abuse-study.html?_r=0&amp;module=ArrowsNav&amp;contentCollection=Education&amp;action=keypress&amp;region=FixedLeft&amp;pgtype=article">the <em>New York Times</em></a>, BJU officials apparently realized they had made a big PR blunder. On Tuesday, the school said that it was resuming the GRACE investigation and would allow a report to be made public later this year. &nbsp;</p>
<p>
	If the goal was to contain the fallout, though, it looks like BJU may be too late. After the school ended the investigation, former alumni like Burchwell went public with their stories, many for the first time, sharing details about BJU&rsquo;s twisted approach to sexual-abuse counseling. And the reverberations haven&rsquo;t been limited to Bob Jones. A <a href="http://www.newrepublic.com/article/116623/sexual-assault-patrick-henry-college-gods-harvard">story published by the <em>New Republic</em></a>&nbsp;last week detailed allegations of mishandled sexual abuse cases at Patrick Henry College, a.k.a. &ldquo;God&rsquo;s Harvard,&rdquo; including one instance in which a dean told a student who had been sexually assaulted in her sleep that if she were telling the truth, &ldquo;God would have kept her conscious to bear witness to the abuse.&rdquo; On <a href="https://www.facebook.com/TellTheTruthBJU">Facebook</a>&nbsp;and <a href="http://www.fromtracie.com/2014/02/growing-up-in-fundamentalism-bju-grace.html">Christian blogs</a>, people like Samantha Field have attested to getting similarly fucked-up abuse counseling at other fundamentalist churches and Christian colleges around the country.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;I&rsquo;ve been really surprised by how many people have come out with their stories&mdash;and I think the school is surprised by it too,&rdquo; Burchwell told me. &ldquo;But this would never have happened if they hadn&#39;t tried to end the report.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	In response to Burchwell&rsquo;s claims, BJU spokesperson Randy Page said that, to his knowledge, &ldquo;no administrator would have told her not to report it to the police if she had wanted to go to the police.&rdquo; He added that BJU has decided not to comment on claims made during the course of the GRACE investigation until after the final report has been released. He also noted that, since 2011, the school has taken several steps to <a href="http://www.bju.edu/about/answering-questions.php">improve its response to students who report past abuses</a>, including implementing new awareness training and appointing a full-time abuse counselor.</p>
<p>
	For Samantha Field, however, the Bob Jones investigation offers little hope for breaking the cycle of abuse and victim-blaming that she argues has permeated the fundamentalist movement. &ldquo;Women in this culture don&#39;t realize that they have the right to have a say what happens to their bodies. They don&#39;t understand that it&rsquo;s not their fault, and they feel complicit in it,&rdquo; Field told me. &ldquo;They are taught [their] whole lives that women who do sexual things with their boyfriends are worthless, so they feel trapped in these abusive relationships.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Field left fundamentalism after graduating from Pensacola Christian College in 2010. She said that she still has night terrors and panic attacks, which she attributes to not receiving proper counseling after her alleged rapes. Her former fianc&eacute; also graduated from PCC, she added. He is now a youth pastor.</p>
<div>
	<div>
		<div id="_com_3" uage="JavaScript">
			&nbsp;</div>
	</div>
</div>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299061</guid>
<author>Grace Wyler</author>
<category>news, Christian fundamentalists, christian fundamentalism, evangelical Christians, sexual abuse, bible belt, College</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>The DIY Engineer Who Built a Nuclear Reactor in His Basement</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/the-diy-engineer-who-built-a-nuclear-reactor-in-his-basement-mb-test</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[The DIY Engineer Who Built a Nuclear Reactor in His Basement
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299084</guid>
<author>Xavier Aaronson</author>
<category>tech, </category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apparently, People Still Care About Cronuts</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/apparently-people-still-care-about-cronuts</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 18:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140238/IMG-0015.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	The Cronut was birthed into this cruel, vacuous existence on May 10, 2013, making it less than a year old. In meme years, however, it&rsquo;s ancient. The &ldquo;<a href="http://dominiqueansel.com/cronut-101/" target="_blank">most virally talked about dessert item in history</a>,&rdquo; chef Dominique Ansel&rsquo;s Cronut&reg; (emphasis on &reg;) caused one helluva fuss a few months ago, with lines of hungry trend hounds famously snaking around the block of Ansel&rsquo;s New York City bakery.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140226/IMG-0064.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	But that was then, and this is now. In a world in which the news cycle is such that we forget about shamed politicians, rape accusations, and the existence of Joseph Kony within days, any logical person would assume the shelf life of Cronuts as a five-hour-wait-worthy snack had surely expired. But the Grove, Los Angeles&rsquo; premier outdoor mall,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.lamoth.org/" target="_blank">located across the street from a Holocaust museum</a>, apparently is a logic-free zone. I say that because hundreds of people recently lined up there, in the rain, for a chance to purchase the pass&eacute; pastry.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140231/IMG-0092.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	A promotional event for Barneys New York&rsquo;s &ldquo;newly converted&rdquo; boutique at the Grove, a gibberish-laden postcard told attendees that &ldquo;to celebrate this Fashion Mash-Up, [they would] have access for the first time in Los Angeles to the original hybrid dessert: the Cronut&reg;.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140246/IMG-0024.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	I got to the Grove more than an hour before the boutique&rsquo;s doors were set to open; an enormous queue, snaking through the parking garage, was already at capacity. A standby line nearby held the stragglers who were unwilling to wake up before sunrise for the privilege of paying $5 for a mouthful of over-hyped sugar and flour.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140242/IMG-0080.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	The first person in line, a young, theoretically normal-looking woman sitting in a folding chair, noticed the gaze of my camera as I snapped her photo. In response, she contorted her face into a mixture of shame and displeasure. I, however, wasn&rsquo;t the one who put an icing gun to her head and made her sit in a wet, drafty parking garage for seven hours in exchange for the privilege of eating a deep-fried croissant. Every time I took her photo, which I did often because I knew it upset her, she gave me a surly look. If legend was to be believed, she had been there since 3 AM.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140233/IMG-0115.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	She wasn&rsquo;t the only person willing to abandon reason and personhood for a pastry. One dweeb allegedly drove up from San Diego (a two-hour drive under pleasant conditions, let alone in a goddamned rainstorm). Once allowed entry into Barneys, people wrote their own pathetic tales on whiteboards they held while posing for iPhone photos with a pained-looking Ansel, the deranged genius himself. One had to &ldquo;drive on the 101 in a downpour!&quot; Another &ldquo;woke up at 4:30 AM!&quot; My friend Rob, who witnessed the devastation alongside me, quipped that the whiteboard should have read, &ldquo;This is why the terrorists hate us.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140240/IMG-0102.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	Thirty minutes to launch time, I set up shop outside the entrance and waited for the gates to open. An endless stream of people, all of whom looked upwardly mobile enough to afford trendy baked goods, approached and took countless iPhone photos of the (ample) signage. A woman in yoga pants (natch) was among them. After she took her shot, she clicked back to her phone&rsquo;s home screen. I immediately noticed she had the TMZ app installed. In that moment, nothing could have made more sense. A sharp-dressed man in his mid 20s approached and asked me to take an iPhone photo (<em>again</em>) of him and his equally sharp female friends, in front of the Cronuts sign. I did as asked. He immediately made me take it again because he &ldquo;wasn&rsquo;t smiling.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140241/IMG-0117.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	A gabble (like a gaggle, but comprised of broads instead of geese) of fashion victims, the most excitable of whom carried a C&eacute;line handbag the internet informed me was worth more than my car, ran over to a similarly vacant, ostentatiously dressed woman. &ldquo;Brad said you can&rsquo;t eat a whole one,&rdquo; the excitable woman gushed, &ldquo;so we&rsquo;re gonna get three for the four of us.&rdquo; The next thing out of her mouth, devoid of any segue, was &ldquo;Oh. My. God. Rachel. You Look. So. Gooooood!!&rdquo; The gabble giggled and squealed and <em>OMG can you believe this line&ndash;</em>d for what seemed like an eternity. When the doors eventually opened, they abstained from getting in line. Hovering outside the entrance like vultures, they made small talk with the doorman, operating under the assumption that, at some point, their enthusiasm and entitlement would allow them entry over the plebes who had to wait. I kept them in my prayers.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140235/IMG-0045.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	The line itself was filled with a surprising amount of young people, squandering said youth, snapping selfies, and scrolling through Instagram. The typical cat mommies one would expect to be excited about new pastry technology were mixed with these young, &ldquo;adventurous&rdquo; types. When it rained, which it did on and off, both groups were sheltered from the storm, a fact I found unfortunate.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140236/IMG-0017.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	A sign, labeled &quot;Cronut&reg; 101,&quot; outlined the rules for consuming the pastries. &nbsp;They were to be eaten immediately (&ldquo;The Cronut&reg; has a shelf life of less than six hours!&rdquo;). They were not, under any circumstances, to be heated, cut with anything but a serrated knife, or refrigerated or frozen (&ldquo;The humidity from both will destroy the Cronut&reg; and make it soggy and stale. Keeping it in a cool dry room for a short time is okay.&rdquo;). For a baked good, these Cronut things seemed pretty uptight.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140237/IMG-0101.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	Despite the Cronut&rsquo;s limited shelf life, few folks ate theirs immediately after purchase. Most seemed content to merely wander around with their tastefully boxed treats, cradling them like C&eacute;line-quality status symbols. I watched a man take an iPhone photo of his while sitting outside the Grove&rsquo;s fountain. I wondered what the street value on a scalped Cronut would be. I wondered <a href="https://news.vice.com/video/russian-roulette-the-invasion-of-ukraine-dispatch-one?trk_source=homepage-lede" target="_blank">what was going on in Ukraine</a> right then.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140225/IMG-0098.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p>
<p>
	I finally tracked down a young man who was eating, not photographing, the mythical pastry. He and his friends had waited in line for two hours. I asked if the wait was worth it; shrugging, he responded that the Cronut was &ldquo;merely OK.&rdquo; As the group joylessly chewed in silence, he continued, &ldquo;You&rsquo;re not missing much, if that&rsquo;s what you&rsquo;re wondering.&rdquo; One of his female friends, vacantly staring into the middle distance, told me a bakery in town called <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/frances-bakery-and-coffee-los-angeles" target="_blank">Frances</a> made their own &ldquo;pretty good&rdquo; version of them (which begged the question, why the fuck was she here?).</p>
<p>
	Indeed, despite Barneys&rsquo; claims that this was the &ldquo;first time&rdquo; the treat had been available in Los Angeles, multiple shops sell their (non-copyrighted) versions of them. One such shop, a place called <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/sk-donuts-and-croissant-los-angeles" target="_blank">SK Donuts</a>, hawks an iteration called the SKronut. SK Donuts is less than a mile away from the Grove. As I drove by it on my way home, there was no line.</p>
<p>
	<em>Megan Koester is a writer and comedian who scoffs at your novelty pastries. See her and other VICE west coast contributors at <a href="http://www.clublosglobos.com/event/487503-entitlement-comedy-night-los-angeles/" target="_blank">ENTITLEMENT on Wednesday, March 5, with special guest Emily Heller</a>,&nbsp;at Los Globos on Sunset Blvd. in Los Angeles. Follow her on <a href="https://twitter.com/bornferal" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.</em></p>

]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299060</guid>
<author>Megan Koester</author>
<category>food, Los Angeles, Cronuts, The Grove</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>VICE News: Venezuela Rising - Part 4</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/vice-news/venezuela-rising-dispatch-four</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	VICE News continues its coverage of the rising tensions in Caracas, Venezuela, against President Nicolas Maduro&#39;s government. We visit a construction site near Altamura Square, where protesters are mining the left-over materials to use as barricades and weapons. As the crisis continues, the materials that protesters are using have evolved, and it seems they will stop at nothing until they see a change in their government.<br />
	<br />
	<em>Follow VICE News on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/vicenews">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/vicenews">Twitter</a>, and <a href="http://vicenews.tumblr.com/">Tumblr</a>.</em></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299058</guid>
<category>news, VICE News, NEWS, Venezuela, protests, Students, opposition, Nicolas Maduro</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Ketamine the New Miracle Drug?</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/ketamine-therapy</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
	<img alt="" src="http://assets.vice.com/content-images/contentimage/140251/daniellecosgrove4.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 640px;" /></p>
<p>
	Danielle Cosgrove rested in a hospital bed with an IV slowly pumping the meds into her veins. She knew the drugs were working when the walls started to melt.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;It was very, very scary,&rdquo; the petite 27-year-old said of her first experience with ketamine-infusion therapy, an increasingly popular but largely unregulated treatment for ailments ranging from intractable depression to untreatable pain, for which she is an outspoken advocate. &ldquo;I thought the walls were made of icing and they were melting down on top of me trying to suffocate me.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	For Danielle, the only thing worse than the hallucinations is her constant, excruciating pain, the hallmark of Complex Regional Pain Syndrome, a rare neurological disorder she developed after a devastating ATV accident in Qatar in 2010. She experimented with a series of invasive treatments and even strong opiates like Oxycontin, with no end to the pain. As a last resort, she turned to ketamine-infusion therapy in 2011.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;Imagine it as having the volume of your pain system cranked up to a ten&mdash;everything that hurts after you develop the disease will hurt more, and everything that hurt beforehand will also hurt more,&rdquo; explained Dr. Enrique Aradillas Lopez, a prot&eacute;g&eacute; of ketamine-infusion therapy&rsquo;s American godfather, Dr. Robert Schwartzman, and a high ranking physician in Drexel University&rsquo;s neurology department.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;The neurons that have changed are disinhibited and in a constant state of excitation,&rdquo; like a club kid lost in a K-hole, Dr. Aradillas Lopez explained. &ldquo;Ketamine blocks the NMDA receptors and gives a chance for the neuron to go back to the way it was before. In a way, it&rsquo;s rebooting your pain system.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	It was desperation that pushed Danielle to the street drug&mdash;Special K&mdash;she had avoided as a student in London. Since starting treatment, she&rsquo;s shuttled between her home in Texas and hospitals first in Chicago and then Philadelphia, subjecting herself to dozens of intravenous ketamine infusions and consecutive days of terrifying drug trips. She carries ketamine pills and a ketamine nasal spray in her purse. For her and untold others, the horse tranquilizer turned trippy club drug is the only medicine that works.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;It&rsquo;s a profoundly valuable drug as [a painkiller],&rdquo; said Colonel Chester &#39;Trip&#39; Buckenmaier III, a military physician who championed ketamine as a frontline pain drug for American soldiers wounded in combat. &ldquo;Ketamine became something that we were falling back on when everything else was maxed-out and failing.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	Ketamine infusion therapy started in 1999, and the last decade has seen the rise of more and more unorthodox uses for the operating-room anesthetic, and in the past two years alone, the number of US clinics offering ketamine infusions to treat everything from fibromyalgia, a syndrome that causes long-term, body-wide pain, to eating disorders and OCD has ballooned.</p>
<p>
	Dr. Aradillas Lopez cited more than a dozen new clinics giving outpatient infusions. Colonel Buckenmaier wouldn&rsquo;t estimate how many military hospitals have adopted ketamine-infusion therapy, but said he&rsquo;s asked for his protocols roughly once a week. Dr. Philip Getson, another Drexel University&ndash;affiliated physician, who practices in New Jersey, put the number of clinics closer to 60.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;It&rsquo;s probably the antidepressant drug with the least significant side effects of any other antidepressant agent now in use,&rdquo; said Dr. Glen Brooks, an anesthesiologist who opened the New York Ketamine Infusions center in downtown Manhattan to treat patients with drug-resistant depression two years ago. &ldquo;Most of my patients are suicidal. Most have failed electroconvulsive therapy and transcranial magnetic stimulation, and in spite of that I&rsquo;ll still see a significant number of patients that have a dramatic response to ketamine.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Researchers believe the drug works similarly to other antidepressants, by regulating the activity of specific electrochemicals in the brain. The difference, Dr. Brooks explained, is that while other antidepressants act on monoamines like serotonin, norepinephrine, or dopamine, which together account for just 15 percent of the brain&rsquo;s neurotransmitters, ketamine targets glutamate, an amino acid that accounts for 50 percent of nervous tissue in the body. SSRIs must be taken every day, but a single shot of Special K can keep a patient smiling for months.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;The only real side effect of ketamine is during the infusion itself: There is a sort of out-of-body experience,&rdquo; Brooks said. &ldquo;Most patients actually enjoy it. Young patients listening to their own music can really get into this out-of-body thing.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Some patients described feeling goofy and happy for about a day afterward, while Danielle described more of a drained and edgy feeling that made her antisocial for a few days.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	Ketamine is FDA-approved strictly as an induction agent&mdash;or what knocks you out on the operating table. But off-label prescriptions are a common practice in the medical field, like the seizure medication Neurontin prescribed for anxiety or the narcolepsy drug Provigil given to patients with ADD.</p>
<p>
	Ketamine is different in part because it&rsquo;s most effective as an IV drug, one that must be administered in a hospital or clinic, often in combination with other strong drugs like Versed, to counteract its hallucinogenic effects. Infusions can last for hours and are sometimes spread over days. Experts have yet to agree on how much and how many doses of ketamine make a safe and therapeutic treatment.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;I do ketamine regularly: It can be up to every two weeks or every two months,&rdquo; Danielle said. &ldquo;It is a heavy drug to be putting into your body constantly<strong>. </strong>You want to be able to say, I&rsquo;m doing this until this point.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	The lack of large-scale clinical trials and funding makes that point difficult to identify. Depending on the patient and the condition, Brooks administers the infusion in one- or two-hour doses while patients sit in a chair, similar to chemo or dialysis. Aradillas Lopez orders a ten-day stay with slow, continuous infusions at intensive care units.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;This drug will never be approved by the FDA [for therapy],&rdquo; Dr. Brooks said, noting that without the administration&rsquo;s bureaucratic gold star, most insurance companies won&rsquo;t foot the bill, either. &ldquo;There aren&rsquo;t that many of us out here doing this, so there&rsquo;s no standard of care.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	According Buckenmaier, who&#39;s spent his career treating injuries that would have been universally fatal even a decade earlier, the medical establishment is losing out on one of the best pain drugs there is.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;In my 26-year career in the military, the deaths that I&rsquo;ve seen from pain management have been from opioids,&rdquo; the Colonel said. &ldquo;I often say, if only the drug in that machine had been ketamine, those people would be alive today.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	But for now, ketamine-infusion therapy is likely to languish without set standards or FDA approval, confined to a handful of military hospitals and a smattering of research institutions, with offshoot clinics like Brooks&rsquo;s few and far between.</p>
<p>
	<em>Follow Sonja Sharp on <a href="http://twitter.com/sovietsonja">Twitter</a>.</em></p>
<!--recommended-->
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299075</guid>
<author>Sonja Sharp</author>
<category>stuff, Ketamine, special k, drug therapy, healtcare, unorthodox drug treatments</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>What&#039;s the Deal with Seinfeld&#039;s Virtual Reality Tour?</title>
<link>http://www.vice.com/read/whats-the-deal-with-seinfelds-virtual-reality-tour-mb-test</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 19:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[What's the Deal with Seinfeld's Virtual Reality Tour?
]]></description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vice.com/299073</guid>
<author>Yannick Lejacq</author>
<category>tech, </category>
</item>
</channel></rss>